[
    [
        {
            "category": "Visual Arts",
            "question": "Born in Crete, this influential painter moved to Spain, where he became highly sought-after for his religious works. His paintings are characterized by elongated figures, dramatic lighting, and an intense spirituality that reflects the religious fervor of his time. Name this artist that was nicknamed for his nationality and is considered a significant figure in the Spanish Renaissance.",
            "answers": ["El Greco", "Dominikos Theotokopoulos"]
        },
        {
            "num": 21,
            "category": "Literature",
            "subcategory": "American",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This city is where Ralph Ellison's Invisible Man works at the Liberty Paint Company. George Selden wrote about a cricket in one of this city's major public spaces. The Great Gatsby takes place in this city where Percy Jackson visits the Metropolitan Museum of Art. This city is where Stuart Little races boats in Central Park. Name this city in which the Harlem Renaissance took place.",
            "round": "1",
            "year": 2012,
            "answers": ["New York City"],
            "id": 391
        },
        {
            "num": 10,
            "category": "Science",
            "subcategory": null,
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "pH in this fluid is regulated by the bicarbonate ion buffer system. Cells in this fluid include leukocytes and erythrocytes, while platelets help form clots that stop its flow. It is carried in arteries and veins. Name this fluid that delivers oxygen and nutrients to cells and is pumped by the heart.",
            "round": "CMST_Round08.pdf",
            "year": 2010,
            "answers": ["blood"],
            "id": 576
        },
        {
            "num": 7,
            "category": "Science",
            "subcategory": "Other",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "Starburst types of these systems have unusually high supplies of gas, and they can combine in a process known as cannibalism. The \"tuning fork diagram\" is a graphic depiction of the Hubble classification scheme for these systems, which divides them into irregular, elliptical and spiral types. M31 is the Andromeda one. Name these regions of the universe that include the Milky Way.",
            "round": "1",
            "year": 2011,
            "answers": ["galaxies", "galaxy"],
            "id": 294
        },
        {
            "num": 10,
            "category": "Geography",
            "subcategory": "Norse",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This country was officially recognized in the Lateran Treaties of 1929. It has extraterritorial authority over Castel Gandolfo. Places of interest in this country include the Sistine Chapel and Saint Peter's Square and Basilica. Voting in this country is restricted to Cardinals under eighty years old. Name this world's smallest country located entirely within the city of Rome.",
            "round": "4",
            "year": 2012,
            "answers": [
                "State of the Vatican City",
                "Holy See",
                "Santa Sede",
                "Stato della Citta del Vaticano"
            ],
            "id": 406
        },
        {
            "question": "An American writer known for his macabre and mysterious stories, his haunting prose and explorations of themes like madness and guilt established him as a master of Gothic literature. Name this author who gained recognition with his poem 'The Raven'.",
            "answers": ["Edgar Allan Poe", "Poe"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 80
        },
        {
            "num": 11,
            "category": "Literature",
            "subcategory": "American",
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This poet delivered \"The Gift Outright\" at President John F. Kennedy's inauguration. One of his poems observes that \"good fences make good neighbors\" and is called \"Mending Wall.\" His poem \"Nothing Gold Can Stay\" notes that \"Nature's first green is gold.\" Name this poet who stated in his most famous poem that he took \"the road less traveled by, and that has made all the difference.\"",
            "round": "6",
            "year": 2012,
            "answers": ["Robert Lee Frost"],
            "id": 752
        },
        {
            "num": 15,
            "category": "Mythology",
            "subcategory": null,
            "difficulty": "MS",
            "tournament": "Collaborative MS Tournament",
            "question": "This figure met his demise when he was struck by a piece of wood from his own vessel. While in Colchis visiting King Aeetes, he accomplished such tasks as yoking fire-breathing oxen and dispatching a group of warriors that sprang forth after dragon teeth were sown into the ground, all to get the Golden Fleece. He was aided in these tasks by his future wife Medea. Name this leader of the Argonauts.",
            "round": "CMST_Round09.pdf",
            "year": 2010,
            "answers": ["Jason"],
            "id": 214
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This video game series is set in a post-apocalyptic world that features a retro-futuristic setting influenced by the post-war culture of 1950s America, imagining an alternate history where the transistor was never invented. Known for its open-world gameplay, it allows players to explore vast wastelands and make choices that affect the game's story and environment. Developed by Bethesda Game Studios and recently adapted into a TV show, what is the name of this RPG series that begins with the aftermath of a global nuclear war?",
            "answers": ["Fallout"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This treaty's Article 231, known as the \"War Guilt Clause,\" assigned full blame for the war and all damages to Germany and its allies. It not only demanded reparations and territory from Germany but also mandated the disarmament of the German military and limited the size of the German navy. Additionally, it led to the creation of new nations in Eastern Europe and the League of Nations. What is the name of this treaty, that was signed in the Hall of Mirrors in a palace and ended World War I?",
            "answers": ["Treaty of Versailles"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Before basketball, this athlete was a competitive swimmer, aiming to compete in the Olympics. Known for his calm demeanor and fundamental playing style, he earned the nickname \"The Big Fundamental.\" He played his entire 19-season NBA career with the San Antonio Spurs, winning five NBA championships and two MVP awards. Who is this legendary power forward, celebrated for his leadership and consistency on the court?",
            "answers": ["Tim Duncan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This famous American traitor started his military career as a pharmacist and bookseller. He initially became a hero in the early stages of the American Revolutionary War by playing a key role in the capture of Fort Ticonderoga and was pivotal in the Battle of Saratoga. However, his name became synonymous with treason after his plot to surrender West Point to the British was exposed. He later served as a brigadier general in the British Army. Who is this controversial figure in American history?",
            "answers": ["Benedict Arnold"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This series is noted for its complex characters and storylines, as well as its frequent use of shocking plot twists, including the infamous \"Red Wedding\" episode. It is based on the book series \"A Song of Ice and Fire\" by George R.R. Martin, who served as a producer on the show. The show's extensive filming locations included Northern Ireland, Croatia, Iceland, and Spain. It set a record for the most Emmy Awards won by a scripted television series. What is the name of this fantasy television series that follows the power struggles among the Seven Kingdoms of Westeros?",
            "answers": ["\"Game of Thrones\""],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This vast desert is not only composed of sand dunes; it also features mountains, rock plateaus, and extensive gravel plains. It is home to the desert ant, Cataglyphis bicolor, known for its unique ability to withstand extreme temperatures by sprinting across the sand. Despite its arid climate, it houses over 20 lakes, most of which are saltwater lakes. Covering most of North Africa, it is nearly as large as the United States. What is the name of this desert, the largest hot desert in the world?",
            "answers": ["Sahara Desert"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Formulated in 1925, this equation is a key foundation of quantum mechanics and provides a mathematical description of the wave-like behavior of particles at atomic and subatomic scales. Unlike classical mechanics, it uses a wave function to describe probabilistically the state of a particle rather than determining precise outcomes. Developed by an Austrian physicist who later won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1933 for his contributions to the wave theory of matter, this equation has revolutionized our understanding of the atomic world. What is the name of this critical equation in quantum physics?",
            "answers": ["Schrodinger's Equation"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This ancient epic is traditionally attributed to a poet who is also credited with composing another foundational work of ancient Greek literature that details a famous war. The narrative centers on the protagonist's challenging journey home following the fall of Troy, which takes an arduous ten years to complete. Throughout his voyage, he encounters various mythical creatures including the Cyclops, the seductive Sirens, and the shape-shifting witch-goddess Circe. This epic is not just a tale of adventure but also explores themes of heroism, loyalty, and the human condition. What is the name of this seminal work, a cornerstone of ancient Greek literature, detailing the adventures of Odysseus?",
            "answers": ["The Odyssey"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Before entering politics, this future president briefly ran a general store and served as a Captain for the Illinois Miltia during the Black Hawk War. Despite his iconic image, he is the only president to hold a patent for an invention. His stovepipe hat was a practical accessory meant to hold important documents and letters. Name this president known for his leadership during the Civil War.",
            "answers": ["Abraham Lincoln"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Major League Baseball team was originally founded in Baltimore, Maryland, in 1901 before moving to New York City in 1903. Known for their distinctive pinstripe uniforms, they are often referred to by their nickname, \"The Bronx Bombers.\" The team holds the record for the most MLB championships, having won 27 World Series titles. Their storied rivalries, especially with the Boston Red Sox, are among the most famous in baseball history. What is the name of this iconic baseball team, synonymous with success and a global fanbase?",
            "answers": ["New York Yankees", "Yankees"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This play is set in the Kingdom of Denmark and features a plot that revolves around themes of treachery, revenge, incest, and moral corruption. The protagonist of the play studies in Wittenberg and is visited by the ghost of his father, who reveals the truth about his murder. Famous for its exploration of the human psyche, it introduces phrases like \"To be, or not to be\" into the English lexicon. Name this tragedy, often considered William Shakespeare's masterpiece, which centers on the Prince of Denmark.",
            "answers": ["\"Hamlet\"", "Hamlet"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Launched into low Earth orbit in 1990, this space-based observatory has become one of the most important instruments in the history of astronomy. It was not the first space telescope, but it is one of the largest and most versatile, known for its deep field images that have provided a deeper look into space and time. This telescope is named after an American astronomer who is famous for his discovery of the universe's expansion. What is the name of this telescope that has allowed astronomers to observe the most distant stars and galaxies ever seen",
            "answers": ["Hubble Space Telescope"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This ancient trade route played a critical role in the spread of Buddhism from India to East Asia. It was established during the Han Dynasty around 130 B.C, and famous travelers like Marco Polo and Ibn Battuta traversed the route, documenting their journeys. Name this historic trade route which connected China with the Mediterranean.",
            "answers": ["The Silk Road"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This peak experiences geological uplift, growing approximately 4 mm every year. Its \"death zone\" above 8,000 meters is notorious for its harsh conditions, where the thin air contains insufficient oxygen to sustain human life for extended periods, contributing to the peril many climbers face. Successfully ascended for the first time by Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay in 1953, this mountain is renowned globally. What is the name of this mountain, known as the highest point on Earth?",
            "answers": ["Mount Everest"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This actress made her stage debut in the play \"The Playboy of Seville\" in 1971. She is known for her ability to master almost any accent, from a British accent in \"The Iron Lady\" to a Polish one in \"Sophie's Choice.\" She holds the record for the most Academy Award nominations of any actor. Known for her roles in diverse films from \"Kramer vs. Kramer\" to \"The Devil Wears Prada,\" who is this acclaimed actress often described as the \"best actress of her generation\"?",
            "answers": ["Meryl Streep"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This golf tournament is the only major that does not rotate between courses, being held annually at the same location since its inception in 1934. It is known for its green jacket, which is awarded to the champion and must be returned to the clubhouse after a year. The event was won by Scottie Scheffler in 2024 and 2022 which Jon Rahm winning in between. Held in Augusta, Georgia, what is the name of this prestigious golf tournament, one of the four major championships in professional golf?",
            "answers": ["The Masters"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This American virologist was born in New York City in 1914. After focusing on influenza research, he shifted his attention to a viral disease that caused widespread fear and paralysis, particularly affecting children. In a significant act of public service, he chose not to patent his greatest medical discovery, famously stating, \"Could you patent the sun?\" His research led to the first effective vaccine against polio, introduced in 1955. What is the name of this influential medical researcher?",
            "answers": ["Jonas Salk"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This international competition features a trophy made of 18-carat gold and weighs approximately 6 kilograms. The inaugural tournament was held in 1930, hosted by Uruguay, who also won the title. It is the most watched sporting event globally, surpassing even the Olympic Games in viewership. Held every four years, teams from around the world compete, but only Brazil has won five times, the most by any country. What is the name of this prestigious international football tournament?",
            "answers": ["FIFA World Cup", "world cup"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This ruler of the Mali Empire during the early 14th century is celebrated not only for his wealth but also for his contributions to the spread of Islam in West Africa. He embarked on a famous pilgrimage to Mecca in 1324, which included a procession of thousands of attendants and camels laden with gold. His journey through Cairo was notably extravagant, causing a temporary devaluation of gold in the region due to his generous distributions. Under his reign, the legendary city of Timbuktu flourished as a center of trade and Islamic scholarship, marked by the construction of the Djinguereber Mosque. Who is this emperor, often cited as one of the wealthiest people in history?",
            "answers": ["Mansa Musa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This marine structure is large enough to be visible from space, comprising over 2,900 individual reefs and 900 islands. It hosts a significant population of dugongs and is one of the most biodiverse ecosystems on the planet. The reef is a breeding area for humpback whales migrating from the Antarctic. Located off the coast of Queensland in northeastern Australia, it is the world's largest coral reef system. What is the name of this UNESCO World Heritage Site known for its vibrant marine life?",
            "answers": ["Great Barrier Reef"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This artist served in the First Regiment of African Light Cavalry in Algeria for two years. He suffered from cataracts in his later years, which greatly influenced his shift to broader brushstrokes and bolder color choices in his paintings. He is known for his detailed garden at Giverny, which he transformed into a living canvas and used as inspiration for many works. His series on water lilies and scenes of the French countryside are celebrated globally. Name this French painter, a founding father of Impressionism.",
            "answers": ["Claude Monet"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Constructed between 1792 and 1800, this iconic building was designed by Irish-born architect James Hoban. It has 132 rooms, 35 bathrooms, and 6 levels in the residence. It was rebuilt after being burned down during the War of 1812 in an event known as the Burning of Washington. Its first resident was President John Adams. What is this famous building called?",
            "answers": ["White House"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This novel intricately portrays the clash of cultures between feudal Japan and the Western world during the early 17th century. It is based on the historical adventures of an English navigator who becomes a samurai and political player within the Japanese feudal system. Published in 1975, it became a bestseller and was later adapted into a successful television miniseries in 1980 and again in 2024. What is the name of this historical novel by James Clavell that explores the rise of a foreigner in the Japanese samurai-led society?",
            "answers": ["Shogun"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This actor began his career with appearances in television commercials before moving on to recurring roles in TV series such as \"Growing Pains.\" He is a committed environmentalist, founding a non-profit organization focused on global warming and preserving Earth's biodiversity. He received critical acclaim for his performance in \"What's Eating Gilbert Grape\" at a young age. Known for his collaborations with director Martin Scorsese in films like \"The Wolf of Wall Street\" and \"Shutter Island,\" who is this Oscar-winning actor famous for his role in \"Titanic\"?",
            "answers": ["Leonardo DiCaprio"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Constructed over several dynasties, this extensive fortification stretches more than 13,000 miles and was primarily built using tamped earth and later enhanced with brick and stone. Its construction began as early as the 7th century BC, with significant extensions during the Ming Dynasty. Originally designed to protect against nomadic invasions, it also controlled immigration and facilitated duties on goods transported along the Silk Road. What is this historical landmark?",
            "answers": ["The Great Wall of China", "great wall"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Initially derived from the pancreases of dogs and later from cattle and pigs, this hormone plays a critical role in part of the body's metabolic regulation. Its first use in treating a human patient was in 1922. This medical advancement earned the discovering scientist the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1923. Today, it is synthesized using recombinant DNA technology, providing essential treatment for diabetes patients worldwide. What is this life-saving hormone called?",
            "answers": ["Insulin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This ancient lake contains over 20% of the world's unfrozen freshwater reserve. It earned the nickname \"Gal\u00e1pagos of Russia\" due to its unique biodiversity. It is home to the world's only freshwater seal species. This UNESCO World Heritage Site boasts an exceptional array of endemic species. Located in southern Siberia, it is the world's deepest lake. What is the name of this lake, often referred to as the 'Pearl of Siberia'?",
            "answers": ["Lake Baikal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Before his infamous legal battles, this individual had a successful career in advertising, notably appearing in commercials for the Hertz rental car company. He set records in the NFL, including rushing over 2,000 yards in a single season, a feat achieved during a 14-game season. His transition to film and television included roles in movies and the popular \"Naked Gun\" series. In 1994, he was tried and acquitted in a highly publicized and controversial criminal trial for the murders of his ex-wife Nicole Brown Simpson and her friend Ronald Goldman. Who is this infamous former NFL running back and actor who died in 2024?",
            "answers": ["O.J. Simpson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This competition is one of the most grueling one-day sporting events in the world, combining three continuous and sequential endurance races. It starts with a 2.4-mile swim, followed by a 112-mile bicycle ride, and finishes with a marathon 26.2-mile run, raced in that order without a break. Originating in Hawaii in 1978 as a challenge among groups of athletes to see who was the fittest\u2014swimmers, cyclists, or runners\u2014it has grown into a global phenomenon. What is the name of this triathlon that tests the limits of human endurance?",
            "answers": ["Ironman", "Ironman Triathlon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This film features a famous scene with a severed horse's head, which was real and acquired from a dog food company. The hauntingly beautiful score for the film was composed by Nino Rota. It is based on a novel by Mario Puzo and portrays the powerful Italian-American crime family of Don Vito Corleone. The film launched the careers of several actors, including Al Pacino, who plays Michael Corleone. Directed by Francis Ford Coppola, what is the name of this iconic film that won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1972?",
            "answers": ["\"The Godfather\"", "Godfather"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This historic chapel's ceiling was originally painted blue and decorated with stars before being replaced by the artwork that is seen today. It serves as the site for the Papal conclave, where new popes are elected. Renowned for its Renaissance art, particularly the frescoes that cover the interior, it features works by several prominent artists of the period, including Botticelli, Perugino, and Michelangelo. Michelangelo's contributions include not only the ceiling but also the iconic \"The Last Judgment\" on the altar wall. What is the name of this chapel located in Vatican City, famous for its magnificent Renaissance art?",
            "answers": ["The Sistine Chapel"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Before joining NASA, this astronaut flew 78 combat missions during the Korean War and tested high-speed aircraft, including the X-15. He was part of the Gemini 8 mission, achieving the first successful docking of two spacecraft in orbit. He later became the first person to walk on the moon, famously declaring, \"That's one small step for [a] man, one giant leap for mankind.\" Who is this pioneering astronaut?",
            "answers": ["Neil Armstrong"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This painting was created during the artist's time at the Saint-Paul-de-Mausole asylum in Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence, France, after he voluntarily admitted himself. It depicts the view from the east-facing window of his asylum room, though it was painted from memory during the day. Characterized by swirling clouds in a starry night and a bright crescent moon, its vibrant colors and emotional depth are a signature of the artist's turbulent state of mind. Currently housed in the Museum of Modern Art in New York City, this work is one of the most recognized paintings in the history of Western culture. Name this iconic 1889 painting by Vincent van Gogh.",
            "answers": ["The Starry Night"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This television series was pitched by its creator, Vince Gilligan, as a story where the protagonist transforms into the antagonist. It features a character named Saul Goodman, who was later the subject of a successful spin-off prequel series. Filmed primarily in Albuquerque, New Mexico, it uses the unique landscape as a backdrop to its intense narrative. The series centers on Walter White, a high school chemistry teacher turned methamphetamine manufacturer. What is the name of this critically acclaimed series that won multiple Emmy Awards for its lead actor, Bryan Cranston?",
            "answers": ["\"Breaking Bad\"", "Breaking Bad"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This South American river is home to the uniquely colored and intelligent pink river dolphin. It flows through the world's largest tropical rainforest, encompassing an area twice the size of India. Despite its vast length, it has no bridges due to its width and the dense forest surrounding much of its length. It is the second-longest river globally but discharges the largest volume of water, influencing the Atlantic Ocean up to 100 miles from its mouth. What is the name of this river?",
            "answers": ["Amazon River"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Originally built between 1871 and 1888 to accommodate the growing staff of the White House, this French Second Empire-style building is located next to the West Wing. It was initially known as the State, War, and Navy Building, reflecting its original occupants. Since 2002, its name honor has honored the 34th U.S. President. What is the official name of this building where the Vice President has an office?",
            "answers": [
                "Eisenhower Executive Office Building",
                "EEOB",
                "Eisenhower"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "First isolated using simple adhesive tape, this material was discovered at the University of Manchester by Andre Geim and Konstantin Novoselov, who were later awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 2010 for their work. It is notable for being just one atom thick, making it one of the thinnest yet strongest materials ever tested.What is this two-dimensional material composed of a single layer of carbon atoms arranged in a honeycomb lattice?",
            "answers": ["Graphene"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete has a successful fashion line and has also been involved in numerous off-court ventures, including voice acting in animated films. She won her first major championship at the U.S. Open in 1999, setting the stage for one of the most dominant careers in tennis. Known for her powerful playing style and strong serve, she has won 23 Grand Slam singles titles, the most by any player in the Open Era. Who is this iconic tennis player, often celebrated as one of the greatest athletes of all time?",
            "answers": ["Serena Williams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This period saw the development of the printing press by Johannes Gutenberg, significantly impacting the accessibility of knowledge. Notably, it emphasized humanism, redefining the intellectual landscape of Europe.It heralded major advancements in arts, introducing techniques like perspective in painting, represented by masters such as Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo. Name this cultural phenomenon that began in 14th century Florence and was characterized by a revival of classical learning and wisdom, a shift that distanced Europe from the Middle Ages.",
            "answers": ["The Renaissance"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This country is home to one of the world's oldest continuous major civilizations, with historical and urban settlements dating back to 4000 BC. It was known as Persia until 1935 and has a significant role in the history of the silk road and international trade. The nation is also known for its substantial oil reserves, ranking as the world's fourth-largest holder of oil. It features a diverse landscape ranging from arid mountains to lush forests. What is the name of this country that launched an air attack at Israel after they destroyed it's embassy in Syria?",
            "answers": ["Iran"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This historical figure was born an Archduchess of Austria before becoming the Queen of France through her marriage to Louis XVI. Known for her extravagant lifestyle amid France's financial crisis, she was a controversial queen, often misquoted in response to hearing that the French peasants had no bread. Her reputation, whether deserved or not, fueled populist rage that contributed to the climactic moments of the French Revolution. She met her end by guillotine in 1793 during the Reign of Terror. Who is this queen, often remembered for her dramatic downfall?",
            "answers": ["Marie Antoinette"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed by a French mathematician in the early 19th century, this mathematical transform is essential for analyzing the frequencies contained in a signal. It decomposes a function or a dataset into a spectrum of its sine and cosine components, enabling engineers and scientists to work with the frequency domain rather than time domain. This technique has wide-ranging applications, including image processing, signal analysis, and quantum physics. What is the name of this transformative analysis method, named after its inventor?",
            "answers": ["Fourier Transform"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Argentine footballer is known for his low center of gravity and dribbling skills. He began his professional career with FC Barcelona, where he spent over two decades, setting records for the most goals scored for a single club. Renowned for his precise left foot, he has won numerous Ballon d'Or awards, distinguishing him as one of the best players of his generation. In 2021, he made a high-profile transfer to Paris Saint-Germain. What is the name of this iconic soccer player, often cited as one of the greatest footballers of all time?",
            "answers": ["Lionel Messi"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic ballet, first performed in 1877 at the Bolshoi Theatre in Moscow, was initially met with criticism but has since become one of the most beloved ballets worldwide. Its music was composed by Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky, and the ballet's plot revolves around a princess turned into a swan by an evil sorcerer's curse. Known for its demanding choreography, particularly the role of the dual lead of Odette/Odile, this ballet is a staple in the classical repertoire. What is the name of this ballet which was made into a movie starring Natalie Portman?",
            "answers": ["Swan Lake"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Canadian actor was born in Beirut, Lebanon, in 1964 and first gained major Hollywood attention for his performance in \"Speed.\" Known for his range, he has appeared in everything from romantic comedies like \"Something's Gotta Give\" to supernatural thrillers like \"Constantine.\" Off-screen, he is lauded for his humility and philanthropic efforts, particularly his contributions to cancer research and children\u2019s hospitals. He is also celebrated for his role as Neo in the \"Matrix\" trilogy and as the titular character in the \"John Wick\" film series. What is the name of this versatile and well-respected actor?",
            "answers": ["Keanu Reeves"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American politician from Louisiana, a member of the Republican Party, has served in the U.S. House of Representatives since 2017. He represents Louisiana's 4th congressional district, which includes the northwestern part of the state. Known for his strong conservative views, he has been a vocal advocate for constitutional conservatism, emphasizing fiscal responsibility, limited government, and traditional family values. In 2023, he was elected as the Speaker of the House, becoming one of the key figures in the national political landscape. What is the name of this politician who currently holds the position of Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives?",
            "answers": ["Mike Johnson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Flowing through more countries than any other river in the world, this major European waterway starts in the Black Forest mountains of western Germany and extends through Central and Eastern Europe to the Black Sea. It has been a vital conduit for cultural exchange among the diverse regions along its path, historically serving as a long-standing frontier of the Roman Empire. Today, it plays a crucial role in the regions\u2019 commerce, environmental sustainability, and tourism. What is the name of this second-longest river in Europe, known for connecting ten countries?",
            "answers": ["The Danube"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This iconic national park, located in California's Sierra Nevada mountains, was established in 1890. It was created largely due to the advocacy of naturalist John Muir. It includes one of the tallest waterfalls in North America as well as giant, ancient sequoia trees, and spectacular granite cliffs. What is the name of this national park known for its stunning natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["Yosemite National Park"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Known for his extraordinary height for a sprinter, this Jamaican athlete revolutionized the science of sprinting, focusing heavily on his start technique and stride efficiency. He set the world record for the 100 meters, 200 meters, and 4x100 meters relay, and his iconic celebration pose has become synonymous with his name. Dominating three consecutive Olympic Games, he secured gold medals in all three sprint events at Beijing 2008, London 2012, and Rio 2016. What is the name of this athlete, often referred to as the fastest man alive?",
            "answers": ["Usain Bolt"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Invented by Nikola Tesla in the late 19th century, this electrical resonant transformer circuit is used to produce high-voltage, low-current, high-frequency alternating-current electricity. Notable for creating impressive electrical arcs and being used in entertainment and educational displays, it was originally developed as part of Tesla's experiments with wireless lighting and electrical power distribution. What is the name of this device that exemplifies Tesla\u2019s work in electrical engineering?",
            "answers": ["Tesla Coil", "coil"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 2010 science fiction film directed by Christopher Nolan features a skilled thief who can enter people's dreams to steal secrets from their subconscious. His greatest challenge involves a complex task where he must implant an idea into a CEO's mind through a layered dream sequence. Known for its elaborate visual effects and a plot that weaves through various levels of consciousness, the film is also famous for its open-ended conclusion, symbolized by a spinning top. What is the name of this critically acclaimed film that explores the concept of dream manipulation?",
            "answers": ["\"Inception\""],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Founded in 1769, this Ivy League institution was originally established to educate Native Americans in Christian theology and the English way of life. This university was the first of an elite group of American universities to bring back a requirement for ACT or SAT scores after the COVID-19 pandemic. Name this Ivy League school located in Hanover, New Hampshire.",
            "answers": ["Dartmouth"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This document, originally issued in 1215, was a result of the political crisis between King John of England and a group of rebel barons within his kingdom. It was first drafted by the Archbishop of Canterbury to make peace between the unpopular King and the rebels. Over time, it has become a symbol of liberty and the rule of law, particularly noted for its role in shaping the legal system of the British constitutional monarchy. What is the name of this historic charter often credited as a foundational document for modern democracy?",
            "answers": ["Magna Carta"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This pivotal event was triggered by legislation passed in 1773 that aimed to rescue the financially struggling British East India Company. It involved a late-night act of rebellion where protestors, some disguised as Mohawk Indians, boarded three ships in a famous harbor. What is this event, famously associated with the phrase \"No taxation without representation\"?",
            "answers": ["The Boston Tea Party"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This figure from Norse mythology is known for his cunning and deceptive nature, often causing as much trouble for the other gods as he resolves. A shape-shifter capable of changing both form and gender, he plays a pivotal role in many myths, including the events leading up to Ragnarok, the end of the world in Norse legend. His complex character has inspired various modern portrayals, including a popular supervillain in the Marvel Cinematic Universe. Known as the Norse god of mischief, what is his name?",
            "answers": ["Loki"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Holding about 90% of the world\u2019s ice and 70% of its fresh water, this continent is crucial for global climate regulation. Governed by an international treaty that designates it as a scientific preserve and prohibits military activity, it has no indigenous human population and supports only temporary research communities. The extreme environment, featuring the coldest temperatures recorded on Earth, facilitates studies ranging from glaciology to climate science. What is the name of this continent, renowned for its expansive ice sheets and unique legal status?",
            "answers": ["Antarctica"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "The first successful use of this invention was achieved in 1903 in Kitty Hawk, North Carolina. The initial use lasted only 12 seconds but covered 120 feet. Today, it is integral to global transportation and commerce. This invention revolutionized travel and military strategy, leading to the first nonstop transatlantic flight in 1919. What is this device which was invented by the Wright Brothers?",
            "answers": ["airplane", "plane"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed in the early 21st century, this groundbreaking biotechnological tool allows for precise editing of the DNA in the genomes of living organisms. It utilizes a component of a bacterial immune system, which captures pieces of DNA from viruses, to make precise cuts in specific DNA sequences. This innovation has transformed genetic research, offering potential treatments for a myriad of genetic diseases and advancements in agricultural science. What is the name of this powerful gene-editing technology?",
            "answers": ["CRISPR", "CRISPR-Cas9"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Originating in Asia and spreading via the Silk Road, this pandemic reached Europe in the mid-14th century, causing massive social upheaval and labor shortages due to its high mortality rate. The pathogen was transmitted by fleas carried on black rats aboard trading ships, leading to rapid spread through congested urban areas. Characterized by painful swellings called buboes, this devastating outbreak is known as one of the deadliest pandemics in human history. What is this historical epidemic commonly called?",
            "answers": ["The Black Death", "bubonic plague", "black plague"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "In the arid regions surrounding this hypersaline lake, ancient manuscripts that include some of the earliest known religious texts were discovered, offering significant insights into early religious practices. Located at the lowest land elevation on Earth, this body of water allows swimmers to float effortlessly due to its extremely high salinity, which also supports a thriving health and cosmetics industry based on its mineral-rich mud. Bordered by Jordan to the east and Israel and the West Bank to the west, what is the name of this unique lake renowned for its buoyancy and therapeutic properties?",
            "answers": ["Dead Sea"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This prestigious tennis tournament, known for its unique tradition of consuming strawberries and cream by spectators, maintains a strict no-play policy on the middle Sunday to allow the grass courts to rest. Established in 1877, it is the oldest tennis tournament in the world and is particularly noted for its requirement that players wear all-white attire. Celebrated for being played on outdoor grass courts, this event is one of the four Grand Slam tournaments held annually. What is the name of this tournament, regarded as the most prestigious in the sport of tennis?",
            "answers": ["Wimbledon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Launched in 2016, this Netflix original series combines 1980s nostalgia with supernatural and horror elements. Set in the fictional town of Hawkins, Indiana, the story begins with the mysterious disappearance of a young boy, which leads to revelations about secret government experiments and a girl with psychokinetic abilities. Created by the Duffer Brothers, this series has become a cultural phenomenon. What is the name of this show?",
            "answers": ["\"Stranger Things\""],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This U.S. government agency is responsible for tax collection and tax law enforcement. It administers the Internal Revenue Code enacted by Congress. Established in 1862 during the presidency of Abraham Lincoln, its primary purpose was to fund the Civil War. The agency is also known for its role in the annual observance of April 15th as Tax Day, the deadline for filing individual tax returns. In recent years, it has implemented various modernization efforts to improve taxpayer service and compliance. What is the name of this agency tasked with ensuring the nation's tax laws are followed?",
            "answers": ["Internal Revenue Service", "IRS"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This British author began his career as a political journalist before achieving fame with serialized novels that highlighted the social and economic challenges of Victorian England. Notable for exploring themes like poverty, child labor, and social injustice, his vivid characters and detailed settings have made works such as \"Oliver Twist,\" \"David Copperfield,\" and \"A Christmas Carol\" enduring classics. Name this author whose works have been adapted into numerous plays and films, continuing to influence popular culture.",
            "answers": ["Charles Dickens"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Scheduled to be the third time this city has hosted the Summer Olympics, the 2024 event plans to integrate iconic landmarks as backdrops for competitions. This edition of the Games will also introduce breakdancing as an official Olympic sport. What is the host nation for the olympics which will feature beach volleyball at the foot of the Eiffel Tower and fencing at the Grand Palais?",
            "answers": ["Paris", "Paris, France"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American basketball legend is renowned for his six NBA championships with the Chicago Bulls and two Olympic gold medals. Known for his scoring ability, defensive skills, and clutch performances, he won five MVP awards and is often regarded as the greatest basketball player of all time. What is the name of this iconic athlete, also famous for his global brand and \"Air Jordan\" sneakers?",
            "answers": ["Michael Jordan", "jordan", "air jordan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This public health concept occurs when a sufficient proportion of a population becomes immune to an infectious disease, either through vaccination or previous infections, thus providing indirect protection to those who are not immune. It helps control the spread of contagious diseases and is crucial for protecting vulnerable individuals who cannot be vaccinated. What is the term used to describe this phenomenon, which plays a key role in preventing outbreaks and achieving disease control?",
            "answers": ["Herd Immunity"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Initiated as a military project during the Cold War, this early computer network was developed by the Advanced Research Projects Agency. The first message sent on this network was supposed to be \"LOGIN\" but famously crashed after the first two letters. This network employed packet switching and was a precursor to the modern Internet. What is the name of this groundbreaking project that fundamentally changed the way information is disseminated and communicated globally?",
            "answers": ["ARPANET"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This famous mural painting by an Italian Renaissance artist depicts Jesus Christ's final meal with his apostles before his crucifixion, as described in the Gospel of John. Notable for its detailed representation of the apostles' reactions and the use of perspective, it is located in the Convent of Santa Maria delle Grazie in Milan. What is the name of this masterpiece, created by Leonardo da Vinci?",
            "answers": ["\"The Last Supper\"", "last supper"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This monarch, born in 1819, was known for her strict standards of personal morality and a lengthy reign that saw the expansion of the British Empire. Her era is often associated with the height of the Industrial Revolution. She was the granddaughter of King George III and the mother of nine children. Name this queen, whose name defines an entire age of British history.",
            "answers": ["Queen Victoria"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 1977 album by a British-American rock band is one of the best-selling albums of all time, noted for its production quality and harmonious sound despite the band members' tumultuous relationships at the time. Hits like \"Go Your Own Way,\" \"Dreams,\" and \"The Chain\" have made it a classic. What is the name of this Fleetwood Mac album, which was largely influenced by personal strife among band members?",
            "answers": ["Rumours", "rumors"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This tropical paradise is made up of 26 atolls in the Indian Ocean, comprising over 1,000 coral islands. Known for its beaches, blue lagoons, and extensive reefs, the country is also the lowest-lying nation in the world, with an average ground level of just 1.5 meters above sea level. It gained independence from British protection in 1965. What is the name of this island nation, renowned for its vibrant marine life and luxury resorts?",
            "answers": ["The Maldives", "maldives"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This European mountain range features the Great St Bernard Pass, a historical route used since Roman times, and is renowned for its extensive ski resorts and hiking trails. Stretching approximately 1,200 kilometers across eight countries including France, Switzerland, Italy, and Austria. The range includes Mont Blanc, the highest peak at 4,809 meters. What is the name of this prominent mountain range known for its scenic beauty and outdoor recreational opportunities?",
            "answers": ["The Alps", "alps"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This poem, first published in 1845, is known for its melodic and dramatic qualities, exploring themes of despair, longing, and the torment of loss. The narrative follows a grieving man who encounters a mysterious raven, whose repeated word \"Nevermore\" enhances the poem's atmosphere of melancholy and doom. Written by an American writer famous for his tales and poems of horror and mystery, what is the name of this poem by Edgar Allan Poe?",
            "answers": ["The Raven"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This device, first successfully demonstrated in 1876, transformed global communication. Its early versions transmitted sound over a single wire, often requiring operators to connect calls. The inventor originally considered it an improvement to the telegraph. What device was famously first used by Alexander Graham Bell to summin his assistant with the words, \"Mr. Watson, come here, I want to see you\"?",
            "answers": ["telephone", "phone"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This type of vaccine uses a synthetic strand of genetic material called messenger RNA to instruct cells in the body to produce a protein similar to one found in a virus. This protein triggers an immune response, preparing the body to fight the actual virus if encountered. First widely used during the COVID-19 pandemic, what is this innovative category of vaccines called?",
            "answers": ["mRNA Vaccines", "mrna"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Founded by a Roman Emperor in 330 AD, this city served as a capital for the Roman, Byzantine, and Ottoman empires. Renowned for its strategic position between Europe and Asia, it was pivotal in controlling the passage between the Black Sea and the Mediterranean. The city fell to the Ottoman Empire in 1453, an event that marked the end of the Byzantine Empire. It was later renamed Istanbul. Name this historically significant city that was once known as the \"Queen of Cities.\"",
            "answers": [
                "Constantinople",
                "The Fall of Constantinople",
                "siege of constantionple",
                "constantinople"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This German Formula One driver is renowned for his seven World Championships, tying him with Lewis Hamilton for the most titles in the history of the sport. Known for his precision driving and competitiveness, he drove for teams like Benetton and Ferrari, where he helped build the latter into one of the most successful teams in F1 history. What is the name of this legendary driver, often celebrated as one of the greatest Formula One racers ever?",
            "answers": ["Michael Schumacher", "Mick Schumacher"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic American television series, created by Rod Serling, premiered in 1959 and is renowned for its twist endings and moral lessons. The show blended elements of science fiction, horror, and fantasy to explore complex social and existential themes through standalone, often surreal narratives. What is the name of this groundbreaking anthology series?",
            "answers": ["The Twilight Zone", "twilight zone"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This popular online puzzle game, created by software engineer Josh Wardle, quickly gained a massive following after its release in 2021. The game challenges players to guess a five-letter word within six attempts, using color-coded feedback to show correct letters and placements. Its simple yet engaging format led to its acquisition by The New York Times. What is the name of this daily word game that has become a global phenomenon?",
            "answers": ["Wordle"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This German composer and pianist was a crucial figure in the transition between the Classical and Romantic eras in Western music. His compositions include 9 symphonies, 5 piano concertos, and a significant number of sonatas, among them the famously emotive \u201cMoonlight Sonata.\u201d Despite his progressive hearing loss, he continued to compose some of his greatest works, which remain central to the music repertoire today. What is the name of this influential composer, known for his symphony \u201cOde to Joy\u201d?",
            "answers": ["Ludwig van Beethoven", "beethoven"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Established after World War I as part of the Treaty of Versailles in 1920, this international organization was intended to maintain world peace and prevent future conflicts. Despite its efforts, it struggled with membership and enforcement power, failing to stop aggression from Axis powers in the 1930s. It was eventually replaced by the United Nations after World War II. Name this precursor to the United Nations, which aimed to promote diplomatic dialogue and collective security.",
            "answers": ["The League of Nations"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Swiss tennis player, renowned for his graceful play and sportsmanship, has won 20 Grand Slam singles titles, a record he held until surpassed by his rivals. Known for his prowess on grass courts, especially at Wimbledon where he has won a record eight times, he is celebrated as one of the greatest tennis players of all time. What is the name of this legendary tennis icon?",
            "answers": ["Roger Federer"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This computer launched in 1977 as one of the first to come with a color display and was sold as a fully assembled circuit board. It included a keyboard and was notably user-friendly, which helped it stand out in a market dominated by technical kits for hobbyists. Name this early PC that helped launch the personal computer revolution and solidified its company, founded by two Steves, as a key player in the technology sector.",
            "answers": ["Apple II", "Apple 2"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These computational systems are inspired by the biological neural networks that constitute animal brains. Utilized in machine learning, they are composed of layers of interconnected nodes or \"neurons\" that can learn to recognize patterns and make decisions by adjusting the strength of the connections based on the data they process. What is the term for these powerful tools in artificial intelligence that mimic the structure and function of the human brain?",
            "answers": ["Neural Networks"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American businessman and television personality turned politician was known for his real estate ventures and the reality TV show \"The Apprentice\" before entering the political arena. In 2016, he won the U.S. presidential election as the Republican candidate, becoming the 45th President of the United States. Noted for his unconventional approach to politics and governance, he is also the first president without prior military or government service. What is the name of this figure, who was impeached twice during his term?",
            "answers": ["Donald Trump"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 1993 film, directed by Steven Spielberg, is noted for its poignant use of black and white cinematography, and it won seven Academy Awards, including Best Picture. It tells the story of a German businessman who saved over a thousand Polish-Jewish refugees during the Holocaust by employing them in his factories. What is the name of this powerful historical drama?",
            "answers": ["Schindler's List"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This mountain range extends over 7,000 kilometers and is known for its varied climates, from arid to one of the wettest places on Earth. It is home to many unique species and reaches its highest point at Mount Aconcagua, which is the highest peak outside Asia. Passing through seven countries, it is the longest continental mountain range located along the western coast of South America. What is the name of this significant mountain range?",
            "answers": ["The Andes", "Andes"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This iconic statue representing a Roman goddess was designed by Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Auguste Bartholdi and dedicated on October 28, 1886. It features a broken chain at its feet, symbolizing freedom and the abolition of slavery. The statue's exterior is made of copper sheets, which have oxidized to form its green patina. Initially, it served as a lighthouse, guiding ships into New York Harbor. What is this American landmark commonly known as?",
            "answers": ["Statue of Liberty"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This ancient civilization, known for its road systems, architectural achievements like the Colosseum, and influential legal structures, became one of the largest empires in history. It reached its peak under Emperor Trajan and eventually split into Western and Eastern segments. The empire began expanding from a city on the Italian Peninsula in the 8th century BC. Name this empire, famous for its vast influence across Europe.",
            "answers": ["The Roman Empire", "roman"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This term describes the boundary around a black hole beyond which no radiation can escape. It shares its name with a 1997 sci-fi horror film that explores a spaceship encountering a similar boundary in space. The concept was first detailed by the German astronomer Karl Schwarzschild. What is this term, which marks the limits of a black hole's gravitational influence?",
            "answers": ["Event Horizon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American filmmaker directed iconic films across genres, including \"2001: A Space Odyssey\" and \"The Shining.\" Known for his meticulous craftsmanship and thematic complexity, his works are celebrated for innovative cinematography and deep philosophical underpinnings. What is the name of this influential director whose style has left a lasting impact on the film industry?",
            "answers": ["Stanley Kubrick"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American golfer has won 15 major championships, including five Masters Tournaments. Famous for his red shirt on final-round Sundays and his influence in making golf a global sport, he is one of the most recognized and highest-earning athletes in the world. What is the name of this iconic golfer, often referred to simply by his first name?",
            "answers": ["Tiger Woods", "tiger"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its two major tributaries with the names, Blue and White, this river traverses eleven countries, including Uganda, Sudan, and Egypt. It plays a vital role in agriculture, particularly for Egyptian civilizations since ancient times. Flowing northward through northeastern Africa and draining into the Mediterranean Sea, this is recognized as the longest river in the world. What is the name of this significant African river?",
            "answers": ["The Nile River", "nile"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This novel, published in 1922 by an Irish author, is known for its stream of consciousness technique and deep exploration of the mundane activities of its characters during a single day in Dublin. The narrative parallels the structure of Homer\u2019s epic, \"The Odyssey,\" with its characters reflecting modern versions of those from the ancient text. What is the name of this complex and highly influential modernist work by James Joyce?",
            "answers": ["\"Ulysses\"", "ulysses"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This region, located on the eastern coast of the Mediterranean Sea, has been a focal point of conflict between Israel and Hamas. The conflict in this region grew into a full war after terrorist attacks by Hamas in Israel on October 7, 2023. What is the name of this territory that has been at the center of protracted and intense geopolitical strife?",
            "answers": ["Gaza Strip", "Gaza"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This series of approximately 250 oil paintings by a French Impressionist captures the artist's flower garden at his home in Giverny, with the main focus on a pond. Created during the last 30 years of his life, these paintings show the artist's shifting focus from representing the garden's landscape to the play of light and shadow across the pond's surface. What is the name of this series by Claude Monet, celebrated for its exploration of perception and natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["Water Lilies"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This pivotal event of World War II occurred on June 6, 1944. The planning of this operation was shrouded in secrecy, utilizing deception techniques such as fake equipment and phantom armies. It involved the largest amphibious invasion in history with the use of over 5,000 vessels and 13,000 aircraft and marked a turning point in the war against Nazi Germany. Originally codenamed Operation Overlord, what is this historic day commonly known as?",
            "answers": ["D-Day", "D Day", "Battle of Normandy"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1995, this groundbreaking film was the first feature-length movie created entirely using computer-generated imagery (CGI). It tells the story of a group of toys that come to life when humans aren't looking, led by Woody the cowboy and Buzz Lightyear, a space ranger. This film set new standards in animation and launched a successful franchise. What is the name of this pioneering animated film produced by Pixar?",
            "answers": ["Toy Story"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team has a storied history with 17 championships, tying them for the most in league history. Known for their purple and gold colors, they have been home to basketball legends such as Magic Johnson, Kobe Bryant, and LeBron James. What is the name of this iconic basketball franchise based in Los Angeles?",
            "answers": ["Los Angeles Lakers", "Lakers"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Asian mountain range is known for containing many of the world's highest peaks, including over 100 that exceed 7,200 meters. It is home to the famous K2 and the highest point on Earth, Mount Everest. The range also forms a natural barrier between the Indian subcontinent and the Tibetan Plateau. What is the name of this extensive mountain range, crucial for its climatic impact and cultural significance in the regions it spans?",
            "answers": ["The Himalayas", "himalayan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This port city in southeastern Ukraine became a focal point during the Russo-Ukrainian War. Heavily industrialized, it is strategically located on the coast of the Sea of Azov, linking it directly to the Black Sea. In 2022, the city endured a significant siege that resulted in widespread destruction and a humanitarian crisis, highlighting the severe impacts of the conflict. What is the name of this city which was subject of an Oscar-winning documentary in 2023?",
            "answers": ["Mariupol"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "First predicted by Albert Einstein's theory of general relativity in 1916, these ripples in spacetime are generated by some of the most violent and energetic processes in the Universe, such as colliding black holes or exploding stars. They were directly detected for the first time in 2015 by the LIGO observatory, confirming a major prediction of Einstein's theory. What are these disturbances in spacetime that share a name with an essential physical force called?",
            "answers": ["Gravitational Waves"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This decisive battle took place on June 18, 1815, near Brussels. It featured a coalition of armies led by the Duke of Wellington and a Prussian army under General Bl\u00fccher, who faced Napoleon Bonaparte\u2019s French troops, and marked the end of the Napoleonic Wars. The defeat led to Napoleon's abdication and exile to Saint Helena. Name this battle, often cited as one of the major turning points in European history.",
            "answers": ["The Battle of Waterloo", "waterloo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Formed by volcanic activity, this archipelago consists of hundreds of islands spread over 1,500 miles in the central Pacific Ocean. It became the 50th U.S. state in 1959 and is known for its rich cultural heritage. The state's major islands include Oahu, Maui, Kauai, and the Big Island. What is the name of this U.S. state, celebrated for its natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["Hawaii", "The Hawaiian Islands", "hawaii"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Founded by Osman I in the late 13th century, this empire expanded across three continents at its peak under Suleiman the Magnificent. Known for its military prowess and cultural synthesis, it significantly influenced Southeastern Europe, Western Asia, and Northern Africa. Name this empire, which had a capital of Constantinople and dissolved after World War I.",
            "answers": [
                "The Ottoman Empire",
                "Ottoman Empire",
                "Turkish Empire"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This British Formula One driver has matched the record for the most World Championships in the sport, with seven titles, sharing this achievement with Michael Schumacher. Known for his skillful driving and advocacy for social issues, he has raced predominantly for Mercedes-Benz and has set numerous records, including the most career wins. What is the name of this influential and successful Formula One racer?",
            "answers": ["Lewis Hamilton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American politician served as a U.S. Senator from Delaware for 36 years before becoming Vice President under Barack Obama from 2009 to 2017. Known for his work on foreign relations, criminal justice, and domestic policy issues, he won the presidential election in 2020 to become the 46th President of the United States. What is the name of this President, notable for being the oldest person inaugurated to this office?",
            "answers": ["Joe Biden"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This American musical blends hip-hop, jazz, R&B, and Broadway styles to tell the story of a forgotten Founding Father. It was inspired by a 2004 biography and features a racially diverse cast to reflect America's contemporary composition rather than its historical one. The show's creator, who also originated the title role, earned widespread acclaim for his innovative approach to storytelling. What is the name of this groundbreaking musical that reimagines the life of Alexander Hamilton?",
            "answers": ["Hamilton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This day in U.S. history witnessed a brave act of passenger resistance aboard United Flight 93, which resulted in the plane crashing into a field in Pennsylvania, thwarting the hijackers' intended attack on the nation's capital. The aftermath of the attacks on this day saw significant changes in U.S. policy, including the establishment of the Department of Homeland Security and stricter aviation security measures. The same day, other hijacked planes struck the World Trade Center and the Pentagon. What is the date of these pivotal events known as in American history?",
            "answers": [
                "9/11",
                "9/11/2001",
                "9/11/01",
                "September 11",
                "September 11 2001"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This popular American sitcom, which debuted in 1994, follows the lives of six friends living in New York City as they navigate the ups and downs of adulthood. Known for its witty dialogue, memorable one-liners, and iconic coffee shop setting, the show remained a top-rated TV show throughout its ten-season run. It has left a lasting impact on television comedy. What is the name of this beloved sitcom?",
            "answers": ["Friends"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This graph, first plotted by scientist Charles David Keeling in 1958, shows the concentration of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) based on continuous measurements taken at the Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii. It is considered one of the most important scientific contributions to the understanding of global climate change because it provides clear evidence of rising CO2 levels over decades. What is this iconic graph that tracks the increasing presence of a key greenhouse gas in Earth's atmosphere called?",
            "answers": ["Keeling Curve"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Revered as sacred by millions, particularly in Hinduism, this river supports one of the world\u2019s highest population densities and is central to agriculture in both India and Bangladesh. Historically significant for centuries, it originates in the Indian Himalayas and flows over 2,525 kilometers into the Bay of Bengal. What is the name of this vital South Asian river?",
            "answers": ["The Ganges River", "Ganges"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Proposed by a British theoretical physicist in 1974, this theoretical prediction suggests that black holes are not entirely black but emit radiation due to quantum effects near the event horizon. This radiation implies that black holes can slowly lose mass and eventually evaporate over astronomical timescales. What is the name of this radiation, named after the scientist who first theorized its existence?",
            "answers": ["Hawking Radiation", "Hawking", "Stephen Hawking"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Italian explorer, sailing under the Spanish flag, set out on his first voyage in 1492 with three ships: the Ni\u00f1a, the Pinta, and the Santa Mar\u00eda. He is often mistakenly credited with being the first European to reach the Americas. His expeditions marked the beginning of European exploration and colonization of the American continents. Name this historical figure whose voyages had a profound impact on the global interactions of the Renaissance era.",
            "answers": ["Christopher Columbus", "columbus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Japanese animated film, released in 2001, became critically acclaimed for its rich storytelling and animation. Directed by Hayao Miyazaki and produced by Studio Ghibli, it tells the story of a young girl navigating a world of spirits and gods after her parents are transformed into pigs. Name this film that won the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature, making it the first and only hand-drawn and non-English-language animated film to win the award.",
            "answers": ["Spirited Away"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This politician is the longest serving Senator from New York. Before he was elected to the senate he served nine terms in the House of Represenatives. He was the first Jewish Senate Majority Leader. Name this current Senate Majority Leader who has led the Democrats in the Senate since 2017.",
            "answers": ["Chuck Schumer", "Charles Schumer", "Shumer"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American golfer, known as \"The Golden Bear,\" has won a record 18 major championships, a mark that stands as the benchmark for success in professional golf. Renowned for his powerful play and strategic approach, he won six Masters Tournaments and four U.S. Open titles among his impressive tally. What is the name of this legendary golfer, celebrated for his dominance in the sport's biggest tournaments?",
            "answers": ["Jack Nicklaus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Initially patented by Joseph Swan, this invention saw significant improvement when a more durable filament material was used by another inventor. It's often associated with a famous American inventor's first major public system of electric illumination. This innovation has evolved into various forms including LED and CFL. What is this invention which is often credited to Thomas Edison and commonly used to illuminate homes and streets?",
            "answers": ["light bulb"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This German composer of the Baroque period is renowned for his intricate compositions and profound influence on the structure of classical music. His works, characterized by their intellectual depth, technical command, and artistic beauty, include the \"Brandenburg Concertos,\" \"The Well-Tempered Clavier,\" and numerous cantatas and fugues. He spent much of his career as a church musician and a Kapellmeister in Leipzig. What is the name of this composer, celebrated for his masterful use of counterpoint and harmony?",
            "answers": ["Johann Sebastian Bach", "bach"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American singer was involved in a highly publicized incident during the Super Bowl XXXVIII halftime show in 2004, which resulted in a nationwide controversy. The performance concluded with a surprise \"wardrobe malfunction\" during a duet with Justin Timberlake, leading to immediate media backlash and changes in broadcast regulations. What is the name of this artist, whose performance led to the coining of the term \"wardrobe malfunction\"?",
            "answers": ["Janet Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This fundamental concept in quantum mechanics, introduced by a German physicist in 1927, states that it is impossible to simultaneously know both the exact position and exact momentum of a particle. The more precisely one property is measured, the less precisely the other can be controlled or known. This principle challenged classical ideas of exactitude in science. Name the physicist who formulated this principle, which has profound implications for the behavior of subatomic particles.",
            "answers": ["Heisenberg's Uncertainty Principle", "Heisenberg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This novel, published in 1925 by a prominent English writer, is set in post-World War I London and spans a single day in the life of its protagonist, who prepares for a party she will host that evening. The narrative delves into the complexities of its characters' thoughts and memories, utilizing the stream of consciousness technique to reveal their inner lives. What is the name of this seminal modernist work which follows Clarissa Dalloway by Virginia Woolf?",
            "answers": ["\"Mrs Dalloway\"", "Mrs. Dalloway"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This national soccer team holds the record for the most FIFA World Cup victories, having won the prestigious tournament five times. Known for their skillful play and prominent players like Pel\u00e9 and Ronaldo, they first won in 1958 and secured their latest title in 2002. What is the name of this country's team, celebrated for its rich football heritage and success on the global stage?",
            "answers": ["Brazil"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This city had over 10 inches of rain fall in a 24 hour period in April 2024. This set a record for the last 75 years in this city which lies in a desert nation known for its oil reserves. This city is also home to the world's tallest building, the Burj Khalifa. Name this city which was recently overwhelmed by flooding in the United Arab Emirates.",
            "answers": ["Dubai"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This geological marvel was first seen by European eyes in 1540, part of an expedition led by Spanish explorers. Despite its remote location, it became more accessible after the construction of a railway bearing its name 1901. This natural wonder was designated as a national park in 1919 by President Woodrow Wilson. What is the name of this famous canyon that was carved over millions of years by the Colorado River?",
            "answers": ["Grand Canyon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This mountain range stretches over 3,000 miles from British Columbia to New Mexico and includes Mount Elbert, its highest peak. Known for the Continental Divide, it forms the eastern portion of the North American Cordillera. This range shares a name with a baseball team based in Denver and has been invoked in beer commercials. What is the name of this iconic North American mountain range?",
            "answers": ["The Rockies", "Rocky Mountains", "rockies"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This transformative period began in Britain in the late 18th century and spread to other parts of the world. It was marked by the transition from hand production methods to machines, new chemical manufacturing and iron production processes, and the rise of the factory system. Notable innovations include the steam engine and spinning jenny. Name this era that dramatically changed economies, societies, and environments across the globe.",
            "answers": ["The Industrial Revolution", "industrial age"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This groundbreaking music video, released in 1983 by an American pop star, revolutionized the music industry with its elaborate narrative and dance sequences. Directed by John Landis and featuring iconic zombie dance moves, the video extended over 13 minutes, blending music with cinematic storytelling. It became a global phenomenon and significantly boosted sales of the album of the same name. What is the name of this influential music video by Michael Jackson?",
            "answers": ["Thriller"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This thought experiment in quantum mechanics involves a hypothetical cat that may be simultaneously both alive and dead, depending on an earlier random event. Devised by an Austrian physicist in 1935, it illustrates the concept of superposition\u2014the ability of a quantum system to be in multiple states at once until it is measured. Name the physicist who created this paradoxical experiment to challenge the Copenhagen interpretation of quantum mechanics.",
            "answers": ["Schr\u00f6dinger's Cat", "Schrodinger"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This period of geopolitical tension between the Soviet Union and the United States spanned from 1947 to 1991. Characterized by the arms race, space competition, and various proxy wars, it never escalated into direct military conflict between the two superpowers. Notable events include the Cuban Missile Crisis and the fall of the Berlin Wall. Name this era marked by the struggle for global supremacy without open warfare.",
            "answers": ["The Cold War"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This major North American river is known for its historical importance as a trade route during the era of steamboats. It flows over 2,300 miles from northern Minnesota to the Gulf of Mexico, making it the second-longest river in the United States. The river also passes through or borders ten states, including Illinois, Iowa, and Louisiana. What is the name of this river, vital for its ecological diversity and economic significance in U.S. history?",
            "answers": ["The Mississippi River", "mississippi"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic statue was sculpted by an Italian Renaissance artist between 1501 and 1504 and stands at over 14 feet tall. Originally commissioned as one of a series of statues for Florence Cathedral, it now resides in the Galleria dell'Accademia in Florence. Representing the Biblical hero who defeated Goliath, it is renowned for its detailed anatomy and expression of calm readiness. What is the name of this famous marble sculpture created by Michelangelo?",
            "answers": ["\"David\"", "david"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Known for his charismatic presence and phrases like \"float like a butterfly, sting like a bee,\" this American boxer became a cultural icon beyond the world of sports. He won the world heavyweight championship three times and participated in several historic boxing matches, including the \"Rumble in the Jungle.\" His refusal to serve in the Vietnam War due to his religious beliefs and stance on civil rights brought him significant attention and controversy. What is the name of this legendary boxer, often referred to as \"The Greatest\"?",
            "answers": ["Muhammad Ali"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This U.S. state, known for its desert climate and picturesque landscapes was admitted to the union in 1912 as the 48th state. This state's Supreme Court recently paved the wave for enforcement of a strict abortion restriction which was passed into law during the U.S. Civil War. What is the name of this southwestern state, recognized for its unique cacti and significant Native American history?",
            "answers": ["Arizona"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This individual won a Grammy Award for his audiobook \"Dreams from My Father\" and taught constitutional law at the University of Chicago Law School. He was the first African American president of the Harvard Law Review in 1990. He was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2009. What is the name of this prominent political figure?",
            "answers": ["Barack Obama"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This women's rights advocate and social reformer was arrested and fined for illegally attempting to vote in the 1872 presidential election.  She was once depicted on a dollar coin issued by the U.S. Treasury, though it failed to gain widespread circulation. She co-founded the National Woman Suffrage Association with Elizabeth Cady Stanton. Name this tireless champion of women's rights",
            "answers": ["Susan B. Anthony"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This dormant volcano in Tanzania is known for its three volcanic cones: Kibo, Mawenzi, and Shira. Popular among climbers and trekkers worldwide, it features a snow-capped summit near the equator, despite being located just 205 miles from the equator. Rising about 5,895 meters (19,341 feet) above sea level, it holds the title of the highest mountain in Africa. What is the name of this mountain, a symbol of towering natural beauty and challenge?",
            "answers": ["Mount Kilimanjaro", "Kilimanjaro"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American director, known for his dynamic storytelling and strong character development, has a long-standing collaboration with actor Robert De Niro, with whom he created classics like \"Taxi Driver\" and \"Raging Bull.\" His films often explore complex themes such as crime, guilt, and redemption. Among his celebrated works is \"Goodfellas,\" a critical and commercial success that redefined the gangster genre. What is the name of this influential filmmaker?",
            "answers": ["Martin Scorsese", "Scorsese", "Marty Scorsese"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American swimmer set the record for the most Olympic medals won by any athlete, totaling 28 medals, including 23 golds. His performances at the 2008 Beijing Olympics, where he won eight gold medals, are particularly celebrated. Who is this legendary swimmer who featured in a series of Subway ads?",
            "answers": ["Michael Phelps"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This musical, based on a French novel of the same name by Gaston Leroux, is renowned for its captivating romance and haunting narrative. It tells the story of a disfigured musical genius, who haunts the Parisian entertainment venue and becomes obsessed with a young soprano, Christine. Composed by Andrew Lloyd Webber, it is one of the longest-running shows on Broadway. What is the name of this iconic musical?",
            "answers": ["The Phantom of the Opera"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This leader implemented the Yassa code to promote trade and communication within his empire, which stretched from Eastern Europe across Asia to the Sea of Japan. He united the nomadic tribes of Northeast Asia, founding the largest contiguous empire in history. His conquests encompassed large parts of Central Asia and China, with his descendants continuing to expand the empire after his death. Name this Mongolian ruler, born in the late 12th century.",
            "answers": ["Genghis Khan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American politician served as the Attorney General of California and then as a United States Senator before making history in her current role. She became the first female Vice President of the United States in January 2021, also making her the highest-ranking female official in U.S. history, and the first African American and South Asian American to hold this office. What is the name of this groundbreaking political figure?",
            "answers": ["Kamala Harris"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed to combat vitamin A deficiency, this genetically modified crop produces beta-carotene in its grain, which the human body can convert into vitamin A. This innovation is especially aimed at improving the health outcomes in developing countries where rice is a staple food but malnutrition is prevalent. What is the colorful name of this biofortified rice that has been altered to address a specific nutritional deficiency?",
            "answers": ["Golden Rice"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known locally as 'Mosi-oa-Tunya,' which translates to 'The Smoke That Thunders,' this natural wonder creates a thunderous roar and a mist that can be seen from miles away. It forms one of the largest curtains of falling water in the world, drawing visitors from all over the globe to its breathtaking views. Designated as a UNESCO World Heritage site, it straddles the border between Zambia and Zimbabwe along the Zambezi River. What is the name of this magnificent waterfall, celebrated as one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the World?",
            "answers": ["Victoria Falls"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Launched in 1588 by King Philip II of Spain, this fleet was one of the largest maritime fleets in European history, consisting of 130 ships manned by 8,000 sailors and over 18,000 soldiers. Its mission was to overthrow Queen Elizabeth I of England and halt the influence of Protestantism in Europe. Despite its formidable size, the fleet suffered a disastrous defeat due to a combination of strategic miscalculations, stormy weather, and effective tactics by the English navy. What is this famous naval campaign commonly known as, which marked a pivotal moment in Anglo-Spanish relations?",
            "answers": ["The Spanish Armada"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This novel intricately portrays the clash of cultures between feudal Japan and the Western world during the early 17th century. It is based on the historical adventures of an English navigator who becomes a samurai and political player within the Japanese feudal system. Published in 1975, it became a bestseller and was later adapted into a successful television miniseries in 1980 and again in 2024. What is the name of this historical novel by James Clavell that explores the rise of a foreigner in the Japanese samurai-led society?",
            "answers": ["Shogun"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This scientist was born in 1822 in a region now part of the Czech Republic and initially entered a monastery where he could receive an education. He conducted hybridization experiments in the monastery's garden, using pea plants to study inheritance patterns. His work laid the foundation for the modern understanding of genetics, though it was largely ignored during his lifetime. What is the name of this pioneer of genetic research, known for his laws of inheritance?",
            "answers": ["Gregor Mendel"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Before becoming president, this man owned a whiskey distillery, one of the largest in the nation. From 1749 to 1750, he served in his first public office as surveyor of Culpeper County in the Colony of Virginia. This Founding Father led the Continental Army in battle against the British during the Revolutionary War. Name this general and first president of the United States.",
            "answers": ["George Washington"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Published in 1925, this iconic American novel captures the spirit of the Roaring Twenties with its themes of decadence, idealism, and the pursuit of the American Dream. Narrated by Nick Carraway, the story delves into the lives of the wealthy occupants of Long Island's North Shore, focusing on his mysterious and affluent neighbor's quest to reunite with a former lover. Celebrated for its sharp critique of social stratification and the elusive nature of happiness, this novel remains a staple of American literature. What is the title of this F. Scott Fitzgerald work, emblematic of the Jazz Age?",
            "answers": ["\"The Great Gatsby\"", "great gatsby"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British singer-songwriter rose to fame with her debut album \"19,\" and further captivated audiences worldwide with her soulful voice in the follow-up album \"21,\" which included hits like \"Rolling in the Deep\" and \"Someone Like You.\" Known for her deep, expressive vocals and poignant lyrics, her music often explores themes of love, heartbreak, and self-reflection. Winning multiple Grammy Awards, she has become one of the best-selling music artists of the 21st century. What is the name of this influential artist whose third album, \"25,\" continued her streak of chart-topping success?",
            "answers": ["Adele"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This annual event, established in 1897, is the world's oldest annual marathon and ranks as one of the world's most prestigious road racing events. It is held on Patriots' Day, the third Monday of April. The race starts in rural Hopkinton. Notably, it was the scene of a tragic event in 2013 when bombings near the finish line resulted in widespread injuries and loss of life. What is the name of this historic marathon known for its challenging course and storied history?",
            "answers": ["The Boston Marathon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1990, this hit song by an iconic pop artist became a global sensation, topping the charts in over 30 countries and becoming one of the best-selling singles of all time. The track is known for its influence on dance and fashion, highlighted in its stylish black-and-white music video, which drew inspiration from 1920s and 1930s Hollywood cinema. What is the name of this influential song by Madonna that brought a specific underground dance style into mainstream pop culture?",
            "answers": ["Vogue"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This former NFL running back is celebrated for his storied career with the Dallas Cowboys, where he became the league's all-time leading rusher. Over his 15 seasons, primarily with the Cowboys and later with the Arizona Cardinals, he amassed 18,355 rushing yards, setting a record that still stands. Known for his durability and powerful running style, he played a key role in helping his team secure three Super Bowl victories in the 1990s. Inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 2010, his legacy as one of the greatest running backs in history is well secured. What is the name of this legendary NFL player?",
            "answers": ["Emmitt Smith"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This tribunal was notorious for its use of torture and public executions, it primarily targeted converted Jews and Muslims suspected of secretly practicing their old religions. It was established in 1478 by Ferdinand II of Aragon and Isabella I of Castile, and it aimed to enforce Catholic orthodoxy in Spain. What is the name of this period of intense religious scrutiny and persecution?",
            "answers": [
                "Spanish Inquisition",
                "Inquisition",
                "Tribunal of the Holy Office of the Inquisition"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This 1803 event dramatically altered the size and shape of the United States, adding approximately 828,000 square miles of territory. It involved a deal with Napoleon Bonaparte of France, who needed funds for his military campaigns. The acquisition doubled the size of the young nation and included land that would become fifteen different states. At less than three cents an acre, it remains one of the largest land deals in history. What is the name of this significant expansion of U.S. territory?",
            "answers": ["Louisiana Purchase"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This American author, known for his legal thrillers, published his first novel, \"A Time to Kill,\" in 1989, drawing upon his experiences as a lawyer and legislator in Mississippi. He gained widespread fame with his second book, \"The Firm,\" which became a bestseller and was adapted into a successful film starring Tom Cruise. Many of his subsequent novels, including \"The Pelican Brief\" and \"The Client,\" have also been turned into popular movies. What is the name of this prolific writer whose works frequently explore legal and moral issues?",
            "answers": ["John Grisham"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its iconic Joshua trees and stark beauty, this desert features unique ecosystems and landmarks such as Death Valley, the hottest place on earth. It is the driest desert in North America and plays a significant role in renewable energy development, particularly solar power. Spanning across southeastern California, Nevada, and small parts of Utah and Arizona, what is the name of this arid region in the United States?",
            "answers": ["The Mojave Desert", "Mojave"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "First proposed by a German mathematician in 1859, this conjecture deals with the zeros of the Riemann zeta function, asserting that all non-trivial zeros have real parts of one-half. It has significant implications for the distribution of prime numbers and remains one of the most important unsolved problems in mathematics. This hypothesis is also one of the seven Millennium Prize Problems, offering a million-dollar reward for a proof. What is the name of this renowned mathematical hypothesis?",
            "answers": ["Riemann Hypothesis"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This entrepreneur, originally from China, has made significant strides in the cryptocurrency industry as the founder and CEO of one of the world's largest cryptocurrency exchanges by trading volume. Established in 2017, his company, Binance, quickly rose to prominence in the crypto community. What is the name of this influential figure in the cryptocurrency world who was sentenced to four months in prison for money laundering charges in April 2024?",
            "answers": ["Changpeng Zhao", "CZ"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This major WWII battle, fought during the winter of 1944-1945, was the largest and bloodiest battle involving American forces. It occurred when German troops launched a massive counteroffensive in the Ardennes region, aiming to split Allied lines. Despite initial success, the Allies ultimately contained the German advance, marking the last major Nazi offensive on the Western Front. What is the name of this pivotal battle?",
            "answers": ["Battle of the Bulge", "Ardennes Offensive"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This desert, often used by scientists as a Mars-like environment for testing space-bound equipment, features vast salt flats, sand, and lava flows. It is known for spectacular flower blooms that occasionally appear following rare rainfalls. Stretching across northern Chile and into parts of Peru, Bolivia, and Argentina, this region is renowned as one of the driest places on Earth. What is the name of this extremely arid region?",
            "answers": ["The Atacama Desert", "Atacama"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This professional ice hockey team, based in Ontario, Canada, is one of the \"Original Six\" members of the National Hockey League. Founded in 1917, they have a storied history and a passionate fan base, known for their long-standing rivalries with teams like the Montreal Canadiens and the Detroit Red Wings. Despite their success in the early years, they hold one of the longest Stanley Cup droughts, having not won since 1967. They play their home games at Scotiabank Arena. What is the name of this NHL team, famous for its blue and white uniforms?",
            "answers": ["Toronto Maple Leafs", "Maple Leafs"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered independently by Carl Wilhelm Scheele and Joseph Priestley in the 1770s, this element is essential for cellular respiration in most aerobic organisms and is the most abundant element by mass in the Earth's crust. Comprising approximately 21% of the Earth's atmosphere, it is vital for combustion processes and is commonly used in medical treatments for respiratory illnesses. What is the name of this colorless, odorless, tasteless gas that is critical for life on Earth?",
            "answers": ["Oxygen", "O2"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Originating in 12th-century France and lasting into the 16th century, this style of architecture is renowned for its verticality and light-filled interiors. Characterized by features such as pointed arches, ribbed vaults, and flying buttresses, it supported taller structures and larger windows than were previously possible. Notable examples include the Notre-Dame Cathedral in Paris and the Cologne Cathedral in Germany. This style also marked a significant shift from the solid, heavy forms of Romanesque architecture to a more ornate aesthetic. What is the name of this architectural style that flourished during the high and late medieval period?",
            "answers": ["Gothic"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This year featured a series of pivotal moments in American history, including the iconic Woodstock music festival, which symbolized the peak of the counterculture movement. It also witnessed the monumental first manned moon landing by Apollo 11, where Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin famously walked on the lunar surface. Additionally, Richard Nixon was inaugurated as the 37th president of the United States during this significant year. In which year did all these historic events occur?",
            "answers": ["1969"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "First celebrated in 1970, this annual event marks the anniversary of the birth of the modern environmental movement. It was founded by U.S. Senator Gaylord Nelson as a way to promote ecology and raise awareness of the growing problems of air, water, and soil pollution. This day encourages environmental action by individuals, communities, and governments around the world to combat issues like climate change and habitat destruction. Activities include planting trees, cleaning up trash, and campaigns for recycling and conservation. What is the name of this global observance dedicated to protecting the planet?",
            "answers": ["Earth Day"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 2008, this film features a memorable performance by Heath Ledger in a role that won him a posthumous Oscar for Best Supporting Actor. It is the second installment in Christopher Nolan's Batman trilogy and is celebrated for its complex characters and dark psychological depth. It f The movie's critical and commercial success helped redefine superhero films as a genre capable of serious storytelling. Set in the fictional Gotham City, it explores themes of chaos, morality, and heroism. What is the title of this influential superhero film?",
            "answers": ["The Dark Knight"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Spanish archipelago is renowned for its vibrant nightlife and beautiful beaches. It includes the Serra de Tramuntana mountain range in Mallorca, a UNESCO World Heritage site, and features historical megalithic stone monuments on Menorca. The group consists of four major islands: Mallorca, Menorca, Ibiza, and Formentera, located in the Mediterranean Sea. What is the collective name of these islands?",
            "answers": ["The Balearic Islands", "Balearic Islands"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This novel, first published in 1851, is a complex tale of a monomaniacal quest for revenge set against the backdrop of the 19th-century whaling industry. The narrative is driven by the obsessive Captain Ahab, commander of the whaling ship Pequod, who seeks vengeance on a giant white whale that once maimed him. The book explores themes of fate, nature, and the struggles between man and the sea. Written by Herman Melville, what is the title of this classic American novel that begins with the famous line, \"Call me Ishmael\"?",
            "answers": ["Moby Dick"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Known as \"El Libertador,\" this influential figure was instrumental in the early 19th-century movements that led to the independence of several South American countries from Spanish rule. His military and political leadership contributed to the liberation of present-day Venezuela, Bolivia, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru, and Panama. Born in Caracas, he is revered as a national hero in many Latin American countries, and his vision of a united South America remains influential. What is the name of this iconic South American liberator?",
            "answers": ["Simon Bolivar"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This site served as the busiest immigrant inspection station in the United States from 1892 to 1954. It processed approximately 12 million immigrants who entered the country. The island was expanded from its original size using land reclamation, largely due to the surplus earth from the construction of the New York City subway system. Today, it is part of the Statue of Liberty National Monument and houses a museum that explores immigrant experiences. What is the name of this island, once known as the \"Gateway to America\"?",
            "answers": ["Ellis Island"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Born Peter Gene Hernandez, this American artist made a splash with his debut album \"Doo-Wops & Hooligans\" in 2010, featuring hits like \"Just the Way You Are\" and \"Grenade.\" Known for his vibrant performances and retro flair, he has won multiple Grammy Awards and achieved international fame with songs such as \"Uptown Funk\" with Mark Ronson. Celebrated for blending pop, R&B, funk, and soul, what is the stage name of this dynamic performer?",
            "answers": ["Bruno Mars"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This university located in Manhattan, New York is led by Minouche Shafik. Established in 1754 as King's College on the grounds of Trinity Church, it is the oldest institution of higher education in New York and the fifth-oldest in the United States. Name this university that made headlines in April 2024 after pro-Gaza protests created an encampment on its campus and occupied a university building.",
            "answers": ["Columbia"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American former professional boxer emerged as the undisputed heavyweight champion of the world in the late 1980s. His quick ascension to the top included becoming the youngest boxer ever to win a heavyweight title at just 20 years old. Known for his powerful punches and controversial moments both inside and outside the ring, his career features significant bouts including a highly publicized match where he was disqualified for biting an opponent's ear. What is the name of this iconic boxer, often referred to by his nickname \"Iron Mike\"?",
            "answers": ["Mike Tyson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This Russian chemist created a systematic table in the late 19th century, organizing elements by atomic mass and chemical properties. His work predicted the properties of elements before they were discovered and has been fundamental to the development of chemical science. Known for this significant contribution to chemistry, what is the name of the scientist who developed the Periodic Table?",
            "answers": ["Dmitri Mendeleev", "Mendeleev"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Emerging as a prominent figure in college football, this quarterback started his career at the University of Oklahoma. He quickly made headlines during his freshman year before transferring to USC, where he continued to excel and won the Heisman Trophy in 2022. In 2024 he was selected as the first pick in the NFL Draft by the Chicago Bears. What is the name of this rising star in the sport?",
            "answers": ["Caleb Williams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This reality television series, which first aired in 2002, features a single man starting with a pool of romantic interests from whom he is expected to select a wife. Over multiple weeks, he dates the candidates, with eliminations based on rose ceremonies, leading to home visits and ultimately, marriage proposals. Known for its dramatic rose ceremonies and often controversial outcomes, this show has spawned numerous spin-offs and international versions. What is the name of this long-running series that has become a cultural phenomenon in the realm of dating shows?",
            "answers": ["The Bachelor"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This figure rose to power after leading a successful revolution in 1959 that overthrew the Batista regime. His policies transformed his nation into the first communist state in the Western Hemisphere. His tenure was marked by significant tensions with the United States, including the infamous Bay of Pigs Invasion and the Cuban Missile Crisis. Known for his long speeches and iconic military-style attire, he remained a controversial global figure until his death in 2016. Who is this revolutionary leader?",
            "answers": ["Fidel Castro"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American figure has made a significant impact both as a professional wrestler and as an actor. Known for his time in WWE, where his catchphrase \"You can't see me\" became iconic, he has won multiple championships and is recognized for his charismatic persona and philanthropy, especially his record number of wishes granted for the Make-A-Wish Foundation. Transitioning into acting, he has appeared in films like \"Trainwreck\" and \"Bumblebee,\" showcasing his versatility beyond the ring. What is the name of this influential entertainer who has successfully crossed over from sports entertainment to mainstream cinema?",
            "answers": ["John Cena"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Organized by Elizabeth Cady Stanton and Lucretia Mott, this 1848 gathering marked the beginning of the organized women's suffrage movement in America. It took place in a small New York town and produced a pivotal document known as the Declaration of Sentiments, which asserted the equality of men and women and demanded women's suffrage among other rights. What is the name of this historic convention?",
            "answers": ["Seneca Falls Convention", "Seneca Falls"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered by Alexander Fleming in 1928, this substance marked the beginning of the antibiotic era, revolutionizing the treatment of bacterial infections. Derived from the Penicillium mold, it was the first antibiotic to successfully combat diseases such as syphilis, gangrene, and tuberculosis. Its development significantly decreased the death rate in World War II by treating infected wounds. What is the name of this groundbreaking antibiotic?",
            "answers": ["Penicillin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its profound influence on classical music, this capital city has been home to legendary composers such as Mozart, Beethoven, and Schubert. Renowned for its architectural beauty, it features iconic structures like the Sch\u00f6nbrunn Palace and St. Stephen's Cathedral. Additionally, this city is famous for its historic coffee house culture, which has been recognized by UNESCO as an intangible cultural heritage. What is the name of this culturally rich European city?",
            "answers": ["Vienna Austria", "Vienna"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This epic poem details the protagonist's ten-year journey home to Ithaca after the fall of Troy, where he encounters numerous obstacles including the Cyclops, the Sirens, and the wrath of Poseidon. Meanwhile, his wife, Penelope, and son, Telemachus, deal with suitors attempting to take over his kingdom. This work attributed to the ancient Greek poet Homer, a sequel to \"The Iliad,\" is considered a seminal piece in Western literature. What is the name of this classic narrative?",
            "answers": ["The Odyssey"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This major Christian holiday marks the culmination of the Passion of Christ, preceded by Lent, a 40-day period of fasting, prayer, and penance. Its date varies each year, determined by the lunar calendar to fall on the first Sunday after the first full moon occurring on or after the vernal equinox. Celebrated with traditions such as egg hunts and a festive bunny, it commemorates a pivotal event: the resurrection of Jesus Christ. What is the name of this holiday?",
            "answers": ["Easter"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This pivotal document took effect on January 1, 1863. It declared that all enslaved people in Confederate-held territory were to be set free, fundamentally shifting the war\u2019s focus to include the abolition of slavery as a Union goal alongside reunification. Although it didn\u2019t immediately free all slaves, it was a crucial step towards the abolition of slavery and paved the way for the Thirteenth Amendment. What is the name of this historic proclamation?",
            "answers": ["Emancipation Proclamation"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Nestled between the imposing Table Mountain and the confluence of the Atlantic and Indian Oceans, this city is known for its stunning natural landscapes and vibrant cultural scene. It is one of South Africa's three capital cities, specifically serving as the legislative center. Notable landmarks include the historic Robben Island, where Nelson Mandela was imprisoned, and the colorful houses of the Bo-Kaap district. What is the name of this picturesque city at the southern tip of Africa?",
            "answers": ["Cape Town", "Cape Town South Africa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Beginning in 1789, this pivotal event marked a period of radical social and political upheaval in a large European nation. It led to the downfall of the monarchy, rise of the Republic, and a series of successive revolutionary governments. Key symbols include the storming of the Bastille and the adoption of the Declaration of the Rights of Man and of the Citizen. What is the name of this historic period in French history?",
            "answers": ["French Revolution"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This former professional cyclist became famous worldwide for winning the Tour de France seven consecutive times from 1999 to 2005, a feat unmatched in the history of the sport. However, his career later became overshadowed by one of the most significant doping scandals in sports, leading to his titles being stripped and his being banned from competitive cycling for life. Known for his cancer survival and founding of a cancer support foundation, what is the name of this controversial athlete?",
            "answers": ["Lance Armstrong"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Launched by NASA in the late 1970s, these twin spacecraft were designed to explore the outer planets and then continue on to study the outer limits of the Sun's influence. Their missions have provided humanity with close-up photos of Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune, vastly expanding our knowledge of these systems and the outer solar system. Remarkably, both probes have now entered interstellar space, sending back valuable data about the heliosphere and beyond. What is the collective name of these pioneering space probes?",
            "answers": ["Voyager"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Written when the author was just 16 years old and published in 1967, this novel is a pivotal piece of adolescent literature that captures the intense class struggles between two rival groups, the Greasers and the Socs, in 1960s Oklahoma. The story is told through the perspective of Ponyboy Curtis, a young Greaser who navigates the challenges of violence, class conflict, and growing up. What is the title of this influential novel by S.E. Hinton?",
            "answers": ["The Outsiders"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1986, this groundbreaking music video features a blend of claymation, pixilation, and stop-motion animation, creating a visually stunning and innovative experience. It was made for a song by Peter Gabriel and won a record nine MTV Video Music Awards, a record that still stands. The video is often celebrated for its creativity and technical achievements in animation, helping to set a new standard for the art form in the music industry. What is the name of this iconic music video, known for its pioneering visual effects and animation techniques?",
            "answers": ["Sledgehammer"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This Russian opposition leader and anti-corruption activist was known for his vocal criticism of the Kremlin and President Vladimir Putin. He organized large-scale demonstrations and utilized social media and YouTube to expose corruption and mobilize public dissent. In 2020, he was the victim of a high-profile poisoning attack, which he survived and attributed to Russian government agents. What is the name of this prominent figure in contemporary Russian politics who died in 2024 after being confined in a Russian prison since 2021?",
            "answers": ["Alexey Navalny"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its rich history that traces back to the Aztec Empire, this city features landmark sites like the Z\u00f3calo plaza and the ancient ruins of Tenochtitl\u00e1n. It boasts an impressive array of museums, including the Frida Kahlo Museum and the National Museum of Anthropology, and is celebrated for its culinary delights, particularly tacos and tamales. Serving as the capital of Mexico, what is the name of this vibrant metropolitan area?",
            "answers": ["Mexico City", "Mexico DF"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American political figure represented West Virginia in the U.S. Senate for over 51 years, making him the longest-serving Senator in history. Initially elected to the House of Representatives in 1952 and then to the Senate in 1958, he held his Senate seat until his death in 2010. Early in his career, he was a member of the Ku Klux Klan, a fact he later said he regretted and spent much of his career attempting to atone for. He also served as the Senate Majority Leader at various times during the 1970s and 1980s. What is the name of this influential senator?",
            "answers": ["Robert Byrd"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Initiated by the February Revolution which led to the abdication of Tsar Nicholas II, this transformative period in 1917 resulted in major political upheaval. The Bolsheviks, led by Lenin, seized power in the subsequent October Revolution, marking the rise of the Soviet Union and the end of the Romanov dynasty. This series of events significantly impacted global politics throughout the 20th century. What is the name of this pivotal period in Russian history?",
            "answers": ["Russian Revolution"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This private aerospace manufacturer and space transport services company, established in 2002, has been a pioneer in the development of reusable rockets. Among its achievements are being the first privately funded entity to send a liquid-fueled rocket to orbit, successfully launch, orbit, and recover a spacecraft, and dispatch astronauts to the International Space Station. Founded with the ultimate goal of enabling Mars colonization, it was started by entrepreneur Elon Musk. What is the name of this company known for revolutionizing space travel?",
            "answers": ["SpaceX"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Established in 1933, this professional American football team is part of the AFC North division in the NFL and is known for its deep-rooted history and passionate fan base. Holding the record for the most Super Bowl titles tied with another franchise, they are renowned for their tough, physical style of play. Famous for their black and gold colors, they play their home games at Acrisure Stadium, where fans are known for waving the iconic \"Terrible Towel.\" What is the name of this team, based in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania?",
            "answers": ["Pittsburgh Steelers", "Steelers"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This American novelist is renowned for her powerful narratives that explore the African American experience.  In 1993, she became the first African American woman to win the Nobel Prize in Literature, celebrated for her epic themes and vivid dialogue. She won the Pulitzer Prize for her novel \"Beloved\" in 1988, a story about a mother and her daughter dealing with the haunting legacy of slavery. Her works often focus on issues of identity, race, and humanity. What is the name of this influential literary figure?",
            "answers": ["Toni Morrison"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1939, this epic historical romance is set in the American South during the Civil War and Reconstruction era. It follows the turbulent life of Scarlett O'Hara, the spirited daughter of a plantation owner, and her romantic entanglements with Ashley Wilkes and Rhett Butler. Known for its sweeping narrative and complex characters, this film won multiple Academy Awards, including Best Picture. It remains one of the highest-grossing films of all time when adjusted for inflation. What is the title of this classic film, famous for its line, \"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn\"?",
            "answers": ["Gone with the Wind"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 2007, this reality television series provides an intimate look into the lives of a high-profile family, chronicling their personal and professional dramas. Known for its influence on pop culture and social media, the show features sisters Kim, Khlo\u00e9, and Kourtney, along with their half-sisters Kendall and Kylie. It has spawned numerous spin-offs and remained a staple in reality TV for over a decade. What is the name of this long-running series that tracks the day-to-day activities of the Kardashian-Jenner family?",
            "answers": ["Keeping Up with the Kardashians", "Kardashians"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This former NFL wide receiver largely played for the Minnesota Vikings and New England Patriots. Known for his impressive vertical leap and speed, he set the single-season touchdown reception record as a rookie in 1998 and later broke his own record in 2007 with 23 touchdown receptions. What is the name of this Hall of Fame wide receiver known for setting remarkable receiving records?",
            "answers": ["Randy Moss"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Founded in 2006, this American social media platform is known for its microblogging service where users post and interact with messages. It has played a significant role in social movements and public discourse worldwide. In 2022 Elon Musk purchased this company and has since renamed it to \"X\". What is the name of this influential social media company which previously featured a blue bird in its logo?",
            "answers": ["Twitter", "X", "Twitter"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This battle featured significant engagements at locations like Little Round Top and Pickett's Charge. This 1863 battle was the conflict with the largest number of casualties in the U.S. Known as the turning point of the Civil War, it concluded with President Abraham Lincoln's famous address, which redefined the purpose of the war. Located in a small town in Pennsylvania, this battle marked a decisive defeat for the Confederacy. What is the name of this historic battle?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Gettysburg", "Gettysburg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This 20th century Colombian author is known for his seminal works in the magical realism genre. He was awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1982 for his novels and short stories that combine the fantastic with the realistic in a richly composed world of imagination. His novel \"One Hundred Years of Solitude\" is acclaimed globally, weaving intricate family sagas with fantastical elements to reflect the political and social realities of Latin America. What is the name of this influential literary figure?",
            "answers": ["Gabriel Garc\u00eda M\u00e1rquez"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This scientific theory describes the large-scale motions of Earth's lithosphere, which is divided into several plates that glide over the mantle. Proposed in the early 20th century and gaining wide acceptance by the 1960s, this theory explains many aspects of geological phenomena, including earthquakes, volcanic activity, and continental drift. It also helps scientists understand the formation of mountain ranges and ocean trenches. What is the name of this fundamental theory that explains the dynamic nature of Earth's surface?",
            "answers": ["Plate Tectonics", "tectonics", "tectonic plates"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "The first of these conflicts between China and Britain ended in 1842 with the Treaty of Nanking, and resulted in Hong Kong's cession to Britain and the opening of several Chinese ports to foreign merchants. The second war, from 1856 to 1860 and involving France alongside Britain, further expanded port access and led to significant treaty concessions. Central to the conflicts was the controversial trade of a narcotic substance. What is the collective term for these conflicts, named after the substance at their heart?",
            "answers": ["Opium Wars"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Historically, this desert has been the habitat for nomadic Bedouin tribes, adapting to life in these challenging conditions. Covering much of the Arabian Peninsula, this desert is one of the largest continuous sand deserts in the world. It features a harsh, arid climate with sand dunes that can reach significant heights. The area is known for its extreme temperatures, which can plummet at night after soaring during the day. What is the name of this expansive desert region?",
            "answers": ["The Arabian Desert", "Arabian"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This medieval ruler, known as the \"Father of Europe,\" was king of the Franks and later crowned Emperor of the Romans, a title that revitalized the concept of a united Western Europe since the fall of the Roman Empire. His reign, beginning in the late 8th century, was marked by numerous military campaigns that expanded his kingdom to cover much of Western and Central Europe. He was a patron of the arts and education, initiating what would later be called the Carolingian Renaissance, a period of cultural and intellectual revival. What is the name of this emperor who significantly shaped European history and laid the foundations for modern European states?",
            "answers": ["Charlemagne"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Founded in 1899, this esteemed football club from Spain, is celebrated for its rich history, distinctive blue and garnet striped jerseys, and a philosophy deeply rooted in attractive, attacking football. Known for their motto \"M\u00e9s que un club\" (More than a club), they are a symbol of Catalan pride and culture. The club has achieved immense success both domestically and internationally, including 27 La Liga titles and 5 UEFA Champions League trophies. Their storied rivalry with Real Madrid in \"El Clasico\" is watched by millions around the world. What is the name of this iconic football club, famous for its youth academy, La Masia, which has produced many top-class players including Lionel Messi?",
            "answers": ["FC Barcelona", "Barcelona"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Known for his reassuring statement during America's Great Depression, \"The only thing we have to fear is fear itself,\" this influential American politician served as the 32nd President of the United States from 1933 until his death in 1945. He introduced the New Deal to combat the economic crisis and led the country through most of World War II, famously collaborating with Britain and the Soviet Union as part of the Allies. Holding office longer than any other U.S. president, he was also renowned for his fireside chats that bolstered national morale. What is the name of this president?",
            "answers": [
                "Franklin Delano Roosevelt",
                "FDR",
                "Franklin Roosevelt"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This platform was originally named A.me but now goes by the name Douyin in China. It was released outside of China in September 2017 and merged with the app Musical.ly in 2018. The app now has over a billion users. It is owned by the Chinese company ByteDance and has come under scrutiny for connections with China's Communist Party. This trend-setting app allows users to share short form video content. Name this app which is the subject of legislation saying it must be sold to a U.S. based company or face a national ban.",
            "answers": ["TikTok"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This surrealist painting is famed for its striking and bizarre images of soft, melting pocket watches. It depicts a dream-like scene in which time appears fluid and warped, reflecting the artist's interpretation of the relativity of space and time. The setting includes a desolate landscape that enhances the ethereal and surreal quality of the work. Created by Salvador Dal\u00ed in 1931, it is often seen as a symbol of the irrationality of the human mind, this painting is one of the most recognizable pieces of surrealist art. What is the name of this influential painting by Dal\u00ed, known for its unique interpretation of time?",
            "answers": ["Persistence of Memory"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known as the \"Land of 10,000 Lakes,\" this U.S. state is famous for its multitude of lakes and the scenic wilderness of its northern regions, including the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness. It is also home to the Mall of America, one of the largest shopping malls in the country, located in Bloomington. The state's vibrant cultural life is highlighted by the twin cities of Minneapolis and St. Paul, the latter serving as the state capital. What is the name of this northern state?",
            "answers": ["Minnesota"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered in 1868 during a solar eclipse, this element is the second lightest and second most abundant in the observable universe, primarily formed from the nuclear fusion of hydrogen in stars. It is colorless, odorless, and inert, making it useful in cryogenics, particularly in the cooling of superconducting magnets, with applications in MRI scanners and NMR spectrometers. Unlike other gases, it does not solidify at standard atmospheric pressure, remaining a liquid down to absolute zero under normal conditions. What is the name of this noble gas, known for causing balloons to float when filled with it?",
            "answers": ["Helium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1967, this groundbreaking album by the British band The Beatles is often hailed as one of the greatest albums of all time. Known for its innovative production, complex music arrangements, and an eclectic mixture of musical styles, it marked a significant departure from the band's earlier pop sound. The album's cover, featuring the Beatles in colorful military-style costumes amid a collage of famous faces, has become iconic. It includes hits such as \"Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds\" and \"A Day in the Life.\" What is the name of this influential Beatles album that is celebrated for its pioneering approach to studio recording?",
            "answers": [
                "Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band",
                "sergeant pepper",
                "sergeant pepper's lonely hearts club band",
                "st pepper"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Held annually on the first Monday of May, this prestigious event is a major fundraising gala for the Costume Institute at the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York City. Known for its exclusive guest list, extravagant outfits, and often provocative themes, it marks the opening of the Costume Institute's annual fashion exhibit. Each year, celebrities and designers collaborate to create elaborate fashion statements that align with the theme of the exhibit, making it one of the most notable nights in fashion. What is the name of this glamorous event, often dubbed as \"fashion's biggest night out\"?",
            "answers": ["Met Gala"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This influential U.S. president is known for his call to action, \"Ask not what your country can do for you\u2014ask what you can do for your country\"? He was instrumental in pivotal events such as the Cuban Missile Crisis, the advancement of the Civil Rights Movement, and the initiation of the Apollo space program. This man served as the 35th President of the United States from 1961 until his assassination in 1963. Name this President whose term was tragically cut short in Dallas, Texas. ",
            "answers": ["John F Kennedy", "JFK", "J.F.K."],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This spiral galaxy, named after the constellation in which it resides, is the nearest major galaxy to the Milky Way and the largest galaxy in our local group. Approximately 2.5 million light-years away from Earth, it is on a collision course with our galaxy, with an expected merger occurring in about 4.5 billion years. Known for its bright appearance and visible to the naked eye under dark skies, this galaxy offers a glimpse into the dynamics of galaxy formation and evolution. What is the name of this galaxy, often studied for its proximity and similarities to our own Milky Way?",
            "answers": ["Andromeda", "andromena"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "First published in 1866, this seminal Russian novel delves into the moral dilemmas of Rodion Raskolnikov, a former student living in St. Petersburg who commits a murder under the pretense of a philosophical theory. The narrative explores his psychological turmoil and the ensuing consequences of his actions, addressing deep questions about morality, guilt, and redemption. Set against the backdrop of a grim 19th-century Russia, this work is celebrated for its psychological depth and its profound exploration of existential despair. What is the title of this classic novel written by Fyodor Dostoevsky that challenges the notion of moral justifiability of crime?",
            "answers": ["Crime and Punishment"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Premiering in 2002, this critically acclaimed television series created by David Simon offers a gritty, realistic exploration of life in Baltimore, Maryland. The show extends over five seasons, each focusing on a different facet of the city from the drug trade and the port system to the city government and schools. The show featured characters called Omar and Stringer played by Michael Kenneth Williams and Idris Elba respectively. What is the name of this TV show renowned for its in-depth look at the interconnectedness of society\u2019s different layers?",
            "answers": ["The Wire"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Russian tsar, known for his extensive reforms aimed at modernizing Russia, ruled from the late 17th century into the early 18th century. His efforts to transform Russian society included the introduction of Western technologies and industries, the reorganization of the Russian military, and the establishment of a new capital, St. Petersburg, which was intended to serve as a \"window to the West.\" What is the name of this towering figure in Russian history, celebrated for his drive to establish Russia as a major European power?",
            "answers": ["Peter the Great"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This professional ice hockey team joined the NHL in 1967 as part of the league's expansion. Known for their black and gold colors, they have won 5 Stanley Cup championships, largely due to the contributions of legendary players like Mario Lemieux and Sidney Crosby. The team has a passionate fan base and plays its home games at PPG Paints Arena. Their successful periods in the early 1990s and late 2000s to early 2010s have cemented their status as a dominant force in the NHL. What is the name of this NHL franchise based in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, renowned for its resilience and championship pedigree?",
            "answers": ["Pittsburgh Penguins", "Penguins"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, one of the original Thirteen Colonies, is located in the northeastern region known as New England. It has a significant place in early American history, often referred to by its nickname \"The Constitution State,\" due to its Fundamental Orders of 1638-1639, considered by some as the first written constitution that created a government. Known for its blend of coastal cities and rural areas dotted with small towns, it has a strong maritime tradition and is a leader in industries such as finance and insurance. What is the name of this state, home to the prestigious Yale University and recognized for its high standard of living?",
            "answers": ["Connecticut"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Created by Norwegian artist Edvard Munch in 1893, this expressionist painting is known for its intense and emotional depiction of a figure against a blood-red sky. The central figure is portrayed in a moment of existential angst and despair, with an agonized expression that has become iconic. The background of a tumultuous sky over a blue-black fjord adds to the drama of the scene. This artwork is widely recognized as a symbol of human anxiety. What is the name of this powerful painting that captures a profound sense of dread and perception of the modern world?",
            "answers": ["The Scream"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "In 1804, these two explorers embarked on a historic expedition commissioned by President Thomas Jefferson following the Louisiana Purchase. Their journey aimed to map the newly acquired territories, establish trade with Native American tribes, and find a practical route across the western half of the continent to the Pacific Ocean. Assisted significantly by Sacagawea, a Lemhi Shoshone woman, they provided valuable geographical and scientific data that contributed to the expansion of the United States. What is the collective name of this duo known for their pioneering expedition to the western United States?",
            "answers": [
                "Lewis & Clark",
                "Lewis and Clark",
                "Lewis and Clark expedition",
                "Corps of Discovery Expedition"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "During this player's illustrious NHL career, which spanned from 1979 to 1999, he set records that still stand, including most points in a season and most career goals, assists, and points. He won four Stanley Cups with the Edmonton Oilers in the 1980s and earned the Hart Trophy as the league's most valuable player an unprecedented nine times. His number, 99, has been retired across the NHL in his honor. Known as \"The Great One,\" this Canadian athlete is widely considered the greatest hockey player of all time. What is the name of this legendary ice hockey player whose exceptional skill and sportsmanship elevated the entire sport?",
            "answers": ["Wayne Gretsky"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This organization was founded by Ahmed Yassin in 1987 after the outbreak of the First Intifada against the Israeli occupation. The group was designated as a terrorist organisation in 1995 by the United States. In 2006 the group won the Palestinian legislative election and has governed the Israeli-occupied Gaza Strip since 2007. The group made headlines in 2023 for carrying out terrorist attacks and kidnapping individuals in Israel on October 7. Name this organization whose attack started a hot war between this organization and the Israeli government.",
            "answers": ["Hamas"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, one of the original Thirteen Colonies, played a significant role in the American Revolution and was the first state to secede from the Union in the lead-up to the Civil War. Known for its subtropical beaches and marshlike sea islands, it is also home to historic cities like Charleston, famous for its well-preserved architecture and rich history as a major slave trading port. The state's economy historically relied on agriculture, but has diversified into manufacturing and tourism. What is the name of this state, also noted for being the site of the first shots fired in the Civil War at Fort Sumter?",
            "answers": ["South Carolina"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 1989, this animated sitcom created by Matt Groening is set in the fictional town of Springfield and follows the lives of a family. Known for its satirical take on American culture, society, television, and many aspects of the human condition, it has become one of the longest-running shows in television history. The series is celebrated for its colorful array of characters and clever humor. What is the name of this iconic TV show that features the characters Homer, Marge, Bart, Lisa, and Maggie?",
            "answers": ["The Simpsons"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Macedonian king, born in 356 BC, was one of history\u2019s most successful military commanders. By the age of 30, he had created one of the largest empires of the ancient world, stretching from Greece to northwestern India. He was never defeated in battle, leveraging his formidable tactical abilities and the military innovations of the Macedonian phalanx. His legacy includes the spread of Greek culture and language across the territories he conquered, significantly influencing subsequent cultural and historical developments. What is the name of this legendary conqueror known for founding over twenty cities that bore his name, the most famous being Alexandria in Egypt?",
            "answers": [
                "Alexander The Great",
                "Alexander",
                "Alexander III of Macedon"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This prominent star, known for its distinct reddish hue, is one of the largest and brightest in the night sky, forming the shoulder of the constellation Orion. Classified as a red supergiant, it is nearing the end of its life cycle, with astronomers predicting that it will eventually explode in a supernova. Located approximately 642 light-years from Earth, it is one of the best examples of a star in the late stages of stellar evolution, providing valuable insights into the life cycles of massive stars. What is the name of this star, famous for its size, brightness, and position in one of the most recognizable constellations?",
            "answers": ["Betelgeuse", "beatlejuice", "beetle juice"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1994 and based on Stephen King's novella, this film follows Andy Dufresne, a banker wrongfully imprisoned for murder in Shawshank State Penitentiary. Over decades, he forms a significant friendship with fellow inmate, Ellis \"Red\" Redding, as they endure the hardships of incarceration. Directed by Frank Darabont, the movie explores profound themes of hope and redemption and has become one of the most revered films in cinema history. What is the title of this film, celebrated for its enduring message that \"hope is a good thing, maybe the best of things, and no good thing ever dies\"?",
            "answers": ["The Shawshank Redemption"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered in 1789 by German chemist Martin Heinrich Klaproth, who named it after a planet, this element is notable for its radioactive properties and heavy atomic weight. It plays a crucial role in nuclear power generation and as the primary material for nuclear weapons. This element's most common isotope, numbered 238, has a half-life of about 4.5 billion years, making it useful in dating the age of the Earth. It is also dense enough to be used in military armor and high-density projectiles. What is the name of this radioactive element named after Uranus that has had significant implications for both energy production and weaponry?",
            "answers": ["Uranium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Commissioned in 1632 by the Mughal emperor Shah Jahan to house the tomb of his favorite wife this iconic mausoleum stands as a symbol of eternal love and is one of the most recognized buildings in the world. Located in Agra, India, it is renowned for its stunning white marble architecture and intricate craftsmanship involving inlaid semiprecious stones and carvings. This UNESCO World Heritage site attracts millions of visitors annually and is celebrated for its majestic presence and aesthetic beauty. What is the name of this famous structure, often described as \"a teardrop on the cheek of time\"?",
            "answers": ["Taj Mahal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Roman general and statesman played a crucial role in the events that led to the demise of the Roman Republic and the rise of the Roman Empire. Known for his pivotal part in the Gallic Wars, he subsequently became a dictator in perpetuity, a title he held until his assassination in 44 BC. His death on the Ides of March marked a turning point that led to the rise of his adopted heir, Augustus, and the establishment of the Roman Empire. What is the name of this historical figure, famous for his declaration \"Veni, Vidi, Vici\" after a swift victory at the Battle of Zela?",
            "answers": ["Julius Caesar"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team gained international fame in the 1990s due to its extraordinary success, including winning six NBA championships between 1991 and 1998. This era of dominance was largely driven by the presence of Michael Jordan, one of basketball's all-time greats, along with key figures like Scottie Pippen and coach Phil Jackson. Known for their iconic red, black, and white uniforms, the team's legacy includes setting an NBA record for most wins in a regular season, a record they held until 2016. What is the name of Chicago's NBA franchise, synonymous with 1990s basketball dominance?",
            "answers": ["Chicago Bulls", "Bulls"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This prominent American patriot was the President of the Continental Congress. A wealthy merchant and smuggler prior to the American Revolution, he used his resources to support the colonial cause and later served as the governor of Massachusetts. His prominent and stylish autograph became so iconic that his name is now synonymous with the word \"signature.\" What is the name of this influential figure whose signature is one of the most recognized in American history?",
            "answers": ["John Hancock"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "First held in 1929, this annual event honors outstanding achievements in the film industry, making it the most prominent and prestigious awards ceremony in Hollywood. Organized by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, it celebrates excellence in cinematic achievements as assessed by the Academy's voting membership. Known for its red carpet and the iconic golden statuette, the event brings together the biggest names in entertainment. What is the name of this ceremony that serves as the pinnacle of recognition for film achievements?",
            "answers": ["Oscars", "Academy Awards", "the oscars"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This southern nation has 11 official languages, reflecting its multicultural heritage. The nation's rich history includes significant archaeological sites like the Cradle of Humankind, where some of the oldest hominid fossils have been found. The country is also famed for its wildlife and conservation areas such as the Kruger National Park. It transitioned from a system of apartheid to a democracy in the 1990s under the leadership of Nelson Mandela, its first black president. What is the name of this country, characterized by its complex history and natural beauty?",
            "answers": ["South Africa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Premiering in 1951, this iconic American television sitcom stars Lucille Ball and her real-life husband, Desi Arnaz. The show follows the comedic antics of a housewife with dreams of stardom, and her bandleader husband, Ricky, as they navigate life in New York City. Known for its pioneering use of the three-camera setup and live audience format, it became famous for its timeless humor and is credited with setting the standard for sitcoms that followed. What is the name of this groundbreaking series, celebrated for episodes like \"Lucy Does a TV Commercial\"?",
            "answers": ["I Love Lucy"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Portuguese footballer is renowned for his exceptional skill and athleticism on the pitch, making him one of the most celebrated players in the sport's history. Known for his prolific goal-scoring abilities, he has won multiple FIFA Ballon d'Or awards and has played for top European clubs including Sporting Lisbon, Manchester United, Real Madrid, and Juventus. His remarkable career is also highlighted by numerous UEFA Champions League titles and a significant impact in international play, leading Portugal to victory in the 2016 UEFA European Championship. What is the name of this iconic forward, often considered one of the greatest footballers of all time?",
            "answers": ["Cristiano Ronaldo", "Ronaldo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Constructed during the Great Depression between 1931 and 1936, this massive concrete arch-gravity dam is located on the border between Arizona and Nevada in the Black Canyon of the Colorado River. Originally known as the Boulder Dam, it was later renamed to honor the man who was the President when the construction started. Today, it is also a major tourist attraction, known for its impressive engineering and historical significance. What is the name of this dam?",
            "answers": ["Hoover Dam"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Located in Central America, this country is known for its rich Mayan heritage, evident in the famous ruins of Tikal, and a diverse landscape that includes rainforests, volcanoes, and mountainous regions. It was once the heart of the Maya civilization, which flourished until the early 16th century. After centuries as a Spanish colony, it gained independence in 1821. Today, it is celebrated for its vibrant indigenous cultures, colorful textile crafts, and a cuisine that blends Spanish and Mayan influences. What is the name of this nation, bordered by Mexico to the north and west, Belize to the northeast, and Honduras and El Salvador to the southeast?",
            "answers": ["Guatemala"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Known as \"The Most Exciting Two Minutes in Sports,\" this prestigious horse race is held annually on the first Saturday in May. Established in 1875, it is the longest-running sporting event in the United States. The race is the first leg of the American Triple Crown, followed by the Preakness Stakes and the Belmont Stakes. It's celebrated with a festival that includes mint juleps, big hats, and the singing of \"My Old Kentucky Home.\" What is the name of this famous race that takes place at Churchill Downs and is a pinnacle of thoroughbred horse racing?",
            "answers": ["Kentucky Derby"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This English monarch, reigning in the early 16th century, is perhaps best known for his six marriages and the drastic measures he took to secure a male heir, which included breaking away from the Roman Catholic Church to establish the Church of England. His split from the Vatican led to the English Reformation, a series of events that significantly altered the religious landscape of England. His reign also saw the dissolution of the monasteries, which redistributed wealth and land from the church to the Crown and nobles. What is the name of this king whose personal and political decisions had a profound impact on English history?",
            "answers": ["Henry VIII", "Henry the eighth"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Woven with intricate detail and extensive lore, this seminal high-fantasy series by J.R.R. Tolkien features the quest to destroy a powerful artifact that epitomizes the potential for both good and evil. The narrative unfolds across a vast, fictional realm known as Middle-earth, where diverse races and languages enrich the complex history of its world. Lauded for its deep exploration of themes such as sacrifice, courage, and the persistent battle against malevolence, the trilogy includes the novels \"The Fellowship of the Ring,\" \"The Two Towers,\" and \"The Return of the King.\" What is the title of this epic literary work that has profoundly influenced the fantasy genre?",
            "answers": ["Lord of the Rings"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Developed by Albert Einstein in 1905, this theory revolutionized physics by introducing new concepts about time and space. It posits that the laws of physics are the same for all non-accelerating observers and that the speed of light within a vacuum is the same no matter the speed at which an observer travels. A key implication of this theory is that time can dilate, or slow down, and lengths can contract depending on the relative speed of objects in motion. What is the name of this groundbreaking theory that fundamentally altered our understanding of how the universe operates?",
            "answers": ["Special Relativity", "Relativity"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered in 1898 by Scottish chemist William Ramsay and English chemist Morris Travers in the residue left over from evaporating components of liquid air, this element is a colorless, dense, odorless noble gas used in a variety of applications. It is employed in flash lamps and arc lamps for photography, and its isotopes are used in the medical field for imaging and anesthesia. Additionally, it is used in ion propulsion systems for spacecraft. Known for its rarity and heavy atomic weight among the noble gases, what is the name of this element that also features prominently in high-performance light-emitting devices and medical imaging?",
            "answers": ["Xenon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This queen of Castile and Le\u00f3n, reigning in the late 15th century alongside her husband Ferdinand of Aragon, is best known for her role in the Reconquista, the completion of which was marked by the conquest of Granada in 1492. Her reign significantly advanced the unification of Spain and the Spanish Inquisition, which aimed to consolidate Catholic orthodoxy within her kingdoms. She also famously sponsored Christopher Columbus's 1492 voyage, which led to the European discovery of the New World. What is the name of this influential monarch?",
            "answers": [
                "Isabella of Spain",
                "Isabella the Catholic",
                "Queen Isabella",
                "Isabella"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1941, this landmark American film, directed by and starring Orson Welles, is frequently lauded as one of the greatest movies of all time. Known for its innovative use of deep focus cinematography, narrative structure, and special effects, the film tells the complex story of a wealthy newspaper magnate inspired by the life of William Randolph Hearst. Its narrative unfolds through a series of flashbacks following a reporter's quest to decipher the meaning behind the magnate's mysterious last word, \"Rosebud.\" What is the title of this influential film that revolutionized the techniques of filmmaking and narrative construction in cinema?",
            "answers": ["Citizen Kane"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Renowned as one of the greatest American architects of the 20th century, this visionary created designs that harmonized with humanity and its environment, a philosophy he called organic architecture. Notable for his innovative work, he designed over 1,000 structures during his career, which emphasized simplicity and natural beauty, fundamentally changing how we think about spaces. His most famous works include Fallingwater in Pennsylvania and the Guggenheim Museum in New York. What is the name of this architect known for his unique approach to building design, which seamlessly integrates the elements of human habitation with the natural surroundings?",
            "answers": ["Frank Lloyd Wright"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This professional football player was selected by the Kansas City Chiefs in the third round of the 2013 NFL Draft out of University of Cincinnati. He recently signed a contract making him the highest paid tight end in the NFL after winning Super Bowl LVIII. He is a cohost of the New Heights podcast with his brother Jason. Name this player who who made headlines for being in a relationship with the pop star Taylor Swift during the last NFL season.",
            "answers": ["Travis Kelce"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "First held in 1911, this iconic automobile race is known as \"The Greatest Spectacle in Racing.\" The race is traditionally run over the Memorial Day weekend and is famous for its 200 laps around a 2.5-mile oval track, totaling 500 miles. It is one of the three events that make up the Triple Crown of Motorsport, which also includes the Monaco Grand Prix and the 24 Hours of Le Mans. What is the name of this renowned race held annually at the Indianapolis Motor Speedway and celebrated for its high speeds and challenging conditions?",
            "answers": ["Indianapolis 500", "Indie 500", "indy 500"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, known for its vast wilderness and sparse population, was purchased from Russia in 1867 in a deal often referred to as \"Seward's Folly.\"  Rich in natural resources, it is a major hub for energy production, particularly oil and natural gas. The state's stunning landscapes, including Denali National Park and the Inside Passage, are major attractions, as well as its abundant wildlife. It is the largest state in the U.S. by area but one of the least densely populated. What is the name of this state, famous for phenomena like the Northern Lights and the Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race?",
            "answers": ["Alaska"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Launched in the 1930s in response to the Great Depression, this series of economic and social reforms included the creation of agencies like the Works Progress Administration (WPA) and the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), which provided employment through public works projects. It also introduced significant financial reforms and established the Social Security system to aid the elderly and unemployed. Initiated by President Franklin D. Roosevelt, this initiative aimed to restore prosperity and dignity to Americans during a time of economic crisis. What is the name of this pivotal economic recovery initiative?",
            "answers": ["New Deal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, admitted to the Union in 1896 as the 45th state, is known for its diverse landscapes ranging from arid deserts with sand dunes to thriving pine forests in mountain valleys. It is renowned for its natural beauty, including national parks like Zion, Arches, and Bryce Canyon, which offer spectacular red rock formations. The state is also a center for outdoor recreational activities, including skiing, which was prominently featured during the 2002 Winter Olympics held near its capital. What is the name of this state, also known for its significant Mormon community?",
            "answers": ["Utah"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Before entering politics, this individual gained fame as a comedian and actor, notably starring in a television show where he played the role of the President of Ukraine. Mirroring his on-screen persona, he ran for the actual presidency and was elected in 2019 with a campaign that promised to tackle corruption and bring peace to the eastern regions of Ukraine, where conflict with separatists had been ongoing. Since then, he has become a prominent figure internationally, especially noted for his leadership during Ukraine's war with Russia. What is the name of this Ukrainian president known for his role as the head of the warring nation?",
            "answers": ["Volodomyr Zelensky"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This figure was the first emperor of Rome, marking the transition from the Roman Republic to the Roman Empire following the tumultuous period of civil wars that ensued after Julius Caesar's assassination. Known originally as Octavian, he was Caesar's adopted son and heir. He reigned from 27 BC until his death in AD 14, establishing a period of relative peace known as the Pax Romana that lasted over two centuries. What is the name of this emperor, celebrated for founding the Roman Empire and inaugurating an era of relative peace and prosperity?",
            "answers": [
                "Augustus",
                "Octavius Caesar",
                "Octavius",
                "Gaius Octavius",
                "Octavian"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This radioactive metallic element was first produced and isolated in 1940 by a team led by Glenn T. Seaborg and Edwin McMillan at the University of California, Berkeley, by bombarding uranium with deuterons. It is used primarily in nuclear reactors and nuclear weapons, notably in the \"Fat Man\" type bombs dropped on Nagasaki in 1945. Highly reactive, it has several isotopes, the most significant being numbered 239, known for its ability to sustain a nuclear chain reaction. What is the name of this element, named after the dwarf planet Pluto, critical to the development of atomic energy and weaponry?",
            "answers": ["Plutonium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American Founding Father is known for his diplomatic efforts during the Revolutionary War when he helped negotiate the Treaty of Paris, which officially ended the war. Additionally, his correspondence with his wife, Abigail, provides an invaluable insight into the era's political and social dynamics. Name this man who was a key figure in drafting The Declaration of Independence, served as the first Vice President of the United States, and later served as the second President.",
            "answers": ["John Adams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic artwork was completed in 1908 during the high point of the artist's \"Golden Phase.\" It depicts a couple embraced in an ornate, golden swirl of robes, blending elements of Art Nouveau and the Byzantine influence that the Austrian Symbolist painter Gustav Klimt admired. The painting is celebrated for its luxurious use of gold leaf and its sensual portrayal of intimacy and love. Displayed in the \u00d6sterreichische Galerie Belvedere museum in Vienna, it remains one of Klimt's most famous and adored works. What is the title of this masterpiece known for its lavish and emotive representation of a couple's embrace?",
            "answers": ["The Kiss"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 1999, this groundbreaking television series is credited with initiating the era of prestige TV, featuring complex characters, intricate plots, and psychological depth rarely seen before in the medium. It centers on a New Jersey mob boss as he struggles to manage the dual responsibilities of his criminal organization and his family life, often discussing these challenges with his therapist. The show blends dark humor with dramatic elements and has been lauded for its deep exploration of issues such as mental health, family dynamics, and the American dream. What is the name of this critically acclaimed series that many consider to be one of the greatest TV shows of all time?",
            "answers": ["The Sopranos"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American gymnast, celebrated for revolutionizing her sport, has won a record-breaking 25 World Championship medals and 7 Olympic medals. Known for her extraordinary skill and athleticism, she dominated the gymnastics scene, securing individual all-around, vault, and floor exercise titles multiple times. She has also contributed several unique skills to the sport, with moves named after her in three apparatuses, showcasing her innovative techniques. Beyond her competitive achievements, she has become a vocal advocate for athletes' mental health. What is the name of this iconic gymnast, known for setting new records and standards in gymnastics?",
            "answers": ["Simone Biles"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American Football team is known for their dynastic run in the early 21st century, when they claimed multiple Super Bowl titles, largely under the leadership of head coach Bill Belichick and quarterback Tom Brady. Based in Foxborough, Massachusetts, this team has become one of the most successful franchises in NFL history with 6 Super Bowl titles. What is the name of this NFL team, noted for its distinctive navy blue, red, and silver uniforms and a strong legacy of championships?",
            "answers": ["New England Patriots", "Patriots"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This red dwarf star is part of the Alpha Centauri star system, located in the constellation of Centaurus. Discovered in 1915 by Scottish astronomer Robert Innes, it is situated approximately 4.24 light-years away from Earth making it the closest known star to the Sun. Despite its proximity, it is too faint to be seen with the naked eye. Notably, in 2016, astronomers discovered an Earth-sized exoplanet in its habitable zone, raising questions about potential life. What is the name of this star, the nearest known neighbor to our solar system?",
            "answers": ["Proxima Centauri", "Alpha Centauri C"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Founded in the early 19th century as a colony for freed American and Caribbean slaves, this West African nation declared its independence in 1847, making it the first democratic republic in African history to gain its independence without a revolution. Its capital, Monrovia, is named after James Monroe, a U.S. President who supported the colonization process. The country has faced significant challenges in recent decades, including two civil wars and the Ebola outbreak, but has been working towards reconciliation and development. What is the name of this country, unique for its historical ties to the United States?",
            "answers": ["Liberia"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1939 and based on L. Frank Baum's novel, this beloved musical film follows Dorothy Gale, a young girl from Kansas who is swept away by a tornado to the magical land of Oz. There, she embarks on a journey to see the Wizard in hopes of returning home, accompanied by her dog Toto and new friends\u2014the Scarecrow, the Tin Man, and the Cowardly Lion. Known for its iconic songs, Technicolor cinematography, and memorable characters, the film has become a cornerstone of American pop culture. What is the title of this classic movie that famously features the song \"Somewhere Over the Rainbow\"?",
            "answers": ["The Wizard of Oz"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Created by the Italian artist Sandro Botticelli in the mid-1480s, this renowned Renaissance painting depicts the goddess Venus emerging from the sea as a fully grown woman, according to classical mythology. The work is celebrated for its grace and beauty, illustrating the idealized human form in harmony with nature. It features Venus standing on a giant shell, being blown towards shore by the winds, personified by Zephyr. Displayed in the Uffizi Gallery in Florence, this artwork remains a quintessential example of Renaissance art's fascination with classical mythology. What is the name of this famous painting that captures the mythological birth of the goddess of love and beauty?",
            "answers": ["The Birth of Venus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American statesman and writer became the 26th President of the United States, known for his exuberant personality and range of interests. Coming to office after the assassination of President William McKinley in 1901, he promoted progressive policies that emphasized anti-trust actions and conservation efforts, founding numerous national parks and forests. He was also a key figure in negotiating the end of the Russo-Japanese War, for which he was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. Notably, he is one of the four presidents featured on Mount Rushmore. What is the name of this dynamic leader who championed the \"Square Deal\"?",
            "answers": ["Theodore Roosvelt", "Teddy Roosevelt"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This king, reigning in the early 5th century, is noted for founding the Merovingian dynasty, which would rule the Frankish kingdom for nearly 300 years. His conversion to Christianity\u2014specifically to the Roman Catholic creed\u2014was a pivotal event, influencing many of his Frankish warriors to follow suit, thus strengthening alliances with Roman Christian churches. This decision had profound implications for the religious landscape of medieval Europe, helping to solidify Catholicism in the region. What is the name of this king, credited with uniting various Frankish tribes under one rule and shaping the future religious and political structure of Western Europe?",
            "answers": ["Clovis", "clovis I"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This militant group, originating in the early 1990s in Afghanistan, emerged from the chaos following the Soviet-Afghan War, drawing members largely from Afghan refugees educated in religious schools in Pakistan. They took control of Afghanistan in 1996 and imposed strict interpretations of Islamic law, leading to widespread human rights criticisms, especially regarding the treatment of women. After being ousted from power in 2001 by U.S.-led forces, they waged an insurgency and regained control in 2021 following the withdrawal of foreign troops. What is the name of this group, known for its fundamentalist policies and governance of Afghanistan?",
            "answers": ["Taliban", "The Taliban"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This monarch, known as the \"Sun King,\" reigned over France for 72 years, making his tenure one of the longest in European history. Ascending to the throne in the mid-17th century, he is best known for his autocratic regime that firmly established the absolute power of the monarchy. His reign saw the construction of the Palace of Versailles, a symbol of royal extravagance and absolutism. He also fostered a flourishing of arts and culture that made France the center of intellectual and artistic life in Europe. What is the name of this French king, under whose rule France became the leading European power?",
            "answers": ["Louis XIV", "Louis the fourteenth", "King Louis"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "First held in 1903, this annual championship series is often referred to as the \"Fall Classic\". It is one of the most watched sporting events in the U.S., known for creating legends and memorable moments in baseball history. The series has seen numerous iconic teams, including the New York Yankees, who hold the record for the most titles. It is the culmination of the Major League Baseball season in the United States, featuring a best-of-seven playoff between the champions of the National League and the American League. What is the name of this prestigious event in baseball?",
            "answers": ["World Series", "The World Series"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Released in 1974, this film is both a sequel and a prequel to its predecessor, expanding on the saga of the Corleone family by depicting the early life and career of Vito Corleone in 1920s New York and his son Michael's expansion and tightening grip on the family crime syndicate during the 1950s. Directed by Francis Ford Coppola, it is noted for its rich storytelling and complex portrayal of the transformation of its characters, particularly Michael Corleone's descent into corruption and moral decay. The movie received critical acclaim and multiple Academy Awards, including Best Picture. What is the title of this acclaimed sequel that explores themes of power, family, and betrayal in the American Mafia?",
            "answers": [
                "The Godfather Part II",
                "The Godfather 2",
                "Godfather II"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, located in the Western region, is best known for its expansive deserts and as the leading silver producer in the country, which earned it the nickname \"The Silver State.\" The state also features significant natural beauty, such as the Sierra Nevada mountains and Great Basin National Park. It is also famed for its liberal laws on gambling and entertainment, with Las Vegas, known as the entertainment capital of the world, drawing millions of tourists annually. What is the name of this state, which became the 36th state to join the Union in 1864 and is known for its vibrant nightlife and historic mining towns?",
            "answers": ["Nevada"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This President is known for his ambitious domestic policies including the \"Great Society\" program, which aimed to eliminate poverty and racial injustice. His administration significantly expanded civil rights, public broadcasting, Medicare, Medicaid, aid to education, and the arts. However, his presidency was also marked by the escalation of the Vietnam War, which overshadowed his substantial legislative achievements. What is the name of this U.S. president who became the 36th President of the United States following the assassination of President John F. Kennedy in 1963?",
            "answers": ["Lyndon B Johnson", "LBJ", "L.B.J"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This is the brightest star in the constellation Ursa Minor and has been used for navigation and orientation for centuries, including by sailors and explorers to determine latitude. This star, also known as the North Star, holds a crucial position almost directly above the North Pole, making it an excellent fixed point for navigation in the Northern Hemisphere.  It is actually a triple star system, consisting of the main supergiant star and two smaller companions. What is the name of this star that is famous for its steadfast position in the sky, guiding travelers throughout history?",
            "answers": ["Polaris"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This executive became CEO of The Walt Disney Company in 2005, overseeing a significant expansion of its global entertainment operations. Under his leadership, the company acquired Pixar, Marvel, Lucasfilm, and 21st Century Fox, significantly broadening its film and television content. He also spearheaded the launch of Disney+, a direct-to-consumer streaming service that competes with other major platforms. Known for his strategic vision and leadership, he played a key role in making Disney a dominant force in the entertainment industry. What is the name of this influential business leader who helped shape the modern landscape of media and entertainment?",
            "answers": ["Bob Iger", "Iger"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This iconic bronze sculpture depicts a life-sized figure deep in thought. Originally part of a larger work called \"The Gates of Hell,\" it represents Dante pondering his great poem, \"The Divine Comedy.\" Over time, the figure has come to symbolize philosophical thinking and introspection more broadly. Versions of this famous work originally created by the French artist Auguste Rodin in 1904, can be found in numerous museums around the world, making it one of the most recognized sculptures in modern art. What is the name of this renowned sculpture, celebrated for its portrayal of contemplation and intellectual engagement?",
            "answers": ["The Thinker"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American technology entrepreneur co-founded a major social media platform while attending Harvard University in 2004. The platform quickly exploded in popularity, redefining global communication and eventually attracting billions of users worldwide, influencing various aspects of society, from business to politics. Known for his role in the development and expansion of social networking, he has also faced significant scrutiny and controversy over privacy issues and the platform's role in disseminating information. What is the name of this influential figure, the CEO of Facebook, who became one of the world's youngest billionaires?",
            "answers": ["Mark Zuckerberg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA franchise, established in 1946, is one of the league's most storied teams. The team has a fierce rivalry with the Los Angeles Lakers, contributing to several epic matchups in NBA Finals history. The team's legacy includes a record-setting number of NBA Championships and a host of Hall of Fame players such as Bill Russell, Larry Bird, and Paul Pierce. Known for their distinctive green and white uniforms, they are a symbol of basketball excellence and tradition. What is the name of Boston's NBA team, famous for its historical success and contributions to basketball lore?",
            "answers": ["Boston Celtics", "Celtics"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This U.S. state, known as the \"Land of Enchantment,\" joined the Union in 1912 as the 47th state. It is renowned for its diverse landscape, which includes desert, mesa, and mountain territories, and a rich blend of Native American and Hispanic cultures, reflected in its art, architecture, and cuisine. The state has a strong scientific community, evidenced by institutions like Los Alamos National Laboratory, where the atomic bomb was developed. It is also famous for hosting the largest hot air balloon festival in the world. What is the name of this state, distinguished by its significant contributions to both nuclear research and cultural heritage?",
            "answers": ["New Mexico"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This film was released in 1994 and directed by Quentin Tarantino. The narrative intertwines the lives of two mob hitmen, a boxer, a gangster's wife, and a pair of diner bandits, exploring themes of redemption and violence in a stylized manner. The movie's structure is a pastiche of various genres, making it a defining example of postmodern cinema. It was a major critical and commercial success, revitalizing the careers of several of its stars, including John Travolta. What is the title of this influential film that features the iconic dance scene between Travolta and Uma Thurman?",
            "answers": ["Pulp Fiction"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This critical biological process involves the conversion of atmospheric nitrogen gas into a form that is usable by living organisms, primarily ammonia. It is carried out by certain types of bacteria, some of which live in a symbiotic relationship with the root nodules of leguminous plants. This natural conversion is essential for building amino acids and proteins, thereby playing a key role in the nitrogen cycle that supports the growth of many forms of life on Earth. What is the term for this process that allows nitrogen, an element vital for life, to be absorbed by plants and enter the food chain?",
            "answers": ["Nitrogen fixation"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This famous painting was created by Dutch artist Johannes Vermeer around 1665. Known for its subtle use of light and shadow, this work is often referred to as the \"Mona Lisa of the North\" due to its enigmatic expression and the mysterious allure of its subject. The artwork belongs to the collection of the Mauritshuis museum in The Hague and continues to intrigue art lovers with its simple yet profound beauty. What is the name of this celebrated painting that portrays a young girl looking over her shoulder, adorned with a striking pearl earring?",
            "answers": ["Girl with a Pearl Earring"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This 18th-century Prussian king is celebrated for his military prowess and enlightened domestic policies. Ascending to the throne in 1740, he expanded Prussian territories through his adept handling of the military during the Silesian Wars and the larger conflict of the Seven Years' War, establishing Prussia as a significant European power. Known for his patronage of the arts and philosophy, he also promoted reforms that made his kingdom a cultural beacon in the Age of Enlightenment. What is the name of this ruler, often referred to as an archetype of the enlightened despot?",
            "answers": ["Frederick the Great", " Frederick II", "Frederick"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American polymath and  Founding Father was instrumental in drafting the Declaration of Independence and the U.S. Constitution. A noted inventor, he created the lightning rod and bifocal glasses. His experiments with electricity were groundbreaking, contributing significantly to the scientific understanding of the time. Also a diplomat, he played a crucial role in securing French support during the American Revolution. What is the name of this influential figure, who also established Philadelphia\u2019s first fire department and library?",
            "answers": ["Benjamin Franklin", "Ben Franklin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered and isolated by Scottish physician Daniel Rutherford in 1772, this diatomic gas constitutes about 78% of the Earth's atmosphere and is essential for all living organisms, being a primary component of amino acids in proteins. It is also utilized in various industrial processes, such as ammonia production and as a coolant for sensitive equipment. What is the name of this colorless, odorless element that is the most abundant in our atmosphere?",
            "answers": ["Nitrogen"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This surprise double album broke Spotify's single-day streaming record upon release. It explores its author's psyche and personal experiences, and features collaborations with Jack Antonoff and Aaron Dessner. It is the eleventh studio album by an acclaimed singer-songwriter who recently embarked on her Eras Tour. This album was released on April 19, 2024 and contains 31 songs across two volumes. What is the title of this record-breaking release by Taylor Swift?",
            "answers": [
                "The Tortured Poets Department",
                "dead poets department"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Forming the northern boundary of the Pacific Ring of Fire, this chain of islands is noted for its active volcanoes and rugged terrain. The archipelago has historical significance due to battles fought on its soil during World War II\u2014the only such battles on U.S. soil against Japan. Additionally, these islands play a crucial role in the migratory paths of various marine animals and host a unique blend of wildlife. Stretching from the Alaskan Peninsula to Russia, what is the name of this island chain?",
            "answers": ["The Aleutian Islands", "Aleutian Islands"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This island was the site of a prominent Native American protest from 1969 to 1971, highlighting Indigenous rights. Before that in 1934, it was converted into a federal prison designed to detain the most troublesome inmates, including notable figures like Al Capone and the \"Birdman\" Robert Stroud.  Managed by the National Park Service, this island attracts over a million visitors each year and is known for its historic lighthouse and military prison facilities. What is this island, often referred to as \"The Rock,\" located in San Francisco Bay?",
            "answers": ["Alcatraz"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This battle is famously depicted in the Bayeux Tapestry, which chronicles the events leading up to and including this historical clash. In 1066, this decisive battle changed the course of English history when William the Conqueror, the Duke of Normandy, defeated King Harold II. This victory led to the Norman conquest of England, significantly influencing the English language, culture, and legal system. What is the name of this pivotal battle that established Norman rule in England?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Hastings"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Serbian tennis player has made a significant impact on the sport, consistently ranking among the world's top players since turning professional in 2003. Known for his exceptional athleticism and mental toughness, he has won numerous Grand Slam titles, holding records for the most Australian Open wins. His rivalry with contemporaries like Roger Federer and Rafael Nadal has been a defining feature of his career, contributing to what many consider the golden era of tennis. What is the name of this elite tennis player known for dominating the modern era of tennis?",
            "answers": ["Novak Djokovic"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 2019 blockbuster is the culmination of over a decade of Marvel Cinematic Universe films, bringing together a vast array of characters to face the formidable villain Thanos in a final showdown. It follows the dramatic events of \"Avengers: Infinity War,\" where many heroes vanished due to Thanos' actions. Known for its epic battles and time-traveling narrative, it became the highest-grossing film of all time until 2021. What is the title of this Marvel Studios movie that serves as a grand finale to its first saga of films?",
            "answers": ["Avengers: Endgame", "endgame"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Composed in Iceland during the 13th century by the historian, poet, and politician Snorri Sturluson, this collection of Old Norse poems and tales is a primary source for modern knowledge of Norse mythology. It serves not only as a manual for aspiring poets, describing the poetic meter of the time, but also details the mythology and stories that were foundational to Norse culture, including the creation of the world and the tales of gods like Odin and Thor. What is the name of this crucial text that preserves much of what we know about Norse mythology and medieval Scandinavian literature?",
            "answers": ["The Prose Edda", "prose edda"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Coined by Mark Twain, this term describes a period in U.S. history from the 1870s to about 1900, marked by rapid industrialization and economic growth, alongside stark income inequality and political corruption. Notable figures like John D. Rockefeller and Andrew Carnegie amassed fortunes, while the railroads, steel, and oil industries boomed. Despite its prosperous facade, the era was rife with underlying social issues. What is the name of this period in American history?",
            "answers": ["Gilded Age"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This rebellion was initiated by a secret society known for practicing martial arts, and the movement aimed to oust imperialist foreigners and restore Chinese sovereignty. The rebellion resulted in the Eight-Nation Alliance invading Beijing to suppress the uprising and relieve besieged foreign embassies. The aftermath included harsh reparations imposed on China, exacerbating the decline of the Qing Dynasty. What is the name this violent anti-foreign and anti-Christian uprising which occurred in China between 1899 and 1901?",
            "answers": [
                "Boxer Rebellion",
                "Boxer Uprising",
                "Boxer Insurrection",
                "Yihetuan Movement"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Discovered first in 1940 by chemists Glenn T. Seaborg, Edwin McMillan, Joseph W. Kennedy, and Arthur Wahl, these synthetic elements are produced artificially in nuclear reactors or particle accelerators. With atomic numbers greater than 92, which is that of uranium, they are not found naturally. This group includes well-known elements such as neptunium and plutonium. What is the collective term for these artificially created elements?",
            "answers": ["Transuranium Elements", "Transuranium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Known for his remarkable longevity and performance in the NFL, this quarterback has won seven Super Bowl titles, more than any other player in league history. He spent the first 20 seasons of his career with the New England Patriots, where he became synonymous with the team's dynasty, before moving to the Tampa Bay Buccaneers and securing another championship. Renowned for his precision passing and clutch performances in critical moments, he has secured multiple MVP awards and numerous Super Bowl MVP titles. What is the name of this iconic football player?",
            "answers": ["Tom Brady"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Founded in 2003, this American company is named after a Serbian-American inventor and is known for its innovative electric vehicles and renewable energy products. Under the leadership of its prominent CEO, it became the first electric car manufacturer to produce a fully electric luxury sedan, the Model S, which has received numerous awards for safety and performance. This company introduced the \"Cybertruck\" and hopes to one day have autonomous taxis. Name this company led by Elon Musk.",
            "answers": ["Tesla"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Known for its modern skyline dominated by the iconic Petronas Twin Towers, once the tallest buildings in the world, this city is a cultural melting pot with a diverse culinary scene and vibrant neighborhoods like Chinatown and Little India. It's also a major global tourism and retail hub, featuring numerous shopping districts and hosting an iconic Fashion Week. Serving as the capital of Malaysia, what is the name of this bustling metropolis in Southeast Asia?",
            "answers": ["Kuala Lumpur", "KL"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic television series, which first aired in 1989, became famous for its scenes of lifeguards patrolling the sunny beaches of California. Known for its red swimsuits and slow-motion running shots, the show focused on the personal and professional lives of a team of lifeguards led by the character Mitch Buchannon. It gained international fame, becoming one of the most watched TV shows globally during the 1990s. What is the name of this series that became synonymous with beach lifeguard drama?",
            "answers": ["Baywatch"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Emerging in the late 16th century in Italy and spreading across Europe, this architectural style is characterized by its dramatic use of light and shadow, expansive ornate structures, and a focus on motion and emotion. Notable for its intricate details and grandeur, it often features large-scale ceiling frescoes, twisted columns, and extensive use of gold. Key examples include the Palace of Versailles in France and St. Peter's Basilica in Rome. What is the name of this exuberant style that dominated European architecture and art through the 17th and early 18th centuries?",
            "answers": ["Baroque"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic American singer, songwriter, and dancer first gained fame as a member of the Jackson 5 and then soared to unprecedented heights with his solo career. His 1982 album featured hits like \"Billie Jean\" and \"Beat It.\" He won numerous Grammy Awards throughout his career, including a record-breaking eight Grammys in one night for \"Thriller.\" What is the name of this legendary entertainer often referred to as the \"King of Pop\"?",
            "answers": ["Michael Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This British writer and scholar, born in 1898, was a noted Christian apologist and a member of the Inklings, a literary discussion group at Oxford, alongside J.R.R. Tolkien. He used his academic background in literature to explore and defend his faith through works like \"Mere Christianity.\" He is best known for creating \"The Chronicles of Narnia,\" a series of seven beloved fantasy novels. What is the name of this influential author and theologian?",
            "answers": ["C.S. Lewis", " CS Lewis"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This Jewish holiday commemorates the Biblical story of Exodus, where Hebrew slaves were freed from bondage in Egypt. According to the narrative, the Israelites were instructed to mark the doorposts of their homes with the blood of a slaughtered spring lamb so that the spirit of the Lord knew to pass over these homes, hence the name of the holiday. Traditionally observed for eight days by many Jewish communities, it involves rituals such as the Seder meal, which includes reading from the Haggadah, eating matzah, and other symbolic foods. What is the name of this holiday that begins on the 15th of the Hebrew month of Nissan?",
            "answers": ["Passover"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Spanning several countries in southern Africa, this vast semi-arid sandy savanna is known for its red sand, sparse vegetation, and diverse wildlife, including meerkats and the famous black-maned lions. Despite its dry conditions, it supports more animal and plant life than a true desert. The region is also home to the indigenous San people, who have adapted traditional techniques to survive its harsh environment. What is the name of this desert that stretches across Botswana, parts of Namibia, and South Africa?",
            "answers": ["The Kalahari Desert", "Kalahari"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Belgian former professional cyclist, often hailed as the most accomplished rider in the history of the sport, won the Tour de France five times during his career in the late 1960s and early 1970s. His dominance extended beyond France into the Giro d'Italia, which he also won five times, and he achieved a record 34 stage wins in the Tour de France. Known for his nickname \"The Cannibal\" due to his relentless competitive drive, what is the name of this legendary cyclist?",
            "answers": ["Eddy Merckx"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Initiated by the Latin Church in the medieval period, these campaigns aimed to reclaim Jerusalem and other holy lands from Muslim control, beginning in the late 11th century and lasting until the late 13th century. Over time, the objectives expanded to encompass various political, economic, and territorial motives. Significantly shaping Christian and Muslim relations, these events had a profound impact on the geography and politics of the Middle East. What is the general term for these historical campaigns?",
            "answers": ["The Crusades", "Crusades"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Triggered by various events such as undersea earthquakes, volcanic eruptions, underwater landslides, or meteorite impacts, these high-energy sea waves can cause catastrophic damage when they reach coastal areas. Notably, the 2004 Indian Ocean event highlighted the critical need for early warning systems to prevent disasters. What is the term used to describe these powerful series of ocean waves?",
            "answers": ["Tsunami"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This project was initiated in response to fears that Nazi Germany would develop nuclear weapons first. It began in 1942 and involved some of the greatest scientific minds of the time, including Robert Oppenheimer and Enrico Fermi. It led to the development and testing of the first nuclear weapons in Los Alamos, New Mexico. The culmination of this project was the dropping of atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki in 1945, significantly impacting the conclusion of World War II. What is the name of this pivotal scientific and military project?",
            "answers": ["Manhattan project"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This poet and Nobel laureate, who adopted a pen name to avoid conflict with his father, became a senator for the Chilean Communist Party. Renowned for his passionate love poems and odes to ordinary objects, his most famous collection, \"Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair,\" was published in his youth. He later served as a diplomat in various countries, writing the poem \"I Explain a Few Things\" during the Spanish Civil War.",
            "answers": ["Pablo Neruda"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "At the age of 14, this Romanian gymnast made history at the 1976 Montreal Olympics by becoming the first gymnast to score a perfect 10.0 in an Olympic event, a feat she achieved not once, but seven times throughout the competition. Her flawless routines on the uneven bars and balance beam earned her three gold medals, including the prestigious all-around title. Name this gymnast who added two more gold medals in the 1980 Olympics.",
            "answers": ["Nadia Comaneci"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This U.S. Senator and his wife, Nadine, are currently facing trial for bribery charges over alleged gifts from Egyptian and Qatari nationals in exchange for favorable treatment. In 2015 this same Senator was charged in a separate corruption case which eventually ended when the charges were dropped in 2018. This Democrat is the senior Senator from New Jersey, serving since 2006. Name this politician who chaired the Committee on Foreign relations from 2013-2015 and 2021-2023.",
            "answers": ["Bob Menendez", " Robert Menendez"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This transcontinental city straddles the Bosphorus Strait, a natural waterway that serves as a boundary between two continents. Its strategic location has made it a coveted prize throughout history, leading to its role as the capital of both the Byzantine and Ottoman Empires. Historically known as Byzantium and Constantinople, a blend of Eastern and Western influences is evident in its architecture, cuisine, and culture. Which city, the largest in Turkey, is the only metropolis in the world situated on two continents?",
            "answers": ["Istanbul"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American president had a centrist political philosophy which became known as the \"Third Way\". He was the first president born in the Baby Boomer generation and participated in the Camp David Summit to advance the Israeli\u2013Palestinian peace process. He was twice elected governor of Arkansas and defeated George H.W. Bush and Bob Dole as he was elected President twice. Name this 42nd President who married Hillary Rodham.",
            "answers": ["Bill Clinton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This science fiction franchise, despite initial cancellation after three seasons, gained a cult following through syndicated reruns and spawned a media empire. It premiered in 1966 with a multiracial crew led by Captain James T. Kirk aboard the USS Enterprise. Its creator, Gene Roddenberry, envisioned a future where humanity united to explore the galaxy. The show's original mission was \"to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.\"",
            "answers": ["Star Trek"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This British politician and writer served as First Lord of the Admiralty during World War I but was demoted after the disastrous Gallipoli Campaign. He is most known for his wartime leadership during World War II, where he delivered powerful speeches, including \"We shall fight on the beaches.\" He earned a Nobel Prize in Literature in 1953 for books he wrote about his WWII experiences. Name this British statesman who served two terms as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom and who coined the phrase \"Iron Curtain\" in a famous speech.",
            "answers": ["Winston Churchill"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This international scientific research project was declared essentially complete in 2003, with 92% of human DNA sequenced. A working draft was announced in 2000, a significant milestone in the project's timeline. Led by an international consortium of scientists, it involved mapping and deciphering the 3 billion base pairs that make up human DNA. This ambitious endeavor sought to map and understand all the genes of human beings. What was the name of this project, which has since revolutionized fields from medicine to forensics?",
            "answers": ["Human Genome Project", "Genome", "Human Genome"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Prussian statesman, born into the Junker nobility, orchestrated the unification of Germany in 1871 through a series of strategic wars, including victories over Austria and France. This man served as the first Chancellor of the German Empire from 1871 to 1890, and became known as the \"Iron Chancellor\". Who is this leader known for his strong leadership and Realpolitik approach to politics?",
            "answers": ["Otto Von Bismark"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Constructed on an artificial island at the entrance of Charleston Harbor in South Carolina, this masonry fort was named for a Revolutionary War hero. It was designed to protect the harbor from naval attacks and became a focal point of tension between the Union and the Confederacy in the lead-up to the Civil War. Following South Carolina's secession from the Union in December 1860, the fort's commander, Major Robert Anderson, refused to surrender it to Confederate authorities, leading to a bombardment that marked the official beginning of the Civil War in April 1861.",
            "answers": ["Fort Sumter"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British actress and fashion icon, known for her roles in classic films during Hollywood's Golden Age, epitomized elegance and charm with her performances in \"Breakfast at Tiffany's,\" \"Roman Holiday,\" for which she won an Academy Award, and \"My Fair Lady.\" Beyond her film career, she was also celebrated for her humanitarian work with UNICEF. Her style and grace left a lasting impression on the fashion and film industries. What is the name of this beloved actress and philanthropist, renowned for both her distinctive cinematic roles and her dedication to charity?",
            "answers": ["Audrey Hepburn"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This single-stranded molecule, essential for protein synthesis, comes in three main types: messenger, transfer, and ribosomal. It carries genetic code from DNA, delivers amino acids to the ribosome, and forms a key component of ribosomes. Which molecule, found in all living cells and some viruses, serves as a vital link between genetic information and protein production, making it indispensable for life?",
            "answers": ["RNA", "Ribonucleic Acid"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This athlete was the first player in NCAA history to lead the nation in both points and assists in a single season. She was named the consensus National Player of the Year in 2023, winning the Naismith Trophy, the Wade Trophy, and the Wooden Award. She led her team to the NCAA championship game in 2023, where they lost to LSU. Name this Iowa Hawkeyes star who was selected as the first overall pick in the 2024 WNBA draft by the Indiana Fever.",
            "answers": ["Caitlin Clark"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This playwright, who married Marilyn Monroe in 1956, was once blacklisted by the House Un-American Activities Committee for refusing to name suspected communists. He is celebrated for his powerful portrayals of American life and social injustice, particularly in plays exploring themes of guilt, responsibility, and the American Dream. Two of his most notable works include \"The Crucible,\" a drama about the Salem witch trials that serves as an allegory for McCarthyism, and \"Death of a Salesman,\" a tragedy about a struggling salesman who grapples with disillusionment and failure.",
            "answers": ["Arthur Miller"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This historic city, located in the \u00cele-de-France region, lies within a basin on the Seine River, approximately 233 miles from its mouth on the English Channel. Its urban landscape is characterized by wide boulevards and a harmonious blend of Haussmannian architecture and iconic landmarks like the Eiffel Tower and Arc de Triomphe. The city is divided into 20 arrondissements, spiraling outward from the historic center on the \u00cele de la Cit\u00e9. Which city, renowned for its art, fashion, and cuisine, serves as the capital of France and a global center of culture?",
            "answers": ["Paris", "Paris, France"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Spanish football club is one of the most successful and popular sports teams globally. Founded in 1902, it has won numerous domestic league titles and holds the record for the most UEFA Champions League victories. Known for their iconic white kits, the club has a storied history featuring legendary players such as Alfredo Di Stefano, Cristiano Ronaldo, and Zinedine Zidane. Their intense rivalry with FC Barcelona, known as \"El Clasico,\" is one of the most famous in sports. What is the name of this football club, renowned for its rich history and success in both national and international competitions?",
            "answers": ["Real Madrid"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "The series finale of this coming-of-age sitcom aired on May 16, 2024 on CBS after seven seasons. This show, filmed in front of a live studio audience, follows the life of a child prodigy in East Texas. It gained a surprising new fan base when it was released on Netflix in Fall 2021. Name this CBS sitcom that is narrated by Jim Parsons and follows the early life of Parsons's character previously featured in the hit show \"The Big Bang Theory.\"",
            "answers": ["Young Sheldon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This revolutionary, born Ioseb Besarionis dze Jughashvili, adopted a pseudonym meaning \"man of steel.\" He orchestrated the Great Purge, a period of political repression and executions. His Five-Year Plans aimed to rapidly industrialize the Soviet Union. As General Secretary of the Communist Party, he led the Soviet Union during World War II and the beginning of the Cold War. Name this Soviet leader.",
            "answers": ["Victor Stalin", "Stalin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "An engineering student at Oregon State University, this athlete struggled to master the straddle and western roll high jump techniques. After experimenting with unconventional methods, he developed a revolutionary back-first technique that he unveiled at the 1968 Mexico City Olympics. Despite initial skepticism, this technique propelled him to a gold medal and quickly became the dominant style in high jump, which now bears his name followed by an alliterative \"Flop.\"",
            "answers": ["Dick Fosbury", "Fosbury"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This cellular structure, a network of interconnected membranous sacs and tubules, plays a crucial role in protein and lipid synthesis. It is divided into two distinct regions: rough, studded with ribosomes and involved in protein production and folding, and smooth, lacking ribosomes and responsible for lipid metabolism and detoxification. Found in all eukaryotic cells, its expansive surface area facilitates its diverse functions. What is the name of this organelle, often referred to as the \"highway\" of the cell due to its role in transporting molecules?",
            "answers": ["Endoplastmic Reticulum", "E.R.", "ER"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Emerging in neutral Switzerland during World War I as a reaction against the war's violence and nationalism, this artistic and literary movement embraced chaos, irrationality, and nonsense. It challenged traditional notions of art and aesthetics, employing techniques like collage, photomontage, and readymades. The name of this movement, possibly chosen at random from a dictionary, is often associated with anti-establishment sentiments. What is the name of this movement whose prominent figures included Tristan Tzara, Marcel Duchamp, and Hugo Ball?",
            "answers": ["Dadaism", "Dada"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "A staunch advocate for democracy, this U.S. president was the first to hold a Ph.D. and taught political science at Princeton University before entering politics. He led the nation through World War I, coining the phrase \"The world must be made safe for democracy.\" However, his dream of establishing the League of Nations faced opposition in Congress, and his health suffered a severe blow when he experienced a debilitating stroke in 1919. Who was this 28th President of the United States who envisioned a new world order after the Great War?",
            "answers": ["Woodrow Wilson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This island city-state, located at the southern tip of the Malay Peninsula, consists of one main island and 62 smaller islets. It is separated from Malaysia by the Johor Strait and from Indonesia by a strait which shares its name. Despite its small size of approximately 734 square kilometers, it is a global financial hub and a major shipping center, boasting the world's busiest transshipment port. Its diverse population comprises predominantly Chinese, Malay, and Indian ethnic groups. Which city-state, known for its cleanliness, efficiency, and strict laws, is a popular destination for both business and leisure travelers?",
            "answers": ["Singapore"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This popular sitcom, filmed in black and white for its first five seasons, was a spin-off of \"The Danny Thomas Show.\" Set in the fictional town of Mayberry, North Carolina, it followed the life of a widowed sheriff, his son, and his bumbling deputy. The show's gentle humor, heartwarming storylines, and memorable characters like Aunt Bee, Gomer Pyle, and Floyd the Barber made it a beloved classic, ranking among the most-watched shows from 1960-1968. Name this iconic comedy series starring Andy Griffith, Ron Howard, and Don Knotts.",
            "answers": ["The Andy Griffith Show", "Andy Griffith"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Born James Cleveland in Oakville, Alabama, this athlete moved to Cleveland, Ohio at age nine. He won four gold medals at the 1936 Berlin Olympics in the 100 meters, 200 meters, long jump, and 4x100 meter relay. His victories challenged Adolf Hitler's propaganda about Aryan racial superiority, as he set Olympic records in the long jump and 200 meters and equaled the world record in the 100 meters. Name this American Olympic icon.",
            "answers": ["Jesse Owens"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "In the 1960s, Canadian scientists Ernest A. McCulloch and James E. Till made a groundbreaking discovery of these cells in mouse bone marrow. Classified into two main types, embryonic and adult, they offer vast potential in regenerative medicine, but also raise ethical concerns, especially with embryonic sources. Their unique ability to differentiate into specialized cells has led to promising research in treating diseases like Parkinson's and diabetes. What are these cells, hailed as a potential breakthrough in medicine yet also the subject of ongoing ethical discussions?",
            "answers": ["Stem Cells"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This European nation established a colony in 1908 which encompassed a vast territory in Central Africa rich in natural resources such as rubber, ivory, and minerals. It gained notoriety for the harsh treatment of the indigenous population under the rule of King Leopold II, leading to international condemnation and a humanitarian crisis. The colonial region ultimately achieved independence in from this nation in 1960, adopting the name Republic of the Congo before later changing it. Name the European nation which held colonial control over the Congo for over five decades.",
            "answers": ["Belgium"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This American president graduated from Eureka College in Illinois and began his career as a sportcaster in Iowa in 1932. He later served as the President of the Screen Actor's Guild then governor of California. John Hinckley attempted to assassinate this man in during his first term, thinking it would impress the actress Jodie Foster. Name this 40th US President who defeated Jimmy Carter and Walter Mondale.",
            "answers": ["Ronald Reagan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Debuting in 1975, this iconic American television show is known for its live sketch comedy and variety performances. Created by Lorne Michaels, it has launched the careers of many comedians and actors, becoming a staple of weekend television. The show is renowned for its topical humor, parodies of political figures, and musical performances, making it a significant part of American pop culture. It has also won numerous Emmy Awards over the decades. What is the name of this long-running program that features a different celebrity host and musical guest each week?",
            "answers": ["Saturday Night Live", "SNL"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Harlem Renaissance poet, who once worked as a busboy, is celebrated for his vibrant depictions of African American life and culture, often incorporating elements of jazz and blues into his writing. Two of his most famous poems include \"I, Too,\" a defiant declaration of racial equality, and \"Harlem,\" a poignant exploration of deferred dreams. He is considered a pioneer of jazz poetry, and his works continue to inspire and resonate with readers today.",
            "answers": ["Langston Hughes"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This vibrant city, nestled between lush mountains and the Atlantic Ocean, is famous for its dramatic landscape, featuring iconic landmarks such as Sugarloaf Mountain and the Christ the Redeemer statue. Its world-renowned Carnival celebrations, filled with music, dance, and elaborate costumes, attract millions of visitors each year. The city's Guanabara Bay, one of the world's largest natural harbors, is dotted with picturesque islands and surrounded by stunning beaches like Copacabana and Ipanema. Which city, the second most populous in Brazil, served as the nation's capital from 1763 to 1960?",
            "answers": ["Rio de Janeiro"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This television show concluded its 25th season on May 16, 2024, extending it's record as the longest-running primetime action series. It airs on NBC and was created by Dick Wolf as a spin off of a classic procedural crime drama. This series focused on two detectives as they investigate and prosecute sexually based crimes in New York City. Name this TV show which stars Mariska Hargitay and Christopher Meloni which was the first spin off from Law and Order. ",
            "answers": [
                "Law and Order: SVU",
                "SVU",
                "special victims unit",
                "law and order: special victims unit"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This organelle, named after its Italian discoverer in 1897, is often referred to as the cell's \"post office\" due to its role in modifying, sorting, and packaging proteins and lipids. It consists of a series of flattened, stacked pouches called cisternae, and plays a crucial role in the secretory pathway. What is the name of this organelle, essential for cellular transport and processing?",
            "answers": ["Golgi Apparatus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Orphaned as a teenager and captured by the British during the Revolutionary War, this future president survived an assassination attempt in 1835 when his would-be killer's pistols misfired. Nicknamed \"Old Hickory\" for his toughness, he rose from humble beginnings to become a lawyer, planter, and military leader. This seventh U.S. president is remembered for his controversial policies towards Native Americans, including the Indian Removal Act and the Trail of Tears. Who is this prominent figure in American history?",
            "answers": ["Andrew Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This historic city, built on seven hills, straddles the Tiber River in the Lazio region of central Italy. Its strategic location on the river, approximately 15 miles inland from the Tyrrhenian Sea, contributed to its rise as a powerful empire. The city's iconic landmarks, including the Colosseum, the Pantheon, and the Forum, are testaments to its rich history and cultural significance. Which city, often called the \"Eternal City,\" serves as the capital of Italy and the spiritual center of the Catholic Church, with Vatican City located entirely within its boundaries?",
            "answers": ["Rome"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This iconic American actress, model, and singer, born Norma Jeane Mortenson in 1926, became one of the most popular sex symbols of the 1950s and early 1960s. Renowned for her comedic \"blonde bombshell\" roles, she starred in several successful films, including \"Some Like It Hot\" and \"The Seven Year Itch,\" the latter featuring the famous scene of her standing over a subway grate as her white dress is blown upwards. Her life, marked by glamour and personal struggles, ended tragically in 1962. What is the name of this legendary film star known for her beauty and tragic life story?",
            "answers": ["Marilyn Monroe"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This region, notorious for its rugged terrain and dense rainforests, poses a significant challenge to travelers and remains a missing link in the Pan-American Highway. It's a biodiversity hotspot, home to a wide array of flora and fauna, including jaguars, harpy eagles, and poisonous dart frogs. Indigenous groups like the Embera and Wounaan have inhabited the area for centuries. In recent years, it has become an increasingly perilous route for migrants fleeing economic and political instability, seeking passage between South and Central America. What is the name of this 66-mile stretch of undeveloped wilderness between Panama and Colombia?",
            "answers": ["Darien Gap"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Austrian-born corporal and failed artist served in the Bavarian Army during World War I. He rose to power as the charismatic leader of the National Socialist German Workers' Party, becoming Chancellor of Germany in 1933. His hateful ideology, outlined in his book Mein Kampf, led to the persecution and genocide of Jews and other minorities in the Holocaust. His aggressive expansionist policies, including the annexation of Austria and invasion of Poland, plunged the world into the devastating conflict of World War II. Who is this infamous dictator who committed suicide in a Berlin bunker in 1945?",
            "answers": ["Adolf Hitler"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Nicknamed \"Big Red,\" this chestnut racehorse with three white stockings won the Triple Crown in 1973, setting records in all three races that still stand today. His Belmont Stakes victory, a 31-length triumph, is considered one of the greatest performances in horse racing history. Upon his death, his heart was found to be more than twice the size of an average horse's heart, a possible explanation for his exceptional speed and endurance. Name this legendary racehorse.",
            "answers": ["Secretariat"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This openly gay American poet, known for his raw and confessional style, wrote a controversial poem which led to a landmark trial for freedom of speech in 1957. A leading figure of the Beat Generation, he was expelled from Columbia University for writing obscene graffiti and befriended other Beat icons like Jack Kerouac and William S. Burroughs. His works often explored themes of sexuality, spirituality, and the American experience, with notable poems including \"Howl\", \"Kaddish\", and \"America.\"",
            "answers": ["Allen Ginsberg"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Born in Texas and raised in Kansas, this five-star general served as Supreme Commander of the Allied Forces in Europe during World War II, overseeing the D-Day invasion of Normandy. A gifted strategist and charismatic leader, he later became president of Columbia University before being elected President of the United States. Known for his \"Atoms for Peace\" speech and his farewell address warning of the \"military-industrial complex,\" he championed infrastructure development with the Interstate Highway System during his two terms in office. Who is this military hero and 34th President of the United States?",
            "answers": ["Dwight D Eisenhower", "Eisenhower"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This politician is being investigated by the FBI for possible campaign violations related to illegal fundraising from Turkish nationals. Before he was a politician, this man served as a New York police office for more than 20 years. He went on to become the first Black President of Brooklyn Borough in New York in 2013. In 2021, this man was elected Mayor of New York over Curtis Silwa.",
            "answers": ["Eric Adams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This exiled revolutionary adopted a pseudonym derived from the Lena River. This man published the \"April Theses\" which led to the October Revolution, in which his Bolsheviks overthrew the Russian regime. An offshoot ideology of Marxism bares his name. Name this man who was the first leader of the Soviet Union from 1922-1924.",
            "answers": ["Vladimir Lenin", "Vladimir Ilyich Ulyanov", "Lenin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This sprawling metropolis, the third most populous in Africa, traces its roots back to a Roman fortress established in the 1st century AD. Its name, derived from the Arabic word \"Al-Qahirah\" meaning \"the victorious,\" reflects its historical significance as a center of power and culture. Located near the apex of the Nile Delta, it boasts iconic landmarks such as the Citadel of Salah al-Din and the Mosque of Muhammad Ali. Which city, a modern-day megacity with a population exceeding 20 million, is home to the renowned Museum of Egyptian Antiquities, housing a vast collection of ancient artifacts, including the treasures of Tutankhamun?",
            "answers": ["Cairo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Overcoming polio as a child, this athlete became the first American woman to win three gold medals in track and field at a single Olympic Games. Competing at the 1960 Rome Olympics, she dominated the 100-meter and 200-meter sprints, as well as the 4x100-meter relay, solidifying her place as one of the greatest female athletes of all time. Name this athlete who retired from competition at the peak of her athletic career in 1962 and went on to graduate from Tennessee State University and become an educator and coach.",
            "answers": ["Wilma Rudolph"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This German astronomer, mathematician, and author was born in Weil der Stadt in 1571. Despite suffering from smallpox as a child, he worked as an assistant to Tycho Brahe and later succeeded him as the imperial mathematician. He has been described as the \"father of science fiction\" for his novel Somnium. He is most known for his three laws of planetary motion, which revolutionized our understanding of the solar system and paved the way for Isaac Newton's law of universal gravitation. Who was this key figure in the scientific revolution?",
            "answers": ["Johannes Kepler"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This popular Christmas character, created by Robert L. May for a Montgomery Ward promotional booklet, was initially rejected by the company's executives for his unusual physical trait. Voiced by Billie Mae Richards in the 1964 stop-motion animated television special, this character is ostracized for his unusual nose but eventually becomes a hero when his unique attribute proves essential for guiding Santa's sleigh through a blizzard. The character's story has been adapted into numerous songs, movies, and television shows, and has become a beloved symbol of acceptance and embracing differences.",
            "answers": [
                "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer",
                "rudolph",
                "rudolf",
                "rudolph the reindeer"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Originally written in French during World War II, this allegorical novella tells the story of a young prince who travels from his asteroid to Earth, encountering various characters like a vain rose, a conceited king, and a drunkard. The book is beloved for its simple yet profound message about the importance of childlike wonder and imagination, and it has been translated into over 500 languages, making it the second most translated book of all time after The Bible. What is the name of this book which has sold over 140 million copies?",
            "answers": ["The Little Prince"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This party was founded by several ex-Whigs. Past leaders of this party include Newt Gingrich, the creator of the Contract with America, and Teddy Roosevelt. One member of this party made a campaign pledge of \"no new taxes,\" and Libertarians traditionally run under this major party's banner. It is currently chaired by Michael Whatley. Name this major party also called the \"Grand Old Party.\"",
            "answers": ["Republican Party", "Republican"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This American city, built on three islands - Manhattan, Staten Island, and part of Long Island - is home to five boroughs, each with its own distinct character. The city is also home to Central Park, an 843-acre oasis in the heart of Manhattan, and the Statue of Liberty, a symbol of freedom and democracy. What is the name of this bustling metropolis, known for its skyscrapers, Broadway theaters, and diverse population?",
            "answers": ["New York City", "New York", "NYC"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NFL team, established in 1919, is the only community-owned franchise in the league. It boasts a passionate fanbase known as \"Cheeseheads,\" who often wear foam cheese-shaped hats to games. The team's colors are green and gold, and their logo features a white oval with a green \"G\" inside. They have won four Super Bowl championships, including the first two Super Bowls. What is the name of this team, whose home stadium is Lambeau Field in Wisconsin?",
            "answers": ["Green Bay Packers", "Packers"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This restaurateur and television personality is known for his distinctive blonde spiky hair and goatee. He studied abroad as an exchange student in Chantilly, France, which expanded his culinary horizons. He gained widespread recognition by winning the second season of The Next Food Network Star in 2006. Who is this celebrity chef, known for his catchphrase \"Flavortown\" and hosting shows like \"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives\"? ",
            "answers": ["Guy Fieri"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This man described a trip around America with his poodle in Travels with Charley. In a novella by this man, George shoots Lennie to prevent him from being lynched. This man also wrote about the Joad family's attempt to escape the Depression by moving to California from Oklahoma. Identify this American author of Of Mice and Men and The Grapes of Wrath.",
            "answers": ["John Steinbeck", "Steinbeck", "John Ernst Steinbeck"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Despite being heavily guarded, this structure was successfully breached over 5,000 times by individuals using creative methods like hot air balloons, tunnels, and even tightropes. Its construction led to the displacement of over 100,000 people, and its existence became a focal point for Cold War tensions and a symbol of oppression. The first victim of this barrier was Ida Siekmann, who died while attempting to jump from her apartment window in East Berlin. What is the name of this infamous structure, which divided a city and a nation for 28 years? ",
            "answers": ["Berlin Wall"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Robert Fico, the Prime Minister for this nation was shot in an assassination attempt on May 15, 2024. The Central European country, known for its medieval castles and picturesque mountain ranges, is home to the High Tatras, the smallest high mountain range in the world. Its capital, Bratislava, is the only capital city that borders two other countries, Austria and Hungary. What is the name of this country, whose national dish is bryndzov\u00e9 halu\u0161ky, potato dumplings with sheep cheese and bacon?",
            "answers": ["Slovakia"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This constellation is often interpreted as fighting Taurus with his dogs Canis Minor and Canis Major. Stars within this constellation include the \"amazon star\" Bellatrix, the red giant Betelgeuse, and Rigel. It is most easily recognizable by the three stars making up the belt of the figure in this constellation. Name this constellation also known as \"the Hunter.\"",
            "answers": ["Orion"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "On May 19, 2024, this nation's President died in a helicopter crash while flying back from neighboring Azerbaijan. Although they have a president, the country is led by Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei, the longest serving head of state in the Middle East. The United States and its allies agreed to the Joint Comprehensive Plan on Action to end economic sanctions on this nation in exchange for a restriction on producing enriched uranium for nuclear weapons. The United States pulled out of this deal during the Trump Administration. Name this nation formerly known as Persia.",
            "answers": ["Iran"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Formed in London in 1962, this band is known for their iconic tongue and lips logo, their blues-inspired sound, and their rebellious image. Their 1969 album \"Let It Bleed\" included hits like \"Gimme Shelter\" and \"You Can't Always Get What You Want.\" Who is this legendary band, fronted by Mick Jagger and Keith Richards?",
            "answers": ["The Rolling Stones"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This five-week battle in 1945 was immortalized by Joe Rosenthal's Pulitzer Prize-winning photograph of six US Marines raising the American flag atop Mount Suribachi. The iconic black sand beaches of this island were the site of the initial landings, and the battle saw some of the fiercest fighting of the Pacific War. What is the name of this battle, which ultimately resulted in an American victory, but with heavy casualties on both sides?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Iwo Jima"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NFL team, established in 1959 as the Titans, is the only team in NFL history to win its lone Super Bowl appearance, defeating the heavily favored Baltimore Colts in Super Bowl III. Their victory was led by quarterback Joe Namath, who famously guaranteed a win before the game. The team's colors are green and white. What is the name of this team, whose home stadium is MetLife Stadium in East Rutherford, New Jersey?",
            "answers": ["New York Jets", "Jets", "NY Jets"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This man wrote about an animal who steals from the farmers Boggis, Bunce and Bean in The Fantastic Mister Fox. He also wrote about a girl with psychic powers who reads every book in the library and then loses her powers in Miss Honey's class in his book Matilda. A better known book by this man sees its title fruit get stuck on top of the Empire State Building. Name this author of James and the Giant Peach.",
            "answers": ["Roald Dahl", "Dahl"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The law of these objects states that the torque on one side is equal to the torque on the other side. These objects can be classified as first class, second class, or third class depending on the location of the fulcrum. Name these simple machines, familiar examples of which include a wheelbarrow and see-saw.",
            "answers": ["levers"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Landmarks on this island include the El Yunque rainforest and Fort San Felipe del Moro. Humacao, Caguas, Bayamon, and Ponce are some of its municipalities. The largest municipality shares the name given to the island by Columbus, San Juan. Identify this island, a United States commonwealth in the Caribbean.",
            "answers": ["Puerto Rico"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "After having much of his legislation overturned by the Supreme Court, this leader proposed his court packing plan. The Tennessee Valley Authority was one piece of New Deal legislation that was not overturned by the Court. Although he led his country for most of World War II, he did not make the decision to drop the atomic bombs on Japan. He succeeded Herbert Hoover. Who is the only President of the United States to be elected to more than two terms in office?",
            "answers": [
                "Franklin Delano Roosevelt",
                "FDR",
                "Franklin Roosevelt",
                "F.D.R."
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This artist's statues of a dying slave and a horned Moses were to adorn the tomb of Julius II. His only signed work is one in which Mary holds the dead body of Jesus, entitled Piet\u00e0. One of his works depicts a nude giant killer holding a sling. This man depicted several scenes from Genesis in The Last Judgement. Name this Italian Renaissance painter of the Sistine Chapel ceiling.",
            "answers": ["Michelangelo", "Buonarroti"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "One theory of this entity's creation states that a Mars-sized body named Theia collided with its parent planet. This object exhibits synchronous rotation with its parent planet, and that rotation results in the namesake \"dark side\" of this object. The Sea of Tranquility lies on what astronomical body responsible for the Earth's tides, its largest natural satellite?",
            "answers": ["The Moon", "Luna", "moon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This left fielder for the Chicago White Sox, known for his exceptional hitting ability and illiterate background, allegedly participated in the infamous Black Sox Scandal of 1919. Despite being acquitted in court, he was banned from baseball for life by Commissioner Kenesaw Mountain Landis. His lifetime batting average of .356 remains the fourth-highest in Major League Baseball history. Who is this player, nicknamed \"Shoeless Joe\" for once playing a game without his cleats due to blisters?",
            "answers": ["Joe Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Located on the Yangtze River Delta in East China, this city is home to the world's busiest container port and is divided into two sections by the Huangpu River. It is a major financial hub and home to the third tallest building in the world. Its unique cityscape features a mix of traditional Chinese architecture and modern skyscrapers. What is the name of this city, known for its historic Bund waterfront and vibrant nightlife?",
            "answers": ["Shanghai"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "The sale of this iconic Memphis property was recently stalled by a Tennessee judge. This mansion, located on Elvis Presley Boulevard, was purchased in 1957 for just over $100,000 from a woman named Ruth Moore, whose family had built the home two decades earlier. It's famous for its Jungle Room, a Polynesian-inspired den complete with a 15-foot waterfall. The property includes a Meditation Garden, the final resting place of the King of Rock and Roll and several of his family members. What is this iconic Memphis landmark, a pilgrimage site for Elvis fans worldwide?",
            "answers": ["Graceland"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This philosopher's method of questioning, known as \"elenchus,\" involved a series of inquiries aimed at exposing contradictions and inconsistencies in a person's beliefs. He never wrote down his ideas, but his student Plato recorded his teachings in dialogues like \"The Republic\" and \"Apology.\" This philosopher was sentenced to death by hemlock for \"corrupting the youth of Athens.\" Name this ancient Greek thinker, considered the father of Western philosophy.",
            "answers": ["Socrates"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British rock band's 1985 Live Aid performance is regarded as one of the greatest live performances in history. The band, known for their flamboyant stage presence and operatic harmonies, was founded in London in 1970 by Freddie Mercury, Brian May, Roger Taylor, and John Deacon. Their 1975 single stayed at the top of the UK charts for nine weeks and is considered one of the greatest rock songs of all time. Who is this iconic band, whose music has sold over 300 million records worldwide?",
            "answers": ["Queen"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This 1876 battle, a major turning point in the Great Sioux War, saw Lakota, Northern Cheyenne, and Arapaho warriors led by Sitting Bull and Crazy Horse defeat the U.S. 7th Cavalry Regiment. It took place near a river in Montana Territory, and is often romanticized as \"Custer's Last Stand.\" This victory for Indigenous forces was short-lived, as the U.S. Army eventually prevailed in the war. Name this battle, which has been the subject of numerous films and books.",
            "answers": ["Battle of Little Bighorn", "Custers Last Stand"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "One variety of this faith is outlined in the Pali Canon. Another variety venerates those who become enlightened but remain in samsara, called bodhisattvas. Those varieties are Theravada and Mahayana.  Adherents to another variety of this faith meditate on koans such as \"What is the sound of one hand clapping?\". Name this Asian faith that venerates Siddhartha Gautama.",
            "answers": ["Buddhism"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Responsible for the formation of salts like table salt, this chemical bond results from the transfer of electrons between atoms, creating oppositely charged ions that attract each other. It is typically formed between metals and nonmetals, and its strength is determined by the magnitude of the charges and the distance between the ions. What is this type of bond called?",
            "answers": ["ionic bond"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Canadian city, situated on the northwestern shore of Lake Ontario, is actually built on a glacial plain. It is home to a group of 15 islands which were formed by sediment deposits and erosion. The city's Don River Valley, carved by the last ice age, is a popular natural area for hiking and biking. What is the name of this city, the largest in Canada and the fourth largest in North America? ",
            "answers": ["Toronto"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British filmmaker began his career designing title cards for silent films. His 1929 film, Blackmail, was the first British \"talkie.\" He was knighted by Queen Elizabeth II in 1980, just a few months before his death. He directed suspenseful thrillers such as \"Psycho,\" \"Vertigo,\" and \"North by Northwest,\" earning him the nickname the \"Master of Suspense.\" Who is this iconic director, known for his cameo appearances in his own films? ",
            "answers": ["Alfred Hitchcock"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Policies during this war included the \"strategic hamlet\" program and the use of Agent Orange as a defoliant. The Battle of Khe Sanh was fought during this war, which ended with the fall of Saigon, a city that was renamed after the victorious side's leader, Ho Chi Minh. A memorial wall in Washington, DC lists the American casualties of what conflict in Southeast Asia?",
            "answers": ["Vietnam War"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This British Prime Minister surprisingly called for a snap election to be held on July 4, 2024. Before becoming Prime Minister, he served as the Chancellor of the Exchequer beginning in 2020 under Boris Johnson. He was born in Southampton and received an MBA from Stanford University as a Fulbright Scholar. Name this man who has led the United Kingdom's Conservative Party since 2022 when he became the first British Asian Prime Minister.",
            "answers": ["Rishi Sunak"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This two-time Olympic gold medalist and two-time FIFA Women's World Cup champion was the youngest woman to ever play for the U.S. national soccer team at the age of 15. She held the record for most international goals scored until 2013 and still ranks third in the history of the U.S. team for international caps and first for career assists. She is married to former MLB shortstop Nomar Garciaparra. Who is this legendary soccer player, often considered one of the greatest female athletes of all time?",
            "answers": ["Mia Hamm"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This play's opening brawl is started by Gregory and Samson. Later in this play, Friar John fails to deliver a letter written by Friar Lawrence. Mercutio is killed by Tybalt in Act III of this play. This play features the feud between the Montagues and the Capulets. Name this Shakespeare tragedy, depicting a doomed romance between the two title \"star-crossed lovers.\"",
            "answers": ["Romeo and Juliet"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This landmark Supreme Court case centered on a Texas state law that criminalized abortion in most instances. The plaintiff, a pregnant woman seeking to terminate her pregnancy, challenged the law's constitutionality. The Court's 1973 decision established that a woman's right to have an abortion was protected by the constitutional right to privacy. Name this controversial case, which was later overturned in 2022 by Dobbs v. Jackson Women's Health Organization.",
            "answers": ["Roe v. Wade", "Roe vs. Wade", "Roe"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Built on 43 hills and surrounded by the Pacific Ocean and a bay, this city is home to the infamous former prison on Alcatraz Island and a man-made island initially built for a World's Fair. Locals often refer to the city's frequent fog by the name \"Karl\". What is this city known for its steep streets, including the crooked Lombard Street?",
            "answers": ["San Francisco"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Nicknamed the \"First Lady of Song\", this jazz vocalist was known for her scat singing and ability to imitate instruments with her voice. She won her first Grammy in 1958, becoming the first African-American woman to do so. Who is this iconic singer, known for her collaborations with Louis Armstrong and Duke Ellington?",
            "answers": ["Ella Fitzgerald"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This American transportation service experienced an outage between New York and Philadelphia on May 21 and 22 causing major delays for commuters. The service was founded in 1971 as a quasi-public corporation and is headquartered in Union Station in Washington D.C. Nearly 87,000 passengers ride more than 300 of the service's trains daily. In 2022, they served 22.9 million passengers. Name this rail service with service in 46 U.S. States.",
            "answers": ["Amtrak"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This man fought against Ariovistus, a German leader, and Vercingetorix, a chieftain of the Arverni whose defeat is described in this man's book, Commentaries on the Gallic Wars. He led his troops across the Rubicon to start a civil war with Pompey, one of his partners in the First Triumvirate. Name this Roman leader who was assassinated by Brutus on the Ides of March.",
            "answers": ["Julius Caesar", "Caesar"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team's home court, Madison Square Garden, is often referred to as \"The World's Most Famous Arena.\" The team's colors are orange, blue, and white. They have won two NBA championships, both in the early 1970s, with a team that included legends like Walt Frazier and Willis Reed. In 1994, they made it to the NBA Finals but lost to the Houston Rockets. What is the name of this team, located in New York City?",
            "answers": ["New York Knicks", "Knicks"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Two liquids are said to be immiscible if they cannot combine to form this type of mixture. In the most common form of this mixture, solid particles are small enough to completely dissolve in a liquid. Name this type of mixture that is not a colloid or suspension, an example of which is sugar dissolved in water.",
            "answers": ["solution"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "The most winning woman he ever knew was hanged for poisoning three little children for their insurance-money. Irene Adler, always THE woman to this man, outwitted him during his investigation of 'A Scandal in Bohemia.' This man returned in 'The Adventure of the Empty House' after battling Professor Moriarty to the death. Name this detective faithfully accompanied by John Watson.",
            "answers": ["Sherlock Holmes"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Supreme Court case centered around a Louisiana state law mandating racial segregation on trains. The plaintiff, a man of mixed race, deliberately violated this law to challenge its constitutionality. The Court's controversial ruling in 1896 established the doctrine of \"separate but equal,\" which upheld racial segregation in public facilities for decades. Name this landmark case, which had a profound impact on the civil rights movement in the United States.",
            "answers": [
                "Plessy vs Ferguson",
                "Plessy",
                "Ferguson",
                "Plessy v. Ferguson"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "In the Spring of 2024, this rapper revitalized a feud with Drake by releasing the first in a series diss tracks, \"Euphoria\", in response to Drake's release of \"Push Ups\" and \"Taylor Made Freestyle\". This Pulitzer Prize-winning rapper released his debut studio album, \"Section.80,\" in 2011, which gained critical acclaim and established him as a rising star in hip hop. His subsequent albums, including \"Good Kid, M.A.A.D City,\" \"To Pimp a Butterfly,\" and \"DAMN.,\" explored themes of race, identity, and social justice, earning him numerous awards and accolades. Name this West Coast rapper who first released music under the name K.Dot in high school.",
            "answers": ["Kendrick Lamar"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Discovered in 1799 by French soldiers during Napoleon's Egyptian campaign, this black basalt slab contains a decree issued in Memphis, Egypt, in 196 BCE on behalf of King Ptolemy V Epiphanes. Its inscription is written in three scripts: hieroglyphics, Demotic script, and Ancient Greek. This allowed scholars to decipher hieroglyphics, unlocking the secrets of Ancient Egypt and revolutionizing our understanding of this ancient civilization. What is the name of this artifact, now housed in the British Museum in London?",
            "answers": ["Rosetta Stone"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The Euler line passes through the orthocenter, circumcenter, and centroid in this figure. The area of this polygon can be found by halving the product of two sides and the sine of the angle opposite of the third side or by simply using Heron's formula. It is the only polygon that cannot be concave, because its angles must add to 180 degrees. Name this polygon with three sides.",
            "answers": ["triangle"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "At one point in this musical, Dr. Dillamond sings \"Something Bad.\" At another point, Madame Morrible announces that the main character is now an enemy of the town, and that character then sings \"Defying Gravity.\" The two heroines in it were originally played by Kristin Chenoweth and Idina Menzel. The relationship between Elphaba and Glinda is documented in what musical based on The Wizard of Oz?",
            "answers": ["Wicked"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "In this novel, a town is fooled by two men who pull off the Royal Nonesuch, and those men go on to steal the property of the late Peter Wilkes. The Widow Douglas wants to \"sivilize\" the title character, who misses a turn at Cairo and keeps floating south. Name this novel that sees Jim and the title friend of Tom Sawyer travel down the Mississippi River, a work by Mark Twain.",
            "answers": [
                "The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn",
                "Huckleberry Finn",
                "Huck Finn"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team's colors are navy blue, gold, and cool gray. They have won three championships, all in the ABA, and have a fierce rivalry with the Detroit Pistons. Reggie Miller, one of their most famous players, is known for his clutch three-pointers and trash-talking. What is the name of this team currently coached by Rick Carlisle, based in Indianapolis, Indiana?",
            "answers": ["Indiana Pacers", "Pacers"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "The Andean type of these entities occurs beneath a continental plate, and it is at these sites that about 20% of Earth's crust has been consumed. This antithesis of the mid-oceanic ridge is usually typified by lines of volcanoes running parallel near an oceanic trench. Identify this region where tectonic plates collide, and one goes underneath the other.",
            "answers": ["subduction zone"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This character was named after the wife of King Leontes in The Winter's Tale. This character forms an organization called S.P.E.W., and purchases a half-cat, half-kneazle known as Crookshanks. Though she is called a 'mudblood' because of her dentist parents, she is smart enough to have memorized \"Hogwarts: A History.\" Name this female companion to Harry and Ron in the \"Harry Potter\" series.",
            "answers": ["Hermione Granger", "Hermione", "Granger"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "In Spring 2024, Kenya committed 1,000 police officers to help diminish gang violence in this nation as part of a U.N. sanctioned mission which is being financed by the United States. On July 7, 2021 the president of this nation was assassinated and no replacement has been chosen. The country has a recent history of devastating earthquakes leading to increased poverty. Name this Caribbean nation, once a French colony known as Saint-Domingue, is where the Vodou religion originated.",
            "answers": ["Haiti"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "The title character in the movie \"V for Vendetta\" wears a mask depicting this man. In 1605, this devout Catholic attempted to assassinate King James I of England by blowing up the House of Lords during the State Opening of Parliament. He was discovered in the cellar beneath Parliament and was subsequently tortured and executed. His actions are commemorated annually on November 5th in the United Kingdom, with fireworks displays. Who is this historical figure, whose name has become synonymous with rebellion and conspiracy?",
            "answers": ["Guy Fawkes", "Guy Fox", "Fawkes", "Fox"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Union general's \"Special Field Order No. 15\" promised freed slaves \"forty acres and a mule,\" though it was later revoked. His capture of Atlanta in 1864 boosted Union morale and helped re-elect President Lincoln. He is known for his \"March to the Sea,\" a destructive campaign through Georgia designed to demoralize the Confederacy. Name this general, infamous for his embrace of \"total war\" tactics during the American Civil War.",
            "answers": [
                "William Tecumseh Sherman",
                "General Sherman",
                "General William Tecumseh Sherman",
                "Tecumseh Sherman"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "While travelling back to his hometown, this man solves a riddle with the answer of 'man.' He kills his own father over the right-of-way at a crossroads. This man fathers his daughter Antigone by his own mother Jocasta, fulfilling a prophecy made at his birth. Name this title character of plays by Sophocles, including one in which he is at Colonus and one in which he is Rex, or The King.",
            "answers": ["Oedipus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American tennis player, known for her powerful serve and volley game, won 39 Grand Slam titles throughout her career. She co-founded the Women's Tennis Association and the World TeamTennis league, advocating for gender equality in sports. In 1973, she defeated Bobby Riggs in the highly publicized \"Battle of the Sexes\" tennis match. Who is this influential athlete, the first prominent female athlete to come out as gay?",
            "answers": ["Billy Jean King", "King"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "A pressure associated with this process is a colligative property proportional to mass and temperature, and is defined as the hydrostatic pressure necessary to counteract this process. A 'reverse' form of this process is sometimes used to purify water. Name this movement of water across a semi-permeable membrane from an area of high concentration to an area of low concentration.",
            "answers": ["osmosis", "diffusion"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "One piece of evidence that supports the existence of this land mass is that the Caledonian mountains of Northern Europe are a continuation of the Appalachian Mountains. This entity broke up into Laurasia and Gondwanaland. Alfred Wegener coined its name during a lecture in which he discussed his theory of continental drift. Name this supercontinent theorized to have existed 250 million years ago.",
            "answers": ["Pangea"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The size of these objects is given by the Schwarzschild radius. According to quantum mechanics, these objects emit Hawking radiation. One of them, Sagittarius A Star, sits at the center of our galaxy and has four million times the mass of our sun. Name these objects in outer space from which supposedly nothing, not even light, can escape?",
            "answers": ["black hole"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This man's wife Jiang Qing was a member of the Gang of Four. He escaped a Kuomintang offensive led by Chiang Kai-shek and went on the Long March in 1934. After he took power in 1949, his government adopted such policies as the Great Leap Forward and the Cultural Revolution. The Little Red Book was written by what Chairman of China's Communist Party?",
            "answers": ["Mao Zedong", "Mao"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "The oldest person to hold this position was Roger Taney. This office serves as Chancellor of the Smithsonian, and also presides over Presidential impeachment trials. It was held by Charles Evans Hughes, John Marshall, and Earl Warren, the latter of whom wrote an opinion that mandated the so-called 'Miranda Rights'. Name this position currently held by John Roberts Jr., the head of the federal judiciary.",
            "answers": [
                "Chief Justice of the Supreme Court",
                "chief justice",
                "chief justice of the us supreme court",
                "chief justice of the united states supreme court"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "The kicker of this NFL team has recently come under fire for his graduation speech at Benedictine College in Kansas. In the speech, delivered by Harrison Butker, he derided pride month, university diversity initiatives, and suggested that women may not achieve the same fulfillment in careers and they would from homemaking. This team won the Super Bowl in 2023 and 2024 quarterbacked by Patrick Mahomes. Name this NFL team which plays in Kansas City. ",
            "answers": ["Kansas City Chiefs", " Chiefs"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British actor, writer, and director, born in London in 1889, became a global icon for his character \"The Tramp,\" a bumbling yet endearing figure with a bowler hat, cane, and oversized shoes. He was a pioneer in the silent film era, writing, directing, and starring in \"The Kid,\" \"The Gold Rush,\" and \"City Lights.\" He was satirized Adolf Hitler in his 1940 film \"The Great Dictator.\" Who is this legendary figure of early cinema, known for his physical comedy and heartwarming stories?",
            "answers": ["Charlie Chaplin"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NHL team, with their iconic winged wheel logo, has a rich history dating back to 1926, when they were known as the Cougars. They are one of the \"Original Six\" teams in the NHL and have won 11 Stanley Cup championships, the most of any American team. They are known for their passionate fanbase and the tradition of throwing octopi on the ice during playoff games. What is the name of this team, based in Detroit, Michigan, whose home arena is Little Caesars Arena?",
            "answers": ["Detroit Red Wings", "Red Wings"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Australian city, the capital of New South Wales, is home to the world's largest natural harbor, Port Jackson. It's home to Iconic landmarks like the Harbour Bridge, and it is bordered by national parks, including the Royal National Park to the south and the Blue Mountains National Park to the west. The city's most famous landmark, designed by Danish architect J\u00f8rn Utzon, has a distinctive sail-like design. What is the name of this bustling metropolis, renowned for its beaches?",
            "answers": ["Sydney"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Three square windows can be seen in the back of this painting, and the back of a chair takes up its lower center portion. The central figure is wearing red and blue with his hands on a table; to his right is an effeminate figure believed to be the Apostle John. Judas clutches a bag of silver in what Leonardo da Vinci painting that depicts Christ's final meal with his disciples?",
            "answers": ["The Last Supper"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "During his execution, this figure was pierced by the Lance of Longinus. In addition to yelling at a fig tree for not bearing fruit, this figure healed a pig-eating man from Gerasa possessed by a horde of devils named Legion. This man was put to death by Pontius Pilate, and drops of his blood fell into the Holy Grail. Name this Messiah and only son of God according to Christianity.",
            "answers": ["Jesus", "Jesus Christ"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This type of chemical bond, formed by the sharing of electron pairs between atoms, is responsible for the stability of many molecules, including water and carbon dioxide. Its strength is determined by the number of shared electron pairs, with double and triple bonds being stronger than single bonds. It is prevalent in organic compounds, forming the backbone of complex molecules like DNA and proteins. What is the name of this bond, which plays a crucial role in the chemistry of life?",
            "answers": ["Covalent bond"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "In the buildup to this battle, the losing commander set up a fortification at Gloucester shortly after retreating from Williamsburg. A key turning point in this battle was the arrival of reinforcements under Count Rochambeau. British naval forces under Thomas Graves failed to break through the French blockade. Name this final Revolutionary War battle, after which Lord Cornwallis surrendered.",
            "answers": ["Battle of Yorktown", "Yorktown"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "He fulfilled a prophecy by accidentally killing his grandfather Acrisius with a discus. Acrisius had imprisoned his mother, Danae, but Zeus visited her as a golden shower. This man borrowed the invisibility cap of Hades, the reflective shield of Athena, and the winged sandals of Hermes. He slew a sea monster that was about to consume Andromeda, whom he made his wife. Name this figure who beheaded Medusa.",
            "answers": ["Perseus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "The island of Bornholm is in this body of water, which is connected by the Kiel Canal to the North Sea. One arm of this sea is the Gulf of Bothnia, and the large island of Saaremaa guards its Gulf of Riga. Five national capitals lie on this body of water, including Tallinn, the capital of Estonia, and Stockholm. Name this sea south of Scandinavia.",
            "answers": ["Baltic Sea"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "The International Criminal Court issued an arrest warrant for this international leader in March 2024. This man has served as prime minister of his home nation three separate times making him the nation's longest serving prime minister. Chair of the Likud Party, he was raised in West Jerusalem and the United States. Name this prime minister of Israel who has come under fire from the ICC due to Israel's military operations in Gaza.",
            "answers": [
                "Benjamin Netanyahu",
                "Bibi Netanyahu",
                "netanyahu",
                "bibi"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete of Native American heritage won gold medals in both the pentathlon and decathlon at the 1912 Stockholm Olympics, only to have them stripped due to a technicality regarding his amateur status.  He later played professional football, baseball, and basketball, becoming the first president of the American Professional Football Association (later the NFL). In 1950, an Associated Press poll named him the greatest athlete of the first half of the 20th century.  Who is this remarkable multi-sport athlete, whose Olympic medals were posthumously restored in 1983? ",
            "answers": ["Jim Thorpe"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Spanish-American chef, known for his innovative tapas, trained under Ferran Adri\u00e0 at elBulli in Spain. He later moved to the United States, where he opened a series of successful restaurants, including Jaleo, Zaytinya, and minibar. He also founded World Central Kitchen, a non-profit organization providing meals to communities affected by disasters. Who is this culinary icon, named one of Time's 100 Most Influential People in both 2012 and 2018?",
            "answers": ["Jose Andres"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The DNA in this organelle is inherited only from the mother. The inner membrane of this organelle contains folds known as cristae and encloses its matrix. This organelle is the site of oxidative phosphorylation, which occurs at the end of the electron transport chain. Name this organelle responsible for cellular respiration, which produces ATP and thus provides energy for the cell.",
            "answers": ["mitochondria", "mitochondrion"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Born Robert Allen Zimmerman in Duluth, Minnesota, this singer-songwriter's early career was marked by his folk music and protest songs like \"Blowin' in the Wind\" and \"The Times They Are a-Changin'.\" He later transitioned to electric guitar and rock music, a move that caused controversy among his folk fanbase. His poetic lyrics and distinctive voice earned him a Nobel Prize in Literature in 2016. Name this musician who released his first album in 1962.",
            "answers": ["Bob Dylan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This man composed a ballet called The Creatures of Prometheus, and Leonato is a major character in his opera Fidelio. His third symphony was originally written to honor Napoleon and was called Eroica. A later symphony by this man borrows from Schiller's \"Ode to Joy\" for its choral final movement. Name this composer whose fifth symphony begins with a fate knocking at the door theme and who went deaf before his death in 1827.",
            "answers": ["Ludwig von Beethoven", "beethoven"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NFL team, established in 1965, has appeared in two Super Bowls, Super Bowl XXXIII and Super Bowl LI, losing both times. The team's iconic \"Dirty Bird\" dance, popularized by running back Jamal Anderson in the late 1990s, became a symbol of their success during that era.  They currently play their home games at Mercedes-Benz Stadium. What is the name of this team, based in Atlanta, Georgia, whose colors are red, black, silver, and white?",
            "answers": ["Atlanta Falcons", "Falcons"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This man won the right to appeal his extradition to the United States for violating the Espionage Act on May 22, 2024. He is currently serving prison time in the United Kingdom for violating the Bail Act due to the fact he dodged a European arrest warrant by taking asylum in the Ecuadorian embassy in London from 2012-2019. Name this Australian founder of WikiLeaks",
            "answers": ["Julian Assange", "Assange"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Born in Nepal during the 6th century BCE, he renounced his royal life at the age of 29 to seek enlightenment and understand the nature of suffering. After meditating under a bodhi tree for 49 days, he attained enlightenment and became known as the \"Awakened One.\" He then dedicated his life to teaching others the path to liberation from suffering, establishing a religion that has profoundly influenced the world for over 2,500 years. Who is this spiritual leader and religious founder?\n",
            "answers": ["Buddha", "Siddhartha Gautama"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This landmark Supreme Court case challenged the \"separate but equal\" doctrine established in Plessy v. Ferguson. The case involved several African American students who were denied admission to public schools attended by white children. The Court's unanimous decision in 1954 declared that racial segregation in public education violated the Equal Protection Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment, effectively overturning Plessy v. Ferguson. Name this case, which marked a major victory for the civil rights movement in the United States.",
            "answers": [
                "Brown vs Board of Education",
                "Brown",
                "Brown v. Board",
                "Brown v. Board of Education"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This European capital city, built on the River Thames, is divided into 32 boroughs. It is home to the Prime Meridian of the World, which passes through the Royal Observatory in Greenwich. The city is also known for its many parks and green spaces, including Hyde Park, Regent's Park, and Greenwich Park. What is the name of this city, famous for its red double-decker buses and black cabs?",
            "answers": ["London", "London, England"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "J. R. R. Tolkien was inspired to create the Ents by his disappointment with the resolution of a prophecy in this play, in which an army dresses up as trees. Another prophecy in this play is fulfilled when a character reveals that he was born by C-section. A character cries \"out, damned spot!\" after encouraging her husband to kill Duncan in what Shakespeare play about a Scottish king?",
            "answers": ["Macbeth", "The Tragedy of Macbeth"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "A thinker from this country wrote an essay claiming that \"God is dead and we have killed him\". A philosopher from this country declared \"a specter is haunting Europe\" in a work in which he stated, \"all history is the history of class struggles\". Two philosophers from this country collaborated to write the Communist Manifesto. Name this birthplace of Karl Marx and Friedrich Nietzsche.",
            "answers": ["Germany"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This player spent his entire 18-year career with the Pittsburgh Pirates. He was a 15-time All-Star and won 12 consecutive Gold Glove Awards for his exceptional defense in right field. In 1966, he won the National League MVP Award, and in 1971, he was named the World Series MVP. Tragically, he died in a plane crash on December 31, 1972, while delivering aid to earthquake victims in Nicaragua. Name this Hall of Famer who recorded his 3,000th and final career hit in his last at-bat of the 1972 season.",
            "answers": ["Roberto Clemente"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This conflict began with a surprise invasion across the 38th parallel on June 25, 1950. Early successes by the northern forces were reversed by the Inchon Landing, leading to the recapture of the southern capital. Chinese intervention led to a stalemate, and after three years of bloody fighting, an armistice agreement was signed in 1953, leaving this peninsula divided. Name this Cold War conflict.",
            "answers": ["Korean War", "Korea"],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Gail Halvorsen dropped candy to children in this city during an event that ended a blockade by the Soviets. Checkpoint Charlie was a highly guarded crossing point in this city, where the US helped organize a 1948 airlift. Ronald Reagan demanded that Mikhail Gorbachev \"tear down\" a structure that divided this city into East and West halves. A Cold War-era wall was located in what capital of Germany?",
            "answers": ["Berlin", "Berlin Germany"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "In May 2024, the ANC Party in this nation did not win a majority in national elections for the first time in 30 years. The current president of this nation is Cyril Ramaphosa who represents the African National Congress Party. The most spoken language in this country is Zulu, and the population is 80% Black but is home to the largest number of white people in Africa. What is this nation where the ANC won the first election after ending apartheid and chose Nelson Mandela as its president in 1994?",
            "answers": ["South Africa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Woodie Flowers co-founded a competition involving these things which encourages \"gracious professionalism\". Czech author Karl \u010capek coined the word for these things in his play R. U. R. These things \"may not injure a human being\" according to the first of three laws for them written by Isaac Asimov. What machines are exemplified by HAL 9000, Bender from Futurama, and droids in Star Wars?",
            "answers": ["robots"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The \"dark-field\" variety of a technique using these devices involves placing a condenser beneath the diaphragm. These devices may be \"finely\" or \"coarsely\" adjusted using two different-sized knobs. Rotating the eyepiece of these devices allows for different levels of magnification. Name these laboratory devices used to observe objects too small to be seen with the naked eye.",
            "answers": ["microscope"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Garlic, parsley, and salt may be mixed with this food to create its \"compound\" type, often used on steaks. To thicken sauces, this food and flour are combined in a roux. The Iowa State Fair commonly houses a cow made of this food. Ghee, commonly used in Indian cooking, is the \"clarified\" version of this food. Shaking heavy cream in a jar is one way to \"churn\" what dairy product you might spread on bread?",
            "answers": ["butter"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This scandal involved the secret leasing of federal oil reserves by the Secretary of the Interior to private oil companies in exchange for bribes. It took place during the administration of President Warren G. Harding and led to the conviction of the Secretary of the Interior, making him the first cabinet member to be imprisoned for crimes committed in office. Name this scandal named after a geological formation in Wyoming where one of the oil reserves was located. ",
            "answers": ["Teapot Dome Scandal"],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "A period of low observance of certain features on this body occurred during the Maunder Minimum and they follow an 11-year cycle. The radiative zone causes mass ejections that occur from the hottest layer of this body. The photosphere of this star forms dark areas in regions where certain \"spots\" form. NASA proposed a HelioSwarm mission to this star using nine probes. Name this closest star to Earth.",
            "answers": ["sun", "the sun"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "The town of Shush in this modern-day country lies near the ancient city of Susa, the capital of the ancient Elamite kingdom. This country's flag contains an emblem of the word \"Allah\" in calligraphy as well as the words \"God is great\" written at the borders between its red, white, and green horizontal stripes. The Strait of Hormuz lies south of what country ruled from its capital of Tehran?",
            "answers": ["Iran"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This empire, centered in northern Mesopotamia, rose to prominence in the late Bronze Age and became a major regional power during the Iron Age. Known for their advanced military tactics and brutal warfare, they established a vast empire stretching from the Persian Gulf to Egypt. Their capital, Nineveh, was a major center of culture and learning, boasting a vast library of cuneiform tablets. Name this empire that dominated the ancient Near East for centuries, with renowned rulers like Tiglath-Pileser III, Sennacherib, and Ashurbanipal.",
            "answers": ["Assyrian Empire", "Assyrian"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This player managed the Cincinnati Reds from 1984 to 1989 while also playing on the team. He is a 17-time All-Star and won three World Series rings with the Cincinnati Reds and Philadelphia Phillies. In 1985, he broke Ty Cobb's all-time hits record, finishing his career with 4,256 hits. Name this player who received a lifetime ban from baseball due to accusations of gambling on games.",
            "answers": ["Pete Rose"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This basketball player and announcer died on May 27, 2024. He won two NCAA championships at UCLA and was a three-time National College Player of the Year. He was selected first overall in the 1974 NBA draft and went on to win two NBA championships with the Portland Trail Blazers and Boston Celtics. Known for his unique personality, outspoken views, and colorful commentary, he has become a beloved figure in the basketball world. Name this Hall of Famer known for his Grateful Dead fandom and signature tie-dye attire.",
            "answers": ["Bill Walton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Instruments in this family may be tuned with pegs or fine tuners found near the bridge. Rosin is used to make friction when playing instruments in this family. F-holes are found in instruments in this family, which can be played \"pizzicato\", or plucked, but are usually played with a bow. Antonio Stradivari made instruments in this family, including basses and cellos. Violins are what kind of instrument?",
            "answers": [
                "stringed",
                "strings",
                "string instrument",
                "chordophones"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This conflict began in response to the Iraqi invasion of Kuwait in August 1990. It involved a massive U.S.-led coalition of 35 nations. The conflict consisted of two main phases: Operation Desert Shield, the buildup of troops and defense of Saudi Arabia, and a similarly named operation, a 42-day air campaign followed by a 100-hour ground offensive that liberated Kuwait. Name this conflict that took place in the Persian Gulf in 1991.",
            "answers": [
                "The Gulf War",
                "Operation Desert Storm",
                "Desert Storm",
                "Gulf War"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This musician gained fame as a member of the Yardbirds and Cream before embarking on a successful solo career. Known for his blues-inspired guitar playing and soulful vocals, he has released numerous hit albums and singles, including \"Layla,\" \"Tears in Heaven,\" and \"Wonderful Tonight.\" He is the only three-time inductee to the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame, having been honored for his work with the Yardbirds, Cream, and as a solo artist. Name this guitarist known for his signature song \"Cocaine\" and his nickname \"Slowhand.\"",
            "answers": ["Eric Clapton"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "In a story by this author, a school is built so a thief can get in, but may not get out. This author's The Sketch Book of Geoffrey Crayon features a short story where the title character falls asleep in the Catskills for 20 years. This author of \"Rip Van Winkle\" wrote about Brom Bones, who impersonates a dead Hessian soldier to scare Ichabod Crane. Name this author of \"The Legend of Sleepy Hollow.\"",
            "answers": [
                "Washington Irving",
                "Irving",
                "Diedrich Knickerbocker",
                "Geoffrey Crayon"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This footballer won the Ballon d'Or in 1998, the same year he led France to victory in the World Cup, scoring two goals in the final against Brazil. In 2001, he transferred to Real Madrid for a then-world record fee. Known for his elegant playing style and exceptional technique, he scored a memorable volley in Real Madrid's 2002 Champions League final victory. Name this midfielder who infamously headbutted Marco Materazzi in the 2006 World Cup final, his last professional match.",
            "answers": ["Zinedine Zidane", "Zidane", "Zadan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This river receives the Green River in Canyonlands National Park before flowing downstream into Lake Powell. Low water levels in Lake Mead, which this river flows through, have raised concern of a \"dead pool\" when this river will not be able to flow through Hoover Dam. This river forms the border between California and Arizona. The Grand Canyon was carved by what river named for a Rocky Mountain state?",
            "answers": ["Colorado", "Colorado River"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "At the end of 2023 this company announced a lawsuit against OpenAI for copyright infringement. In 2022, Sarah Palin lost a case against this company after it linked her to the shooting of Gabby Giffords. This newspaper won a landmark 1964 court case against L. B. Sullivan, and along with the Washington Post, Daniel Ellsberg gave this newspaper the \u201cPentagon Papers.\u201d Nicknamed \u201cThe Old Gray Lady,\u201d Name this newspaper with the motto \u201cAll the News That's Fit to Print,\u201d headquartered in Manhattan.",
            "answers": ["New York Times", "NYT"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Orbital resonance with Jupiter causes certain points called Kirkwood gaps in one region to be devoid of these objects. Some of these objects that share sections of Jupiter's orbit are called trojans. Vesta and Ceres are the largest of these objects, one of which hit Earth and caused the K-T extinction. What rocky bodies are found most commonly between Mars and Jupiter in a namesake \"belt\"?",
            "answers": ["asteroids", "asteroid", "asteroid belt"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This empire, with its capital at Constantinople, emerged as the eastern continuation of the Roman Empire after the fall of the Western Roman Empire in the 5th century. It lasted for over a thousand years, preserving and transmitting Greco-Roman culture, while also developing its own unique traditions in art, architecture, and law. Name this empire known for its iconic landmark, the Hagia Sophia, and its powerful emperors like Justinian I.",
            "answers": ["Byzantine", "Byzantine Empire"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The top quark has the highest value of any particle for this property. Particles with a positive value for this property\ninteract with the Higgs field. Photons are able to move at the speed of light because they have a\nvalue of zero for this quantity. The gravitational force between two objects is directly\nproportional to what quantity measured in kilograms?",
            "answers": ["mass"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Supreme Court case involved a defendant who was interrogated by police without being informed of his right to remain silent or his right to an attorney. The Court held that suspects in custody must be informed of these rights before questioning, and any statements made without this warning are inadmissible in court. Name this landmark 1966 case that established the requirement for police to issue a formal warning bearing the name of this case.",
            "answers": [
                "Miranda v. Arizona",
                "Miranda",
                "Miranda vs. Arizona",
                "Miranda Rights"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "To farm this crop, the ancient Igorot people terraformed Banaue in the modern-day Philippines to construct massive terraces. The cultivation of millet and this crop around 4,000 years ago was enabled by irrigation next to the Yellow River. Ancient Indians began harvesting this crop's basmati type, which grows during the monsoon. Many Asian cultures used paddies to grow what widely consumed grain?",
            "answers": ["rice"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This man was found guilty on June 11, 2024 on federal charges related to firearm possesion. This man's laptop was a major right-wing story during the 2020 election. He published a memoir titled Beautiful Things. When he was two years old, his mother and his one year old sister died in a car accident. Name this son of President Joe Biden who has struggled with drug abuse especially after the death of his older brother, Beau.",
            "answers": ["Hunter Biden", "Hunter", "Biden"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "One form of this Hindu god, Kurma, was a turtle who supported Mt. Meru during the Churning of the Ocean. This god is the chief deity of the Vaishnavist tradition. This god is often depicted resting on the serpent Anantashesha, often alongside his consort Lakshmi. The Dashvatara are the ten most famous avatars of this Hindu god. Which Hindu god known as The Preserver has avatars including Rama and Krishna?",
            "answers": ["Vishnu", "Narayana", "Hari"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team won its first NBA championship since 1975 by defeating the Cleveland Cavaliers in the 2015 NBA Finals. Led by the \"Splash Brothers\" duo of Stephen Curry and Klay Thompson, they reached five consecutive NBA Finals from 2015 to 2019, winning three championships. Their head coach, Steve Kerr, was a former NBA player who won five championships as a player with the Chicago Bulls and San Antonio Spurs. Name this team that plays its home games at the Chase Center in San Francisco.",
            "answers": ["Golden State Warriors", "Warriors"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Two artists walked across this structure to each other in a performance called The Lovers, only to break up afterwards. At the start of one movie, Shan Yu leads an attack on this structure. To deter a Hun invasion, Qin Shi Huang ordered the building of this structure. Astronauts have debated whether this man-made structure is visible from space. What defensive structure was built to protect China?",
            "answers": ["Great Wall of China", "Great Wall"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This musician co-founded a band known for their influential music and cultural impact during the 1960s. He was a prolific songwriter, penning classics like \"Help!,\" \"Strawberry Fields Forever,\" and \"Imagine.\" His partnership with Paul McCartney produced some of the most iconic songs in rock history. An outspoken advocate for peace and social justice, he and his wife Yoko Ono became symbols of the counterculture movement. Name this singer and songwriter who was tragically assassinated in 1980, ending his solo career and leaving a lasting legacy as a musical icon.",
            "answers": ["John Lennon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This person is said to have caused the \"Miracle of the Sun\" after appearing to three children in F\u00e1tima, Portugal. The prayer most commonly recited during the rosary is addressed to this figure, and calls her \"full of grace\". The doctrine of the Immaculate Conception concerns this figure, whose titles include \"Queen of Heaven\". Catholics affirm the \"perpetual virginity\" of what mother of Jesus?",
            "answers": ["Mary", "Virgin Mary", "Mary, mother of Jesus"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Points of minimal motion on \"standing\" types of these entities are called nodes. Two of these entities may undergo constructive or destructive interference. Refraction causes these entities to change direction when passing between media. These things are defined by their frequency, amplitude, and namesake \"length\". Name these oscillations which, in the ocean, will often \"break\" near the shore.",
            "answers": ["waves", "standing waves", "wavelength"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Alluvial fans are created when these geographic features transition from mountainous to flat\nterrain. Oxbows are created when parts of these features are cut off, and many of these features\nare surrounded by flat floodplains. Examples of these features that flow into larger ones are\ncalled tributaries. Name these features that carry fresh water into the oceans.",
            "answers": ["rivers", "streams", "creeks", "brooks", "rill"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "A \"revolution\" named for this color was pioneered by Nobel Peace Prize winner Norman Borlaug. In the election of 2000, Ralph Nader ran with a party named for this color. To spread a movement named for this color, Gaylord Nelson created Earth Day. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez proposed a \"New Deal\" of this color supported by Greta Thunberg. Name this color that environmental activists might tell you to \"go.\"",
            "answers": [
                "green",
                "green new deal",
                "green revolution",
                "green party",
                ""
            ],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This musician co-founded a band known for its eclectic musical style, blending elements of rock, folk, country, and blues. He was renowned for his improvisational guitar solos and distinctive vocals. His band's concerts were legendary for their extended jams and loyal fan base known as \"Deadheads.\" Name this musician who led the Grateful Dead for over three decades.",
            "answers": ["Jerry Garcia"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This nation recently elected its first female president who will also be its first Jewish president. The current president goes by his initials, AMLO, and created the Moreno Party which is represented by the newly elected Claudia Sheinbaum. This nation is one of the top two trading partners with the United States, and US companies have recently been moving more manufacturing to this country in what has been called \"friendshoring\" -- shifting production from geopolitical foes to allies. Name this North American nation.",
            "answers": ["Mexico"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Thirteen people surround one of these objects in a Salvador Dal\u00ed painting featuring a translucent human torso and arms. Tintoretto oriented one of these objects diagonally in his version of the same Biblical scene. Jesus, his apostles, and Judas sit behind one of these objects, which is covered in plates and bread, in a painting by Leonardo da Vinci. What pieces of furniture are typically included in depictions of the Last Supper?",
            "answers": ["table", "a table"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This coach led the Los Angeles Lakers to four NBA championships in the 1980s and the Miami Heat to one in 2006. Known for his slicked-back hair and Armani suits, he is credited with developing the \"Showtime\" era of Lakers basketball, emphasizing fast breaks and high-scoring games. He also coached the New York Knicks to the NBA Finals in 1994. Name this Hall of Famer who currently serves as the president of the Miami Heat.",
            "answers": ["Pat Riley"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This Louisiana native was born Stephanie A. Gregory in 1979. She was a key witness in the trial which led to the first criminal conviction of a US President. In the trial the prosecution argued that Michael Cohen paid this person $130,000 to deny she had an affair a decade earlier with Donald Trump. Name this pornstar whose affair with Donald Trump led to his conviction on 34 counts of falsifying business records.",
            "answers": ["Stormy Daniels", "Stormy", "Daniels"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This empire, located in Mesopotamia, rose to prominence under the reign of Hammurabi, who is known for his code of laws, one of the earliest surviving legal texts. It reached its peak of power in the 6th century BCE under Nebuchadnezzar II, who is credited with building the Hanging Gardens of Babylon, one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. Name this empire that conquered the Kingdom of Judah and exiled its people to Babylon.",
            "answers": [
                "Babylonian Empire",
                "Babylonian",
                "Akkadian empire",
                "Akkadian"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "The \"Six Arrows\" represent the ideology of this country's founder, who introduced the Latin alphabet to it and banned the wearing of fezzes. This country contains the largest population of Kurds in its southeast, and its first president was Mustafa Kemal Atat\u00fcrk. In 1922, the Ottoman Empire was replaced by what country which contains the transcontinental city of Istanbul?",
            "answers": ["Turkey", "Republic of Türkiye", "Türkiye"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 1999 film follows an insomniac office worker who forms an underground organization with a charismatic soap salesman named Tyler Durden. Their club evolves into an anti-establishment organization called Project Mayhem. The film is known for its twist ending revealing a shocking truth about the relationship between the narrator and Tyler Durden. Name this film directed by David Fincher and starring Edward Norton and Brad Pitt. ",
            "answers": ["Fight Club"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This composer incorporated jazz and ragtime elements into pieces like \"Ebony Concerto\" and \"Ragtime for Eleven Instruments.\" He gained international fame after collaborating with the Ballets Russes on pieces like \"The Firebird\" and \"Petrushka.\" A premiere of his ballet \"The Rite of Spring\" sparked a riot due to its dissonant music and unconventional choreography. Name this Russian composer of \"Pulcinella\" and \"The Soldier's Tale.\"",
            "answers": ["Igor Stravinsky"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Disorders of this organelle are typically maternally inherited because this organelle, along with chloroplasts, became part of the cell through endosymbiosis. This organelle's matrix is the site of the Krebs cycle. This organelle produces most of the cell's ATP through cellular respiration so it can be used to produce chemical energy. Name this organelle sometimes called the \"powerhouse of the cell.\"",
            "answers": ["mitochondria", "mitochondrion"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This coach is known for his implementation of the triangle offense and his incorporation of Zen Buddhism into his coaching philosophy. He led the Chicago Bulls to six NBA championships in the 1990s, coaching Michael Jordan and Scottie Pippen, and the Los Angeles Lakers to five championships in the 2000s, coaching Shaquille O'Neal and Kobe Bryant. Name this 11-time NBA champion coach, the most in league history. ",
            "answers": ["Phil Jackson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Supreme Court case involved multiple same-sex couples who challenged state bans on same-sex marriage. The Court held that the Fourteenth Amendment requires states to license and recognize marriages between two people of the same sex. Name this landmark 2015 case that legalized same-sex marriage nationwide.",
            "answers": ["Obergefell v. Hodges", "Obergerfell", "Hodges"],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This poet wrote about a train in the poem \"I like to see it lap the Miles\". This poet concluded another poem by declaring that \"the Horses' Heads / were toward Eternity\". This poet wrote \"How dreary \u2013 to be \u2013 Somebody!\" in a short poem that exemplified her use of dashes. Name this \"Belle of Amherst\" who wrote \"I'm Nobody! Who are you?\" and \"Because I could not stop for Death\".",
            "answers": ["Emily Dickinson", "Dickinson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Protestors found the large shoe collection of this country's first lady Imelda during the People Power Revolution. The Muslim Moro people resisted this country's colonization by the US after the Spanish-American War. The son of this country's former dictator Ferdinand Marcos succeeded Rodrigo Duterte. This country was named after a Spanish king who colonized it. What country's capital is Manila?",
            "answers": ["The Phillipines", "Phillipines"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Morgan Spurlock, the creator of this 2004 documentary film died on May 23, 2024. The film follows a filmmaker who embarks on a 30-day experiment, consuming only McDonald's food for every meal. The film documents the detrimental effects of this diet on his physical and psychological health, as well as the broader implications of the fast-food industry's marketing and influence on public health. Name this film which sparked widespread debate about the dangers of fast food and its contribution to the obesity epidemic. ",
            "answers": ["Super Size Me"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This science fiction film, directed by Stanley Kubrick and co-written with Arthur C. Clarke, follows a voyage to Jupiter after the discovery of a mysterious black monolith. It explores themes of human evolution, artificial intelligence, and extraterrestrial life. The film is known for its groundbreaking special effects, ambiguous ending, and use of classical music, including Richard Strauss's \"Also Sprach Zarathustra.\" Name this 1968 film featuring the iconic sentient computer HAL 9000.",
            "answers": ["2001: A Space Odyssey", "2001", "space odyssey"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This coach led the Boston Celtics to nine NBA championships and is known for his signature victory cigar. He drafted future Hall of Famers such as Bill Russell and Larry Bird, and is credited with breaking racial barriers by drafting Chuck Cooper, the first African American player in the NBA. Name this legendary coach and executive who is considered one of the most influential figures in NBA history.",
            "answers": ["Red Auerbach", "Red aurbach"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This constant is the only positive number for which squaring it is the same as adding 1 to it. The ratio of a regular pentagon's diagonal length to its side length is equal to this constant. The ratio of consecutive terms in the Fibonacci sequence approaches this constant. Name this value equal to about 1.618 which is often associated with natural or artistic beauty.",
            "answers": [
                "golden ratio",
                "golden number",
                "golden proportio",
                "golden mean",
                "mean of Phidias",
                "phi"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This country's flag reflects the myth that a city in it was founded where an eagle was seen eating a snake atop a cactus. A civilization from this modern day country worshipped a god that took the form of a \"feathered serpent,\" named Quetzalcoatl. At Tenochtitlan, a civilization from this country performed human sacrifice for its gods.The myths of the Aztec civilization are from what country?",
            "answers": ["Mexico"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "An activist for this non-feminist cause changed their name from Isabella Baumfree after saying \"the Spirit calls me, and I must go\". In support of this cause, the Secret Six funded a raid on Harpers Ferry led by John Brown. Harriet Beecher Stowe's novel Uncle Tom's Cabin helped drum up support for this cause. Sojourner Truth promoted what cause accomplished by the 13th Amendment and the Emancipation Proclamation?",
            "answers": [
                "abolition of slavery",
                "slavery",
                "ending slavery",
                "13th amendment",
                "13 amendment"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 1993 science fiction adventure film, directed by Steven Spielberg, follows a group of scientists and a lawyer who are invited to preview a theme park on a tropical island inhabited by genetically engineered dinosaurs. The park's security systems fail, leading to a chaotic series of events as the dinosaurs escape their enclosures. Name this film featuring iconic creatures like the Tyrannosaurus rex and Velociraptors, based on the novel by Michael Crichton.",
            "answers": ["Jurassic Park"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This player was selected second overall in the 2007 NBA draft. He won the NBA Rookie of the Year Award and was named the Most Valuable Player in 2014 while playing for the Oklahoma City Thunder. He has won two NBA championships and two Finals MVP awards with the Golden State Warriors. Name this 13-time All-Star known for his scoring ability and signature shoe line with Nike. ",
            "answers": ["Kevin Durant"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Peremptory challenges may be used to remove members of these groups. Members of these groups may be \"sequestered\" away from media to prevent outside influence. The 6th Amendment granted the right to an \"impartial\" one of these groups, which must be unanimous to convict. Indictments are delivered by \"grand\" examples of what groups of 12 people who deliver verdicts in court cases?",
            "answers": ["jury", "juries"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This language was used to write a short story collection whose name translates to \"Fictions,\" which includes the stories \"Library of Babel\" and \"The Garden of Forking Paths.\" The town of Macondo is built by members of the Buend\u00eda family in a novel in this language titled One Hundred Years of Solitude. Jorge Luis Borges and Gabriel Garc\u00eda M\u00e1rquez wrote in what language used by most Latin American writers?",
            "answers": ["spanish", "espanol"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This political scandal involved the secret sale of arms to Iran in exchange for the release of American hostages held in Lebanon. The proceeds from the arms sales were then illegally used to fund anti-communist rebels in Nicaragua, known as the Contras. It occurred during the second term of the Reagan administration and involved several high-ranking officials, including Oliver North. Name this scandal that involved covert operations and raised serious questions about the executive branch's authority in foreign policy.",
            "answers": ["Iran Contra Affair", "Iran Contra"],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This city's \u201cOrloj\u201d, the world's oldest operating astronomical clock, is mounted to its Old Town Hall. During the \u201cVelvet Revolution\u201d, many demonstrations were held in this city's Wenceslas Square. Statues of various saints line this city's historic Charles Bridge, which spans the Vltava River. Many historic defenestrations occurred in what capital of Czechia?",
            "answers": ["Prague"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This dynasty, founded by Liu Bang in 206 BCE, lasted for over four centuries and is considered a golden age in Chinese history. It saw significant advancements in art, technology, and governance, including the establishment of the Silk Road, the invention of paper, and the development of a sophisticated bureaucracy. Name this dynasty that is divided into Western and Eastern periods, with its capital initially at Chang'an and later at Luoyang.",
            "answers": ["Han Dynasty", "Han"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Levels of this molecule decrease during the \u201caustral spring\u201d when its concentration, measured in Dobson units, reaches its lowest values. The Montreal Protocol helped levels of this molecule over Antarctica rise to previous levels by banning CFCs, which caused its namesake atmospheric \"hole.\" UV radiation is absorbed by the stratosphere\u2019s \u201clayer\u201d of what molecule with chemical formula O3?",
            "answers": ["ozone", "o3", "ozone layer", "ozone hole"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "After a conflict, this city was the target of a rebellion known as the Mercenary War. This Phoenician colony was legendarily founded by the queen Dido. A general from this city encircled a much larger force to achieve a victory at Cannae. Scipio Africanus defeated this city, whose forces marched elephants across the Alps while led by Hannibal. What ancient city in North Africa lost the Punic Wars to Rome?",
            "answers": ["Carthage"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Ezra Pound wrote \"translations\" of poems from this country like \"The River-Merchant's Wife\" despite not knowing its language. A poem from this country describes \"bowing my head\" and \"frost upon the ground\". \"Drinking Alone by Moonlight\" and \"Quiet Night Thought\" are by a poet from this country. The Monkey King, Sun Wukong, appears in a novel from what country where Li Bai wrote during the Tang Dynasty?",
            "answers": [
                "China",
                "PRC",
                "Zhongguo",
                "Zhonghua Renmin\nGongheguo"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Bruhat Soma won this competition in a lightning-round tiebreaker in May 2024. This annual event began in 1925 with nine contestants and has since grown to include millions of participants from across the United States and several other countries. It is open to students who have not passed the eighth grade and have not reached their 15th birthday. Name this prestigious competition hosted in Washington, D.C. that is known for its challenging words and impressive displays of spelling prowess.",
            "answers": ["Scripps Spelling Bee"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Disney animated film, initially titled \"King of the Jungle,\" was considered a \"B-project\" while the studio focused on \"Pocahontas.\" It features a voice cast that includes Matthew Broderick, James Earl Jones, and Jeremy Irons, who temporarily lost his voice while recording \"Be Prepared.\" Its iconic soundtrack, composed by Elton John and Tim Rice, includes songs like \"Circle of Life,\" \"Hakuna Matata,\" and \"Can You Feel the Love Tonight,\" which was almost cut from the film. Name this 1994 highest-grossing hand-drawn animated feature of all time.",
            "answers": ["The Lion King", "Lion King"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Supreme Court case arose from a dispute over the appointment of a justice of the peace in the District of Columbia. The Court ruled that a provision of the Judiciary Act of 1789, which granted the Court the authority to issue certain writs, was unconstitutional. This decision established the principle of judicial review, the power of the Court to declare acts of Congress unconstitutional. Name this landmark 1803 case that solidified the Supreme Court's role in the system of checks and balances.",
            "answers": ["Marbury v. Madison", "Marbury", "Madison"],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "A nine-point one of these shapes can be drawn to pass through the midpoints of its given triangle's sides. Right triangles are usually drawn inside one of these shapes in the Cartesian plane to explain the calculation of trig functions. A line between two points on one of these shapes is called a chord. Name these shapes whose circumference is equal to pi times their diameter.",
            "answers": ["circle"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team relocated to Nashville in 1997 after playing in Houston as the Oilers since 1960. They reached Super Bowl XXXIV in 2000 but lost to the St. Louis Rams by one yard in the final seconds. Their star running back, Derrick Henry, has won two NFL rushing titles and was named the NFL Offensive Player of the Year in 2020. Name this team that plays its home games at Nissan Stadium.",
            "answers": ["Tennessee Titans", "Titans"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This city, located on the island of Honshu, is the most populous metropolitan area in the world. Situated at the head of a bay sharing its name, it is a major economic and cultural center, home to iconic landmarks such as the Imperial Palace. Name this city, formerly known as Edo, that was devastated by the Great Kant\u014d earthquake in 1923 but has since been rebuilt into a modern metropolis.",
            "answers": ["Tokyo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This 1991 psychological thriller follows a young FBI trainee who enlists the help of an incarcerated and manipulative cannibalistic serial killer to catch another serial killer, known as \"Buffalo Bill,\" who skins his victims. The film features iconic performances by Jodie Foster as Clarice Starling and Anthony Hopkins as Hannibal Lecter, and won five Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Adapted Screenplay. Name this film based on the novel by Thomas Harris.",
            "answers": ["Silence of the Lambs", "The Silence of the Lambs"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "John Cage added screws to make a \"prepared\" form of this instrument, which is silent for four minutes and 33 seconds in another Cage piece. Scott Joplin's Maple Leaf Rag is played on this instrument. Thelonious Monk and Duke Ellington were famous jazz players of this instrument. \"Tickling the ivories\" refers to playing what instrument with 88 black and white keys?",
            "answers": ["piano", "pianoforte"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Supreme Court case involved challenges to state laws establishing racial segregation in public schools. The Court held that such segregation violated the Equal Protection Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment, declaring that \"separate educational facilities are inherently unequal.\" Name this landmark 1954 case that overturned the \"separate but equal\" doctrine established in Plessy v. Ferguson and paved the way for desegregation in the United States.",
            "answers": [
                "Brown v. Board of Education",
                "Brown vs board",
                "Brown"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "GUIs in this programming language can be developed using the Swing API. This language developed by Sun Microsystems has the slogan \"Write Once, Run Anywhere\", advertising its namesake \"virtual machine\". Much of the original codebase of Minecraft was written in this programming language. Name this popular object-oriented programming language whose symbol is a cup of coffee.",
            "answers": ["Java"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This battle's name was applied to an 1819 massacre against government reform protestors in Manchester. Borders were resolved using terms set at the Congress of Vienna after this battle, at which Prussian forces under von Blucher fought alongside the Duke of Wellington. When this battle's loser was exiled to St. Helena, the French monarchy was restored. What 1815 battle was Napoleon's final defeat?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Waterloo", "Waterloo"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This fighter defeated Trevor Berbick in 1986 to become the youngest heavyweight champion in history at the age of 20. Known for his ferocious punching power and intimidating presence, he won his first 19 professional fights by knockout. In 1992, he was convicted of rape and served three years in prison. After his release, he regained the heavyweight title but lost it to Evander Holyfield in 1996. In a rematch the following year, he was disqualified for biting Holyfield's ear. Name this boxer nicknamed \"Iron Mike.\"",
            "answers": ["Mike Tyson"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "A bend in this river created an exclave of Fulton County named for the town of New Madrid. The cities of Natchez and Vicksburg are located on the banks of this river. Part of this river's flow drains to the ocean through the Atchafalaya, and this river joins the Ohio River at Cairo, Illinois. St. Louis is located on the west bank of what river which flows through New Orleans into the Gulf of Mexico?",
            "answers": ["Mississippi River", "Mississippi"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This mans interpreter, Ippei Mizuhara, plead guilty to bank fraud and tax evasion related to illegal gambling debts. This player made his MLB debut with the Los Angeles Angels in 2018, becoming the first player since Babe Ruth to both pitch and hit regularly in the major leagues. He won the American League Rookie of the Year Award in 2018 and was named the American League Most Valuable Player in 2021. In 2023, he became the first player in MLB history to win a home run title and record ten pitching wins in the same season. Name this two-way Japanese superstar known for his exceptional talent as both a pitcher and a designated hitter.",
            "answers": ["Shohei Ohtani"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "The Ten Days of Repentance are observed immediately following this holiday. Righteous people's names are recorded in the Book of Life on this holiday. During this holiday, people eat apples dipped in honey and may use the greeting \"shanah tovah\", which means \"good year\". The first day of Tishrei and the first of the Jewish High Holy Days is what holiday that celebrates the Jewish New Year?",
            "answers": ["Rosh Hashanah", "Yom Teruah"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This country is home to the \"Catatumbo lightning\", an intense localized thunderstorm that occurs for hours a day almost half the days of the year. This country's \"tepui\", or flat-topped \"table mountains\", inspired the South American landscape in the Pixar movie Up. The world's highest uninterrupted waterfall, Angel Falls, is located in what South American country led from Caracas?",
            "answers": ["Venezuela"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This region is described by the Three Cell Model, where it is divided into Hadley, Ferrel, and polar cells. The planetary boundary layer is the lowest part of this region of the atmosphere. The\ntop of this region contains jet streams. This region is where most of Earth's weather occurs. Name this layer of the atmosphere that lies below the stratosphere.",
            "answers": ["troposphere"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team relocated to Los Angeles in 2016 after playing in St. Louis since 1995. They won Super Bowl LVI in 2022, defeating the Cincinnati Bengals at their home stadium, SoFi Stadium. Their star defensive tackle, Aaron Donald, is a three-time NFL Defensive Player of the Year and a Super Bowl champion. Sean McVay, their head coach, is the youngest head coach in NFL history to lead a team to the Super Bowl. Name this team that shares SoFi Stadium with the Los Angeles Chargers. ",
            "answers": ["L.A. Rams", "Rams", "LA Rams", "Los Angeles Rams"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "The blood from the right half of this figure was said to bring the dead back to life. Stheno and Euryale were siblings of this child of Ceto, who gave birth to Chrysaor upon her death. A body part of this figure was placed upon the Aegis shield by Athena. This figure was transformed into a monster after Poseidon assaulted her at a temple to Athena, and was slain by Perseus. Identify this gorgon whose gaze petrified men.",
            "answers": ["Medusa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Zero Moustafa inherits one of these places in a Wes Anderson film set in Zubrowka. The caretaker of one of these places writes \"All work and no play makes Jack a dull boy\" hundreds of times in the film The Shining. A group of British pensioners move to India in a film titled for \"The Best Exotic Marigold\" one of what kind of place where Kevin spends hundreds of dollars on room service in Home Alone 2?",
            "answers": ["hotel", "hotels"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This tennis player lost his first match before the fourth round of the French Open when he lost to Alexander Zverev in the first round in 2024. He won his first French Open title in 2005 at the age of 19, becoming the second-youngest man to win a Grand Slam singles title. He is known for his powerful left-handed forehand, exceptional athleticism, and relentless fighting spirit. He has won a record 14 French Open titles, earning him the nickname \"King of Clay.\" Name this Spanish tennis player who has also won four US Open titles, two Wimbledon titles, and one Australian Open title, for a total of 22 Grand Slam singles titles.",
            "answers": ["Rafael Nadal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "One event in this city occurred on King Street and resulted in Thomas Preston's trial and the death of Crispus Attucks. The Old North Church in this city was the site of the \"one if by land, two if by sea\" command to Paul Revere. The Sons of Liberty threw goods into this city\u2019s harbor in one event. The Battle of Bunker Hill took place in what city, where tea was destroyed in a namesake 1773 \u201cTea Party\u201d?",
            "answers": ["Boston", "Boston Massachussetts"],
            "used": "TRUE",
            "source": ""
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This figure skater became the first American woman and the second woman to land a triple axel in competition. She won the U.S. Figure Skating Championships in 1991 and 1994, but her career was overshadowed by her association with the attack on fellow skater Nancy Kerrigan in 1994. She pleaded guilty to hindering prosecution and was banned for life from the U.S. Figure Skating Association. Name this controversial figure skater portrayed by Margot Robbie in a 2017 film.",
            "answers": ["Tonya Harding"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Paul Robeson played the title character of this play in its longest-running New York theatre production. The main character of this play is convinced by a handkerchief that his wife is cheating on him. In this play, Emilia is killed for exposing the treachery of her husband Iago. Desdemona is smothered with a pillow in what Shakespeare play about a \"Moor of Venice\"?",
            "answers": ["Othello"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "One of this leader's speeches discusses a \"frightful despotism\" and forbids \"entangling\nalliances.\" The Newburgh Conspiracy and the Conway Cabal were plots to replace this leader with\nHoratio Gates after this leader's losses at Germantown and Brandywine. After issuing his\nfarewell address warning against political parties, this leader retired to Mount Vernon. Name this President of the United States.",
            "answers": ["George Washington"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This neo-noir mystery film follows an aspiring actress named Betty, who befriends an amnesiac woman named Rita after she survives a car crash. As they try to uncover Rita's identity, they become entangled in a web of dreams, illusions, and Hollywood conspiracies. This film is known for its surreal imagery, non-linear narrative, and ambiguous ending, leaving much open to interpretation. Name this 2001 film directed by David Lynch, named after a famous Los Angeles road that is often cited as one of the greatest films of the 21st century.",
            "answers": ["Mulholland Drive", "Mullholland Dr"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This city was home to the Francis Scott Key Bridge which collapsed on March 26, 2024 after a cargo ship named Dali collided with the bridge. The city, located on the Patapsco River in Maryland, was a major shipbuilding center during World War II and is home to Fort McHenry, where \"The Star-Spangled Banner\" was written during the War of 1812. It is also known for its distinct neighborhoods, such as Fells Point and Federal Hill, and its unique culinary traditions, including a famous crab cake. Name this city, nicknamed \"Charm City,\" that is the largest city in Maryland.",
            "answers": ["Baltimore"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Juan Sebastian Elcano continued one of this explorer's expeditions after they were killed by forces under Lapu-Lapu at the Battle of Mactan. This explorer's voyage to the Spice Islands made them the first to discover a strait south of South America, which was later named for them. Name this Portuguese explorer who died while attempting the first circumnavigation of the earth.",
            "answers": ["Ferdinand Magellan", "Magellan"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "An airport in this city is nicknamed \"The Busiest Square Mile on Earth\". The South Shore Line is a commuter train connecting this city to South Bend. The codes MDW and ORD are used for airports in this city. This city's elevated trains, nicknamed the \"El\", converge in a downtown area named the Loop. Midway Airport and O'Hare Airport serve what most populous city in Illinois?",
            "answers": ["Chicago"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Orbital resonance with Jupiter causes certain points called Kirkwood gaps in one region to be devoid of these objects. Some of these objects that share sections of Jupiter's orbit are called trojans. Vesta and Ceres are the largest of these objects, one of which hit Earth and caused the K-T extinction. What rocky bodies are found most commonly between Mars and Jupiter in a namesake \"belt\"?",
            "answers": ["asteroids", "asteroid"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Al Smith's adherence to this faith may have caused his election loss to Herbert Hoover. Prejudice against Italian immigrants to America was partially driven by their adherence to this faith, along with Irish-American immigrants such as the Kennedys. In 2020, Joe Biden became the second president in American history to be a member of what \"Roman\" Christian denomination?",
            "answers": ["Roman Catholic", "Catholic", "Catholicism"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "In early June, this news organization's executive editor abruptly resigned after disagreements with the organization's CEO, Will Lewis. This newspaper, founded in 1877, gained national prominence for its investigative reporting during the Watergate scandal in the early 1970s. Reporters Bob Woodward and Carl Bernstein played a crucial role in uncovering the Nixon administration's involvement in the break-in at the Democratic National Committee headquarters. Name this newspaper, owned by Jeff Bezos which is headquartered in Washington D.C.",
            "answers": ["The Washington Post", "Washington Post"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "The KGB may have killed a leader of this group, Dag Hammarskj\u00f6ld, in a plane crash over present-day Zambia. An \"educational, scientific, and cultural organization\" within this group recognizes world heritage sites. This group's Security Council gives unilateral vetoes to five permanent members, including Russia. What international organization headquartered in New York has 193 member states?",
            "answers": ["United Nations", "UN", "U.N."],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This scientist discovered that the plane of polarization for linearly polarized light can be rotated using an external magnetic field. This scientist's law of induction describes how a magnetic field can produce an electromotive force. This scientist used an ice pail to demonstrate electromagnetic shielding in his namesake cage. Name this English physicist who lends his name to the SI unit of capacitance.",
            "answers": ["Michael Faraday", "Faraday"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This quarterback, nicknamed \"Joe Cool\" for his calm demeanor under pressure, led the San Francisco 49ers to four Super Bowl victories in the 1980s. He is renowned for engineering numerous come-from-behind victories, including \"The Catch,\" a last-minute touchdown pass to Dwight Clark in the 1981 NFC Championship Game against the Dallas Cowboys. Name this three-time Super Bowl MVP who is considered one of the greatest quarterbacks in NFL history.",
            "answers": ["Joe Montana"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Women in this country may wear a bathrobe-like summer dress known as a yukata. A silk dress from this country is held together by a belt called an obi and may feature designs of Sakura, or cherry blossoms. Ladies-in-waiting like Lady Murasaki during the Heian period were some of the first to wear kimonos in what country, where they're worn by women living in Tokyo?",
            "answers": ["Japan", "Nippon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "John Grimes' upbringing in this city is the subject of James Baldwin's novel Go Tell It On the\nMountain. A musician plays piano in this city in the poem \"The Weary Blues.\" An author from this\ncity asked \"What happens to a dream deferred?\" in a poem titled for a Black majority\nneighborhood in it. Langston Hughes was part of the Harlem Renaissance centered in\nwhat American city?",
            "answers": [
                "New York City",
                "NYC",
                "New York",
                "New York New York",
                "Harlem",
                "Harlem New York"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This artist, born David Robert Jones, adopted his stage name to avoid confusion with Davy Jones of The Monkees. Known for his flamboyant alter egos, including the Thin White Duke, he constantly reinvented his image and sound throughout his career. His music spanned genres like glam rock, art rock, soul, and electronica, with iconic albums like \"The Rise and Fall of Ziggy Stardust and the Spiders from Mars,\" \"Heroes,\" and \"Let's Dance.\" Name this legendary British musician known for his distinctive voice and theatrical performances.",
            "answers": ["David Bowie"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "At least 14 Jordanian citizens have died in 2024 during this event due to intense heat. A practice similar to this one, but which can take place at any time of year, is Umrah.\nParticipants in this practice throw stones at a wall in a ritual \"Stoning of the Devil\" and reenact\nHajar's search for water by running between two hills. Participants in this event walk seven times\naround the Kaaba at the center of the Masjid al-Haram. The Fifth Pillar of Islam is\nwhat pilgrimage to Mecca?",
            "answers": ["Hajj", "pilgrimage", "Mecca", "pilgrimage to Mecca"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This leader won the Nobel Prize in Literature for A History of the English-Speaking Peoples. This politician was demoted after the Gallipolli campaign during World War I. The \"Blood, Sweat, and Tears\" speech was given by this man, who succeeded Neville Chamberlain and declared \"We shall never surrender\" during a war where London was bombed. Name this prime minister who led Britain through World War II.",
            "answers": ["Winson Churchill", "Churchill"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "A faction opposed to this ideology was led by Patrick Henry. This ideology names a series of texts published under the name \"Publius\" to promote the Constitution, as well as a party that supported the first national bank, a strong central government, and opposed the Democratic-Republicans. Alexander Hamilton wrote most of the \"Papers\" named for what ideology that names an early American political party?",
            "answers": ["Federalist", "Federalist Papers", "Federalism"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This element is purified by reducing its oxide in molten cryolite in the Hall-H\u00e9roult process.\nThe Bayer process is used to obtain this element from its ore. It's not chromium, but a\ncharacteristic red color is formed when oxygen and this element form rubies. Bauxite is this\nelement's most common ore. Identify this thirteenth element often used to make foil,\nwith atomic symbol Al.",
            "answers": ["aluminum", "al"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This coach, born in 1913 and known for his houndstooth hat, is considered one of the greatest college football coaches of all time. He led the University of Alabama to six national championships and 13 Southeastern Conference (SEC) titles during his 25-year tenure as head coach. Name this legendary coach whose statue stands outside Bryant-Denny Stadium in Tuscaloosa, Alabama.",
            "answers": ["Bear Bryant", "Bryant"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This country considered giving the mountain Halti to a neighbor to celebrate that neighbor's 100th birthday. This country's capital was named Christiania until merging with another village in 1925. A museum in this country is dedicated to painter Edvard Munch. This country's west coast, on the Atlantic ocean, is famous for its fjords. Name this Scandinavian country whose capital city is Oslo",
            "answers": ["Norway", "Kongeriket Norge"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This modern-day country was the center of an ancient culture which practiced the black-figure and red-figure styles of painting on pottery. The Elgin Marbles were taken from a building in this country. The sculpture Winged Victory from this country represents the goddess Nike. Praxiteles, a sculptor from this country, created a sculpture of the god Hermes. What country is home to the Parthenon?",
            "answers": ["Greece", "Hellas"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This film, featuring memorable scenes of beach volleyball and shirtless pilots, became the highest-grossing film of 1986. Its soundtrack, including Kenny Loggins' \"Danger Zone,\" topped the Billboard charts. The film's iconic motorcycle scene, with Tom Cruise sporting aviator sunglasses and a leather jacket, has been referenced and parodied numerous times in popular culture. Name this film about fighter pilots starring Tom Cruise as Pete \"Maverick\" Mitchell.",
            "answers": ["Top Gun"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "An event involving this activist occurred nine months after a similar one involving 15-year-old\nClaudette Colvin. After one action taken by this activist, carpools and taxis were organized to\nprotest the National City Lines company. A year-long public transit boycott in Montgomery,\nAlabama, was sparked by the arrest of what civil rights activist who refused to give up\nher bus seat to a white person?",
            "answers": ["Rosa Parks"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "The word \"algebra\" comes from a word in this language meaning \"computation\". Maltese is descended from a historic dialect of this language. This is the most-spoken language whose writing system conventionally omits vowels and is written from right to left. The most-spoken Semitic language is what language whose \u201cclassical\u201d form is used in the Qur\u2019an and is also spoken in cities like Cairo and Dubai?",
            "answers": ["Arabic", "al'arabbiyah"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This nation's hockey team, comprised of veteran professional players who had dominated international hockey for years, entered the 1980 Winter Olympics in Lake Placid as heavy favorites. They had won the gold medal in four of the previous five Winter Olympic Games and had recently defeated the young and inexperienced U.S. team 10-3 in an exhibition match. In a shocking upset, the U.S. team defeated this team 4-3 in a medal-round game, which became known as the \"Miracle on Ice.\" Against which country did the United States achieve this iconic victory?",
            "answers": [
                "Soviet Union",
                "USSR",
                "U.S.S.R.The Soviet Union (miracle)"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "In a novel from this country, a \"yellow bakkie\" is owned by a servant of Maureen and Bamford.\nArthur Jarvis is murdered by Absalom, the son of Stephen Kumalo, in a novel from this country.\nThe novel July's People was written by this country's author Nadine Gordimer. Alan Paton wrote\nCry, the Beloved Country in what country where many authors wrote about apartheid?",
            "answers": ["South Africa", "RSA", "Republic of South Africa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This holiday was celebrated on Monday, June 17, 2024. It is an Islamic holiday, also known as the \"Feast of Sacrifice\", and it commemorates Ibrahim's (Abraham's) willingness to sacrifice his son as an act of obedience to God. It is celebrated on the 10th day of Dhu al-Hijjah, the twelfth and final month of the Islamic lunar calendar, and typically lasts for four days. Name this important Islamic festival that follows the annual Hajj pilgrimage.",
            "answers": ["Eid al-Adha", "Eid-ul-Adha", "Bakrid", "Eid"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This revolutionary became a symbol of socialist revolution after his execution in Bolivia in 1967. He played a key role in the Cuban Revolution, serving as a guerrilla leader alongside Fidel Castro. He later held positions in the new Cuban government, including Minister of Industries. His iconic portrait, taken by Alberto Korda, has become one of the most reproduced images in the world. Name this Marxist revolutionary born in Argentina. ",
            "answers": ["Che Guevara"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The Late Heavy Bombardment was a period of intense meteorite impacts on this planet. Banded\niron formations provide evidence for a \"great oxygenation event\" on this planet. A mass extinction\ncalled the Great Dying occurred at the end of this planet's Permian period. The Cambrian\nexplosion saw a rapid emergence of life on what 4.5 billion year old planet?",
            "answers": ["Earth"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This band, originally named On a Friday, formed in Abingdon, Oxfordshire, England in 1985. They achieved critical acclaim and commercial success with their third album, OK Computer, which is often cited as one of the greatest albums of all time. Their musical style has evolved throughout their career, incorporating elements of alternative rock, electronica, and experimental music. Name this band known for songs like \"Creep,\" \"Karma Police,\" and \"Paranoid Android,\" fronted by Thom Yorke.",
            "answers": ["Radiohead", "radio head"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This competitor was recently banned from Nathan's Hot Dog Eating Contest on Coney Island due to a sponsorship conflict. Historically, he has dominated the contest, winning a record 16 titles. In 2021, he set a new world record by consuming 76 hot dogs and buns in 10 minutes. He also holds numerous other eating records in various disciplines, including chicken wings, pizza, and Twinkies. Name this competitive eating legend who has become synonymous with the Fourth of July hot dog eating tradition.",
            "answers": ["Joey Chestnut"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This politician served as a Continental Army officer during the American Revolution and later became a successful lawyer in New York. He served as a U.S. Senator from New York and narrowly lost the presidential election of 1800 to Thomas Jefferson, resulting in him becoming Vice President. He killed his political rival, Alexander Hamilton, in a duel in 1804, and was later tried for treason in 1807 for his alleged conspiracy to create an independent nation in the Western territories. Name this controversial figure in early American history.",
            "answers": ["Aaron Burr"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "The story of the Pied Piper originated in this country. In a story from this country, a wife convinces her husband to abandon his children in the forest, and later in that story a girl pushes an old woman into an oven. In another story from this country, the name of a man who spins straw into gold is revealed to be Rumpelstiltskin. Name this country of Brothers Grimm stories such as \u201cHansel and Gretel.\u201d",
            "answers": ["Germany"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This South Korean dark comedy thriller film follows a poor family, the Kims, who scheme their way into working for a wealthy family, the Parks. The film explores themes of social class, inequality, and the parasitic relationships that can develop between those of different socioeconomic statuses. Name this 2019 film directed by Bong Joon-ho, which won four Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, Best Original Screenplay, and Best International Feature Film, making history as the first non-English language film to win Best Picture.",
            "answers": ["Parasite"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Early on in this conflict, the defensive \"Maginot Line\" completely failed to deter an invasion. In\nthis conflict, the slogan \"Work, Family, Fatherland\" was adopted by a regime led by former war\nhero Philippe P\u00e9tain. In this conflict, a French regime based in the city of Vichy was\nresisted by the \"Free French\". Name this conflict during which France was led by a Nazi\npuppet government.",
            "answers": ["World War II", "WWII", "Second World War"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "One sports team based in this city are nicknamed the \"Toffees\" and play at Goodison Park. A\nteam named for this city came back from a 3-0 deficit to win the Champions League in the\n\"Miracle of Istanbul\". The song \"You'll Never Walk Alone\" is associated with a team in this city,\nwhich plays against Everton in the Merseyside Derby. Name this city whose\nnamesake club is a longtime rival of Manchester United.",
            "answers": ["Liverpool"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Buddy Holly died in a plane crash near this state's Mason City. This state's highest point is located on a farm near the town of Sibley and is called Hawkeye Point. This state's exclave of Carter Lake lies on the west bank of the Missouri River on its border with Nebraska. Illinois shares the \"Quad Cities\" with what Midwestern state, the southern neighbor of Minnesota, whose capital is Des Moines?",
            "answers": ["Iowa"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This anatomical system can be affected by Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease, and the Nodes of\nRanvier are found between Schwann cells, a type of glial cell, in this system. Multiple sclerosis\nattacks the myelin sheath of cells in this system, and synaptic clefts are crossed by molecules like\nacetylcholine and adrenaline to carry impulses throughout it. Neurons are found in\nwhat system which includes the brain?",
            "answers": ["nervous system", "nervous"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This neo-noir science fiction film, set in a dystopian Los Angeles in 2019, follows Rick Deckard who is tasked with hunting down and \"retiring\" four escaped replicants, bioengineered beings indistinguishable from humans. The film is known for its distinctive visuals, philosophical themes about artificial intelligence and what it means to be human, and iconic quotes like \"All those moments will be lost in time, like tears in rain.\" Name this 1982 film directed by Ridley Scott and based on the novel Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep? by Philip K. Dick.",
            "answers": ["Blade Runner"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "In the largest democratic election in history, this man was reelected to a third consecutive term as prime minister. This man will lead a coaltion government for the first time as his party, the Bharatiya Janata Party, did not win an absolute majority of seats. Although his BJP did not win a majority of seats, their alliance known as the National Democratic Alliance won 293 out of the 543 seats. Name this 14th prime minister of India who was born in 1950.",
            "answers": ["Narendra Modi", "Modi"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This player, known for his defensive prowess and intensity, was involved in one of the most infamous incidents in NBA history, the \"Malice at the Palace\" brawl in 2004. He won the NBA Defensive Player of the Year Award in 2004 and was a key member of the Los Angeles Lakers championship team in 2010. Name this player, who legally changed his name to Metta World Peace in 2011.",
            "answers": ["Ron Artest", "Metta World Peace", "Artest"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This country's Queen Christina abdicated to live with the Pope. In the Thirty\nYears' War, this country's king was nicknamed \"Lion of the North.\" A chemist from this country\nwas nicknamed the \"merchant of death\" for inventing dynamite. Russia's Peter the Great won the\nGreat Northern War against this country, which was home to Alfred Nobel. Name\nthis country led from Stockholm.",
            "answers": ["Sweden", "Sverige"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The first confirmed discovery of one type of these objects looked at variations in pulsar timing. The Kepler satellite uses transits to look for these objects outside the Solar System. Astronomers are looking for these objects in the \"habitable zone\" as possible sites of extraterrestrial life. Gas giants are one kind of what objects which orbit stars, such as Venus and the Earth?",
            "answers": ["planets", "exoplanet"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This conflict, ended by the Treaty of Ghent, resulted in no significant territorial changes for either side. One of its key battles, the Battle of New Orleans, was a decisive American victory led by Andrew Jackson, yet it occurred after the peace treaty had been signed. Other notable events include the burning of Washington D.C. and the British bombardment of Fort McHenry, which inspired Francis Scott Key to write \"The Star-Spangled Banner.\" Name this war fought between the United States and Great Britain from 1812 to 1815.",
            "answers": ["War of 1812"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "A sports team was named for these animals to honor an author who died in that team's city. The narrator of one poem says that one of these animals \"will leave me, as my Hopes have flown before\". In that poem, this animal is told to \"get thee back\" to \"the Night's Plutonian shore!\". This animal sits on a bust of Pallas after \"rapping at my chamber door\". What bird repeats the word \"nevermore\"?",
            "answers": ["a raven", "ravens baltimore ravens"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "The U.S. Army blasted heavy metal to lure this country's leader Manuel Noriega out of hiding in Operation Just Cause. Walter Reed's research on yellow fever aided in the completion of a project that began after this country's independence from Colombia. That project, overseen by Theodore Roosevelt, improved Pacific-Atlantic ship travel. What Central American country's isthmus is home to a namesake canal?",
            "answers": ["Panama", "Panama Canal"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This businessman had a pay package worth over $45 billion in stock options approved by shareholders after a Deleware judge initially struck the package down. He also recently dropped a lawsuit against OpenAI, where he was a cofounder, in which he claimed the company had breached its pledge to remain a nonprofit company. Name this entrepenuer who took Twitter private and acts of the CEO of Tesla and SpaceX.",
            "answers": ["Elon Musk"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "In 1889, this state was devastated by a flood in Johnstown. Labor leaders staged the Homestead\nStrike in this state. The working-class \"Yinz\" in one of this state's cities were employed by Andrew\nCarnegie's company, making it the center of the steel industry. To this day, nobody knows how a\ncrack formed on the bell in this state's Independence Hall. Name this state home to\nPhiladelphia.",
            "answers": ["Pennsylvania"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "A stickler for fundamentals and discipline, this coach is often quoted for saying, \"Winning isn't everything, it's the only thing.\" This coach led the Green Bay Packers to five NFL championships in seven years, including the first two Super Bowls. His name now graces the Super Bowl trophy. Name this legendary coach whose name is synonymous with excellence and leadership in the world of sports.",
            "answers": ["Vince Lombardi", "Lombardi"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This city, which lost to the forces of Epaminondas at the Battle of Leuctra against Thebes, was home to slaves called helots. Lysander won the Battle of Aegospotami for this city to end a war against the Delian League. This city's King Leonidas led 300 men in a last stand at the battle of Thermopylae. Name this militaristic Greek city-state that won the Peloponnesian War against Athens.",
            "answers": ["Sparta", "Lacedaemon"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British comedy-drama series follows a dry-witted and unnamed woman as she navigates life in London while dealing with grief, family dysfunction, and complicated relationships. The show is known for breaking the fourth wall, with the main character frequently addressing the audience directly. Created by and starring Phoebe Waller-Bridge, it is based on her 2013 one-woman show of the same name. Name this critically acclaimed series that won multiple Emmy Awards, including Outstanding Comedy Series and Outstanding Lead Actress in a Comedy Series.",
            "answers": ["Fleabag"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "It's not the NGA's sculpture garden, but Louise Bourgeois created a bronze spider for one of these places. Frank Gehry designed one of these buildings in Bilbao, Spain. Frank Lloyd Wright designed a spiral-shaped ramp for another of these museums, which is located on Fifth Avenue in New York City. Name these art museums founded by a philanthropist with the first name Solomon.",
            "answers": [
                "Guggenheim",
                "Guggenheim Museums",
                "Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum"
            ],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Kupffer cells produce bilirubin in this organ from the breakdown of certain cells. This organ is primarily responsible for storing glucose as glycogen in humans. Deoxygenated blood is carried from the spleen to this organ by the portal vein. Bile is produced by this organ and then transported to the gallbladder for storage. Alcohol abuse harms what largest internal organ in humans?",
            "answers": ["liver"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "The governance of this country's indigenous Haida people is based on a traditional gift-giving\nceremony called the potlatch. James Evans developed a syllabic alphabet in this country which is\nnow used for languages such as Cree and Inuktitut, the most-spoken language among its Inuit\npeople. The \"First Nations\" are the indigenous people of what country where the\nSquamish people lived in British Columbia?",
            "answers": ["Canada"],
            "used": "TRUE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This company briefly surpassed Apple as the most valuable public company in the world. The company, founded in 1993, initially focused on developing graphics processing units (GPUs) for the gaming market. However, it has since expanded its reach to include artificial intelligence, data centers, and autonomous vehicles. Its GPUs are now widely used in various fields, including scientific research, machine learning, and cryptocurrency mining. Name this company, headquartered in Santa Clara, California, known for its GeForce series of GPUs.",
            "answers": ["NVIDIA"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "In one contest, this figure asks Vafthruthnir about what he whispered in the ear of his son. This deity hung himself from Yggdrasil for nine days in order to learn about runes, and he uses the ravens Huginn and Muninn as messengers. This owner of the horse Sleipnir drank from the Well of Mimir in exchange for his eye. Identify this Norse \"All Father,\" the ruler of the gods, and father of Thor.",
            "answers": ["Odin"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This infamous criminal gained notoriety during the Great Depression era for his daring bank robberies and multiple prison escapes. He was declared \"Public Enemy No. 1\" by the FBI and became a folk hero to some who admired his defiance of authority and his Robin Hood-like image. He was ultimately killed in a shootout with federal agents outside the Biograph Theater in Chicago in 1934. Name this notorious gangster whose exploits captivated the nation and solidified his place in American criminal lore.",
            "answers": ["John Dillinger", "Dilinger"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team, one of the original NBA franchises, has a long and storied history, including a remarkable run of eight consecutive championships from 1959 to 1966 under legendary coach Red Auerbach. Led by Hall of Famers such as Bill Russell, Bob Cousy, and John Havlicek, they established themselves as a dominant force in the league. More recently, they reached the NBA Finals in 2022 and ultimately secured their 18th championship in 2024, led by Jayson Tatum and Jaylen Brown. Name this team that holds the record for the most NBA championships.",
            "answers": ["Boston Celtics", "Celtics"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This object was described as a \"small cloud\" by Persian astronomer Abd al-Rahman al-Sufi in 964. It takes its name from the constellation in which it appears, which is named for the mythological wife of Perseus. This object is predicted to collide with the Milky Way in about five billion years. Name this member of the Local Group, the closest spiral galaxy to the Milky Way.",
            "answers": ["Andromeda", "andromena", " Andromeda galaxy"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Gordon Sumner, known professionally by this stage name, rose to fame as the frontman, bassist, and principal songwriter of the new wave rock band The Police. After the band's breakup in 1986, he embarked on a successful solo career. He is known for his distinctive voice, socially conscious lyrics, and hits like \"Every Breath You Take,\" \"Englishman in New York,\" and \"Fields of Gold.\" Name this English musician who has sold over 100 million records worldwide.",
            "answers": ["Sting"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This heir presumptive to the Austro-Hungarian throne was assassinated in Sarajevo in June 1914. His death, at the hands of Gavrilo Princip, a Serbian nationalist, sparked a chain of events that led to the outbreak of World War I. Name this archduke whose assassination is considered a key catalyst for one of the deadliest conflicts in human history.",
            "answers": ["Franz Ferdinand"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This island nation, located in the Persian Gulf, is an archipelago consisting of 50 natural islands and an additional 33 artificial islands. It is connected to Saudi Arabia by the King Fahd Causeway, a 25-kilometer bridge, and is separated by a small section of a Persian Gulf from Qatar. This country is the third-smallest nation in Asia by area and is home an international circuit, which hosts an annual Formula One race. Name this country with its capital at Manama.",
            "answers": ["Bahrain"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This country's capital city was designed in the shape of an airplane around a \"Monumental Axis\" by architect Oscar Niemeyer. \"Cariocas\" are residents of this country's second most populous city, which was the origin of bossa nova music and hosts massive parades in the Sambodrome during Carnaval. Name this Portuguese-speaking country in South America which contains most of the Amazon rainforest.",
            "answers": ["Brazil"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NHL team won their first Stanley Cup in franchise history in 2024, defeating the Edmonton Oilers in seven games after initially being up 3-0 in the series. The team lost to the Vegas Golden Knights in the Stanley Cup Finals in 2023. This team, founded in 1993 as an expansion franchise, experienced a Cinderella run to the Stanley Cup Finals in 1996, ultimately losing to the Colorado Avalanche. Name this NHL team based in Sunrise, Florida. ",
            "answers": ["Florida Panthers", "Panthers"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This law enforcement official served as the first Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), holding the position for 48 years under eight presidents. He is credited with modernizing the FBI and transforming it into a major crime-fighting agency, but his legacy is also controversial due to his use of surveillance and intimidation tactics against political activists and civil rights leaders. Name this influential figure in American law enforcement who remains a subject of debate and scrutiny.",
            "answers": [
                "J. Edgar Hoover",
                "Hoover",
                "J Hoover",
                "Edgar Hoover"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This coming-of-age drama film, directed by Barry Jenkins, tells the story of a young African-American man named Chiron as he grapples with his identity and sexuality while growing up in a rough Miami neighborhood. It garnered critical acclaim for its poignant storytelling, powerful performances, and exploration of themes such as masculinity, family, and self-discovery. Name this film that won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2017 after a dramatic mix-up during the live announcement, where \"La La Land\" was initially mistakenly declared the winner.",
            "answers": ["Moonlight"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "A woman in this novel is fired from her factory job for having a child out of wedlock. The protagonist of this novel is given silver candlesticks by a bishop. Gavroche catches a police officer at a barricade in this novel, who kills himself after being mercifully freed. Eponine Thenardier saves the life of Marius in this novel. Name this novel about the ex-convict Jean Valjean by Victor Hugo.",
            "answers": ["Les Miserables", " Les miz"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This pharaoh, who ascended to the throne at the age of nine, reigned for only about a decade before his untimely death at around 19. His tomb, discovered in 1922 by Howard Carter in the Valley of the Kings, was remarkably intact, containing a wealth of treasures and artifacts that provided valuable insights into ancient Egyptian life and burial practices. Name this \"boy king\" whose tomb's discovery sparked a worldwide fascination with ancient Egypt.",
            "answers": [
                "Tutankhamun",
                "Tutankhamen",
                "King Tut",
                "Tutankhamuna",
                "King Tutankhamun",
                "King Tutankhamen"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This prehistoric monument, constructed over multiple phases spanning centuries, features a circular ditch and bank, a ring of bluestones transported from Wales, and a horseshoe arrangement of massive sarsen stones. Its alignment with the sunrise on the summer solstice suggests a connection to solar events and possibly astronomical observations. Name this iconic megalithic structure located on Salisbury Plain in Wiltshire, England, a UNESCO World Heritage Site that continues to be a source of fascination and speculation.",
            "answers": ["Stonehenge"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These objects have a clinamen, or a tendency to swerve, as stated by Lucretius in On the Nature of Things. These objects have electron clouds, which are not represented in the Bohr model of them. Democritus believed that these objects made up everything in the universe. The Greek word for \"indivisible\" provided the name of what fundamental units of matter that can be combined into molecules?",
            "answers": ["atoms", " atom"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Netflix historical drama chronicles the life of Queen Elizabeth II, starting with her early years and ascension to the throne. Claire Foy and Olivia Colman have both portrayed the monarch in different stages of her life. The show delves into the personal and political challenges faced by the royal family, including the Suez Crisis, the Aberfan disaster, and Princess Margaret's relationship with Peter Townsend. Notably, the series has received numerous awards, including Golden Globes and Emmys. What is the name of this critically acclaimed show?",
            "answers": ["The Crown"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Spanish writer, once captured by Barbary pirates, is best known for a two-part novel published in 1605 and 1615. It follows a delusional nobleman who sets out to revive chivalry, accompanied by his pragmatic squire, Sancho Panza.  The novel's characters and themes, deeply ingrained in Western culture, have inspired countless adaptations. It is considered one of the most important works of literature ever written. Who was this author of Don Quixote?",
            "answers": ["Miguel de Cervantes", "Cervantes"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This American League baseball team plays in the oldest active ballpark in Major League Baseball, known for its iconic Green Monster wall. After selling Babe Ruth to the Yankees in 1920, they endured a long \"Curse of the Bambino,\" finally winning the World Series in 2004. They've won nine titles and boast legendary players like Ted Williams, Carl Yastrzemski, and David Ortiz.  What is the name of this Boston-based team?",
            "answers": ["Boston Red Sox", "Red Sox"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This country was the primary battleground of a 17th-century conflict that pitted Roundheads, supporters of Parliament, against Cavaliers, those loyal to the monarchy. Religious and political tensions fueled the conflict, leading to the execution of King Charles I in 1649.  A period of republican rule under Oliver Cromwell followed, but the monarchy was eventually restored in 1660 with Charles II ascending to the throne. Which country was the main setting for this civil war?",
            "answers": ["England", "Britain", "Great Britain"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This dormant stratovolcano, located in the Caucasus Mountains, has two summits, both volcanic domes. It's the highest peak in Russia and the European continent, with the western summit reaching 5,642 meters above sea level. While sulfurous gases are still emitted on its eastern slopes, it is a popular destination for mountaineering and tourism. Notably, it's the 10th most prominent peak in the world, and its glaciers feed several rivers including the Kuban and Malka. What is this mountain called?",
            "answers": ["Mount Elbrus", "Mt Elbrus", "Elbrus"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The de Broglie wavelength of a particle equals Planck's constant divided by this quantity. This\nquantity and position can't be measured with high accuracy at the same time according to\nHeisenberg's uncertainty principle. The conservation of this quantity's angular form, whose rate\nof change is torque, explains why gyroscopes work. What quantity is equal to an\nobject's mass times its velocity?",
            "answers": ["momentum"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This state was initially claimed by the Dutch in the 17th century under the name New Netherland, with New Amsterdam as its capital.  It was one of the original Thirteen Colonies and played a crucial role in the American Revolution, hosting numerous significant battles. The state's constitution was adopted in 1777 and heavily influenced the United States Constitution. In the 19th century, it was a major center of immigration and commerce, with Ellis Island serving as a gateway for millions of newcomers to the country. Which state is this?",
            "answers": ["New York"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This nation became the first to retrieve soil samples from the dark side of the moon in June 2024. The nation launched its first satellite, Dong Fang Hong I, in 1970 from the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center using a Long March-1 rocket. It later successfully sent its first crewed mission, Shenzhou 5, into space in 2003, making it the third country to independently achieve human spaceflight. Name this Asian nation which is led by Xi Jinping.",
            "answers": ["China", "PRC", "People's Republic of China"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Republican politician, known for his \"Front Porch Campaign,\" served as the 25th president of the United States from 1897 until his assassination in 1901. A Civil War veteran and former governor of Ohio, his presidency was marked by the Spanish-American War and the annexation of Hawaii. He was shot by an anarchist named Leon Czolgosz while attending the Pan-American Exposition in Buffalo, New York, and died eight days later. Who was this president?",
            "answers": ["William McKinley"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This West African nation, the most populous on the continent, is known for its diverse landscape, ranging from tropical rainforests in the south to savannas in the north. Its largest city, Lagos, is a major economic and cultural hub, while its capital, Abuja, is a planned city built in the 1980s. It is a significant oil producer, with its petroleum industry playing a crucial role in its economy. It is also home to the Niger River delta, one of the world's largest wetlands. What is the name of this country?",
            "answers": ["Nigeria"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Based on a comic book series of the same name, this post-apocalyptic horror television series premiered in 2010 and ran for 11 seasons. The story follows a group of survivors, led by former sheriff's deputy Rick Grimes, as they navigate a world overrun by zombies, referred to as \"walkers.\" The show explores themes of survival, morality, and the breakdown of society. What is the name of this show that was filmed primarily in Georgia?",
            "answers": ["The Walking Dead"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "The rate at which this process occurs is over 100 times normal rates due to human activity in\nthe Holocene epoch. The non-avian dinosaurs underwent this process following a meteor\nimpact 65 million years ago. Species at risk of this process are classified as endangered or critically\nendangered. Name this process in which all members of a species die out.",
            "answers": ["extinction", " extinct"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Donald Sutherland, one of the stars of this movie which was based on a novel by Richard Hooker, passed away in June 2024. The 1970 film inspired a TV series with the same name. The series, set during the Korean War, followed the lives of medical personnel stationed at the 4077th Mobile Army Surgical Hospital. It featured characters like the irreverent Hawkeye Pierce, the by-the-book Margaret Houlihan, and the wise-cracking Corporal Klinge Its final episode, \"Goodbye, Farewell and Amen,\" remains the most-watched television finale in U.S. history. What is the name of this critically acclaimed and beloved series?",
            "answers": ["M*A*S*H", "MASH", "M.A.S.H."],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This country is the setting for one of the most iconic works of art in the world, a woodblock print by Katsushika Hokusai created in the early 19th century. The artwork depicts a massive wave towering over boats with this nation's iconic mountain visible in the background. The artwork is often referred to as \"The Great Wave\" or \"The Great Wave off Kanagawa\" and is renowned for its striking composition and use of Prussian blue pigment. Which country is the setting for this iconic artwork?",
            "answers": ["Japan"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Major League Baseball team, originally known as the Brown Stockings, adopted its current name in 1900 after a sportswriter remarked on their \"cardinal red\" stockings. They play their home games at Busch Stadium, which opened in 2006, and are one of the most successful franchises in baseball history, with 11 World Series championships.  Their mascot, Fredbird, is a beloved figure among fans.  Hall-of-Famers such as Stan Musial, Bob Gibson, and Ozzie Smith have donned this team's uniform.",
            "answers": ["St. Louis Cardinals", "Cardinals"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Fought near a Central Pacific atoll sharing its name, this pivotal World War II naval battle saw the U.S. Navy, aided by codebreakers who deciphered a JN-25b message, decisively defeat the Imperial Japanese Navy. The Americans lost the Yorktown, but sank four Japanese aircraft carriers\u2014Akagi, Kaga, Soryu, and Hiryu\u2014crippling Japan's naval strength. Occurring six months after the attack on Pearl Harbor, this battle is considered a turning point in the Pacific Theater. What is the name of this battle?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Midway", "Midway"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This state was initially part of North Carolina and was later known as the Southwest Territory. It was the 16th state admitted to the Union on June 1, 1796, with John Sevier as its first governor. Its nickname, \"The Volunteer State,\" stems from its significant contributions to the War of 1812 and the Mexican-American War. During the Civil War, it was the last state to secede and the first to be readmitted to the Union, with both Union and Confederate sympathizers within its borders. Which state is this?",
            "answers": ["Tennessee"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This French Enlightenment writer, known for his wit and satire, penned plays such as \"Za\u00efre\" and \"Oedipe,\" as well as the epic poem \"La Henriade.\" He championed civil liberties, freedom of religion, and separation of church and state, often criticizing the Catholic Church and organized religion. His most famous works include the satirical novella \"Candide\" and the philosophical dictionary \"Dictionnaire philosophique.\" A vocal advocate for social reform, he spent time imprisoned in the Bastille and exiled in England. Who was this influential figure?",
            "answers": [
                "Voltaire",
                "Fran\u00e7ois-Marie Arouet",
                "M de Voltaire"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "A molecule containing this element can be exfoliated by Scotch tape. This element and\nhydrogen are often not labeled on structural diagrams. The atomic mass unit is based on an\nisotope of this element. Graphene and graphite are allotropes of this element. Organic chemistry\nis centered around the properties of this element, which all life is based on. Name this\nsixth element with a symbol matching its first letter.",
            "answers": ["carbon"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This river is immortalized in Richard Wagner's opera cycle, \"Der Ring des Nibelungen,\" as the dwelling place of water spirits who guard a treasure of gold. Flowing from the Swiss Alps, this river passes through major European cities like Basel, Strasbourg, Cologne, and Rotterdam before emptying into the North Sea. Its scenic middle section is known for its numerous castles. Historically, it has served as a vital trade route and a natural border between nations, playing a significant role in European conflicts. What is the name of this river?",
            "answers": ["Rhine River", "The Rhine"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Formed in Los Angeles in 1971, this band's members originally included Glenn Frey, Don Henley, Bernie Leadon, and Randy Meisner. Their debut album, released in 1972, featured hits like \"Take It Easy\" and \"Witchy Woman.\"  Known for their harmonies and blend of rock, country, and folk influences, they achieved immense commercial success throughout the 1970s with albums like \"Desperado,\" \"One of These Nights,\" and \"Hotel California.\" The band broke up in 1980 but reunited in 1994 for the \"Hell Freezes Over\" tour and album. What is the name of this iconic American band?",
            "answers": ["The Eagles"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Indian-born British author, known for his magical realism and historical fiction, faced controversy and a fatwa for his 1988 novel \"The Satanic Verses.\" His works often explore themes of migration, identity, and the clash of cultures.  He won the Booker Prize in 1981 for \"Midnight's Children,\" a sprawling epic about India's transition from British colonialism to independence.  Other notable works include \"Shame,\" \"The Moor's Last Sigh,\" and \"Shalimar the Clown.\" Who is this acclaimed yet controversial author who was attacked on stage in 2022? ",
            "answers": ["Salman Rushdie", "Rushdie"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This baseball player, sometimes considered the greatest all-around player of all time passed away in June 2024. Nicknamed the \"Say Hey Kid,\" this baseball legend was a 24-time All-Star, 12-time Gold Glove Award winner, and two-time National League MVP. Known for his iconic over-the-shoulder catch in the 1954 World Series, he spent the majority of his career with the New York/San Francisco Giants before finishing with the New York Mets. Name this member of the 3,000 hit club with 660 career home runs which rank him among the all-time leaders.",
            "answers": ["Willie Mays"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Nicknamed \"Mr. Hockey,\" this right winger played 26 seasons with the Detroit Red Wings, winning four Stanley Cups. He is known for the a special hat trick\u2014a goal, an assist, and a fight\u2014in a single game.  He was the first player to reach 800 goals and holds the record for most NHL games played with 1,767. His sons Mark and Marty also played professional hockey, even teaming up with him in the WHA. Who is this legendary hockey player?",
            "answers": ["Gordie Howe", "How"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This baseball team, which plays its home games at T-Mobile Park, joined the American League as an expansion team in 1977. Their name reflects the city's strong maritime heritage, and their mascot, the Mariner Moose, is a beloved figure among fans. They have never won a World Series, but they hold the MLB record for most wins in a single season, achieving 116 wins in 2001. What is the name of this team, whose iconic logo features a compass rose and a stylized \"S\"?",
            "answers": ["Seattle Mariners", "Mariners"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Italian Renaissance master, born in 1483, was a child prodigy. He apprenticed to the renowned painter Pietro Perugino at a young age. He was commissioned by Pope Julius II to paint the papal apartments in the Vatican, including his masterpiece, The School of Athens. Despite his untimely death at the age of 37, he left behind a vast body of work, including Madonnas, portraits, and frescoes. Name this artist, considered one of the three great masters of the High Renaissance, alongside Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo. ",
            "answers": ["Raphael", "Raffaello Sanzio da Urbino"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This historic document was sealed at Runnymede in 1215, following a rebellion of English barons against King John; it limited the power of the monarchy, guaranteeing certain rights and liberties to all free men; it established the principle of habeas corpus, preventing unlawful detention; it served as an inspiration for future legal documents such as the United States Constitution. Name this charter, which was written in Latin and means \"Great Charter.\"",
            "answers": ["Magna Carta"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Born in rural Mississippi in 1954, this influential figure overcame a challenging childhood to become a media mogul, actress, and philanthropist. She hosted a wildly popular daytime talk show for 25 seasons, which became known for its focus on self-improvement and empowerment. She also founded a successful magazine, launched a cable network, and even acted in films like \"The Color Purple\" and \"Beloved.\" Name this influential figure who is sometimes referred to as the first Black woman billionaire.",
            "answers": ["Oprah Winfrey", "Oprah"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These mammals, belonging to the order Lagomorpha, are known for their distinctive long ears, short fluffy tails, and powerful hind legs. Unlike rodents, they possess two pairs of upper incisors, with a smaller pair located directly behind the larger front teeth. Their diet consists primarily of grasses and leafy greens, and they have a unique digestive system that includes hindgut fermentation. Due to their high reproductive rate, they are often used in scientific research, particularly in studies related to reproduction, genetics, and immunology. What are these animals called?",
            "answers": ["Rabbit", "bunny", "rabbits", "bunnies"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This actress, whose trademark large eyes and distinctive voice made her a Hollywood icon, was born Ruth Elizabeth Davis in Lowell, Massachusetts, in 1908. She rose to fame in the 1930s and 1940s, known for her fierce independence and willingness to play unsympathetic characters. She had a legendary feud with fellow actress Joan Crawford, which culminated in their collaboration on the 1962 film \"What Ever Happened to Baby Jane?\".  Name this two-time Academy Award winner, whose career spanned six decades and included memorable roles in films like \"Jezebel,\" \"Dark Victory,\" and \"All About Eve.\"",
            "answers": ["Bette Davis", "Betty Davis", "Davis"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This country, whose name is derived from the Greek word \"Aigyptos,\" is home to the oldest and only remaining Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. Its capital, the largest city in Africa, is a major cultural and economic hub. It shares a border with Libya to the west and Sudan to the south. Name this nation on the Nile River, whose ancient civilization flourished for over 3,000 years. ",
            "answers": ["Egypt"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This nation led by President William Ruto had mass protests in June 2024 relating to a finance bill which proposed a large increase in taxes. The bill was passed on June 20. Protesters stormed the Parliament building on June 25 which led to the military being deployed to support the police. President Ruto then reversed course stating he would not sign the bill. Name this African nation home to more than 50 million people with a capital of Nairobi.",
            "answers": ["Kenya"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This river, whose name means \"Lion River\" in Sanskrit, is one of the longest in Asia, flowing over 3,000 kilometers from its source in the Tibetan Plateau to its delta in the Arabian Sea; it's home to a blind freshwater dolphin species found only in this river system; its basin was the cradle of the one of the world's earliest urban civilizations; it's a major source of irrigation and hydroelectric power for Pakistan and India. Name this river, which holds cultural and economic significance for millions of people.",
            "answers": ["Indus River", "Indis"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This barrier was nicknamed the \u201canti-fascist protection rampart\u201d by Soviet officials. Constructed in 1961, it stood as a physical and ideological division between East and West Germany during the Cold War; its initial purpose was to prevent East Germans from defecting to the West; it became a symbol of communist repression and the Iron Curtain; its fall in 1989 marked a pivotal moment in the collapse of the Soviet Union and the end of the Cold War. Name this infamous barrier, whose graffiti-covered remnants are now a popular tourist attraction.",
            "answers": ["Berlin Wall"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This fresco painting, located on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel in Vatican City, depicts a scene from the biblical Book of Genesis; it\u2019s one of nine panels illustrating the creation story and is considered one of the most replicated religious paintings of all time; it portrays God reaching out to Adam, their fingers nearly touching, in a moment that symbolizes the divine spark of life; it was painted by Michelangelo between 1508 and 1512. Name this famous artwork, whose composition and symbolism have been widely studied and interpreted. ",
            "answers": [
                "The Creation of Adam",
                "The Creation of Man",
                "Creazione di Adamo"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This TV show, created by David Lynch and Mark Frost, gained a cult following for its surreal atmosphere and unconventional storytelling; its central mystery revolves around the murder of homecoming queen Laura Palmer in the fictional town in Washington; its haunting theme song, composed by Angelo Badalamenti, became instantly recognizable; the show's dream sequences and supernatural elements added to its unique allure. Name this series, revived in 2017 after a 26-year hiatus. ",
            "answers": ["Twin Peaks"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This element, first discovered during a solar eclipse in 1868, gets its name from the Greek word for sun. It's the second most abundant element in the universe, after hydrogen, yet it's relatively rare on Earth; it's lighter than air, which is why it's used to fill balloons and blimps; at extremely low temperatures, it becomes a superfluid, meaning it can flow without any friction. What is this noble gas, known for its ability to alter the pitch of human voices when inhaled?",
            "answers": ["Helium", "He"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete, nicknamed \u201cHammerin\u2019 Hank,\u201d faced racial prejudice and death threats throughout his career, especially as he approached Babe Ruth\u2019s home run record; he began his professional baseball career in the Negro leagues before joining the Milwaukee Braves; in 1974, he broke Babe Ruth\u2019s record of 714 career home runs, finishing his career with 755; he was inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame in 1982. Name this baseball legend who played the majority of his career with the Atlanta Braves. ",
            "answers": ["Hank Aaron"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This man's podcast, where he hosts long form interviews, is commonly believed to be the most popular in the United States. His podcast has been both praised for its diverse conversations and criticized for spreading misinformation. He began his career as a standup comedian in the 1980s and gained recognition as a co-host on the reality show \"Fear Factor.\" Name this man who has worked as a commentator for UFC and is known to hold black belts in Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu and Taekwondo.",
            "answers": ["Joe Rogan"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This influential politician was born in 1947 and graduated from Wellesley College in 1969, where she gave a commencement speech that received national attention. She served as First Lady of the United States from 1993 to 2001 and played a key role in the administration's health care reform efforts. In 2000, she was elected as the first female senator from New York, serving until 2009 when she was appointed Secretary of State. In 2016, she became the first woman to be nominated for president by a major U.S. political party. Name this politician who ran against Donald Trump in the 2016 presidential election.",
            "answers": [
                "Hillary Clinton",
                "Hillary Rodham",
                "Hillary Rodham Clinton"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This novel, first published in Lippincott's Monthly Magazine in 1890, sparked controversy for its themes of hedonism and immorality. Its title character, a young man of extraordinary beauty, wishes that his portrait would age instead of him, a wish that is mysteriously granted. As Dorian indulges in a life of pleasure and sin, his portrait reflects the corruption of his soul, while he himself remains untouched by time. Name this only novel by Oscar Wilde, a cautionary tale about the dangers of vanity and the pursuit of pleasure.",
            "answers": ["The Picture of Dorian Gray", "Dorian Gray"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This battle, fought in 480 BC, saw a small force of Greek warriors, including the legendary 300 Spartans led by King Leonidas, hold off a massive Persian army under Xerxes I for three days; it took place at a narrow pass called \"Hot Gates\" in Greek; despite their valiant defense and the use of phalanx formations, the Greeks were ultimately betrayed and outflanked, leading to their defeat; this battle has become a symbol of courage, sacrifice, and the defense of freedom against overwhelming odds. Name this battle, which was famously depicted in the 2006 film \"300.\" ",
            "answers": [
                "Battle of Thermopylae",
                "Thermopali",
                "Battle of Thermopali"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This Virginia-born politician served as governor of the Indiana Territory from 1801 to 1812, during which he fought against Tecumseh\u2019s Confederacy in the Battle of Tippecanoe; his victory earned him the nickname \u201cOld Tippecanoe\u201d and helped him win the presidency in 1840 with the slogan \u201cTippecanoe and Tyler Too\u201d; his inauguration speech was the longest on record, lasting nearly two hours in freezing temperatures; he died from pneumonia just 31 days into his term, making his the shortest presidency in US history. Name this president whose death led to the first transfer of presidential power to a vice president.",
            "answers": ["William Henry Harrison", "Harrison", "Henry Harrison"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This actor, born in Dorking, England, trained at the prestigious Central School of Speech and Drama; he gained recognition for his Shakespearean roles on stage, notably his performances as Hamlet, Richard III, and Othello; he was married three times, including a tumultuous relationship with actress Vivien Leigh. Name this influential figure in 20th-century theater and cinema, who directed and starred in several film adaptations of Shakespeare's plays, winning an Academy Award for Best Actor and Best Picture for his 1948 film \"Hamlet.\"",
            "answers": ["Laurence Olivier", "olivier", "lawrence olivie"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This international organization appointed Mark Rutte, a prime minister from the Netherlands as its next leader. Established in 1949 with the signing of its namesake treaty, this intergovernmental military alliance is headquartered in Brussels, Belgium. Its original purpose was to provide collective security against the Soviet Union during the Cold War. It currently has 32 member states from North America and Europe. Its core principle is collective defense, meaning an attack against one member is considered an attack against all. Name this organization whose actions include the intervention in Bosnia and Herzegovina and the ongoing support for Ukraine.",
            "answers": [
                "NATO",
                "N.A.T.O.",
                "North Atlantic Treaty Organization"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This animal\u2019s stomach is actually comprised of four compartments: the rumen, reticulum, omasum, and abomasum; they\u2019re known for their ability to digest cellulose, a complex carbohydrate found in plants, thanks to a symbiotic relationship with microbes in their rumen; their digestive process involves regurgitating and rechewing their food, a process called \u201cchewing the cud\u201d; their milk is a major source of nutrition for humans worldwide, providing protein, calcium, and other essential nutrients. Name this common farm animal, known for its gentle nature and black-and-white markings.",
            "answers": ["Cow", "cows", "bovine"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team, founded in 1989, shares its name with their state animal, the grey wolf; their logo features a howling wolf silhouetted against a blue and green background, representing the state's forests and lakes; they play their home games at the Target Center in Minneapolis, Minnesota; despite reaching the Western Conference Finals in 2004, they have yet to win an NBA championship. Name this team, whose current roster includes Karl-Anthony Towns and Anthony Edwards.",
            "answers": ["Minnesota Timberwolves", "Timberwolves"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This historic city, named after the Greek goddess of wisdom and warfare, is built around a rocky outcrop called the Acropolis, which houses the iconic Parthenon temple. It hosted the first modern Olympic Games in 1896 and is home to the Panathenaic Stadium, the only stadium in the world built entirely of marble. It's considered the birthplace of democracy, with its ancient political system serving as a model for many modern governments. Name this bustling metropolis, the capital of Greece.",
            "answers": ["Athens"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This future president was born into a wealthy New York family and endured a sickly childhood with asthma; during the Spanish-American War, he led a volunteer cavalry regiment known as the Rough Riders; he briefly served as New York City\u2019s police commissioner and is famous for his trust-busting policies against monopolies. Name this conservationist who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize for negotiating an end to the Russo-Japanese War.",
            "answers": ["Theodore Roosevelt", "Teddy Roosevelt"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This pivotal battle, fought in 1066, saw the Norman forces of William the Conqueror defeat the English army under King Harold Godwinson; it took place near the present-day town of Battle, East Sussex, England, and lasted a full day; the Normans' victory marked the end of Anglo-Saxon rule in England and the beginning of the Norman Conquest; it's depicted in the famous Bayeux Tapestry, a 70-meter-long embroidered cloth that tells the story of the battle in intricate detail. Name this battle, which changed the course of English history.",
            "answers": ["Battle of Hastings", "Hastings"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This is the only bone in the human body that\u2019s wider in the middle than at the ends; the strongest part of this bone is the shaft, which can withstand forces of up to 1,800 to 2,500 pounds in a healthy adult. This bone\u2019s name comes from the Latin meaning thigh. Name this longest and strongest bone in the human body, essential for walking, running, and jumping.",
            "answers": ["Femur", "thighbone"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This landform, part of the Southern Alps, is composed of three summits: Low Peak, Middle Peak, and High Peak; it holds great cultural significance to the indigenous M\u0101ori people, who consider it the most sacred peak; its name, in the M\u0101ori language, translates to \"Cloud Piercer\"; it was renamed in 1851 after a British explorer, although the dual name is now officially recognized. Name this landform, the highest mountain in New Zealand.",
            "answers": ["Aoraki / Mount Cook", "Aoraki", "Mount Cook"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This left-handed athlete, born in Prague, Czechoslovakia, defected to the United States in 1975 at the age of 18; known for her aggressive serve-and-volley style, she won 18 Grand Slam singles titles, including a record nine Wimbledon championships; she was a dominant force in doubles, partnering with Pam Shriver to win 20 Grand Slam titles; she held the world No. 1 ranking in singles for a total of 332 weeks, a record at the time. Name this tennis legend who won a total of 59 Grand Slam titles in singles, doubles, and mixed doubles.",
            "answers": ["Martina Navratilova"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Luis Arce, the president of this nation withstood an attempted coup d'\u00e9tat on June 26, 2024. Army commander General Juan Jos\u00e9 Z\u00fa\u00f1iga sent troops to seize Plaza Murillo, the central plaza in La Paz, and storm the Casa Grande del Pueblo, the presidential palace. This nation shares Lake Titicaca, South America's largest lake by volume, with its neighbor Peru. It's known for the Uyuni Salt Flats, the world's largest salt flat, and being a significant producer of tin and lithium. Name this country, formerly known as Upper Peru during Spanish colonial rule.",
            "answers": ["Bolivia"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This author\u2019s real name was Eric Arthur Blair, and he was born in Motihari, British India, in 1903. He served in the Indian Imperial Police in Burma before returning to England to pursue a writing career. He adopted his pen name from a river in Suffolk, England. His most famous works, two dystopian novels published in 1945 and 1949, are still widely read and analyzed for their social and political commentary. Name this author, whose works include \"Animal Farm\" and \"Nineteen Eighty-Four.\" ",
            "answers": ["George Orwell"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This reality TV show, created by Charlie Parsons in 1992, was first aired as Expedition Robinson in Sweden; it features a group of strangers marooned in a remote location, where they must compete in challenges to secure food, shelter, and immunity from elimination; the contestants, known as \u201ccastaways,\u201d are gradually voted off the island until only one remains; it has spawned numerous international adaptations, becoming a global phenomenon. Name this popular series, known for its tagline \"Outwit, Outplay, Outlast.\"",
            "answers": ["Survivor"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Though this river initially forms at the confluence of the Paranaiba and Grande rivers, it ultimately flows into the R\u00edo de la Plata estuary. Forming the border between Paraguay and Argentina, it is the second-longest river in South America. Home to the Itaipu Dam, the world's second-largest hydroelectric power plant, it is a major waterway for transportation and commerce. Which river's name translates to \"like the sea\" in the Tupi language? ",
            "answers": ["Paran\u00e1 River", "parana"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This man's memoir \"On Call\" debuted as a New York Times bestseller in June 2024. This physician and immunologist, born in Brooklyn, New York in 1940, joined the National Institutes of Health (NIH) in 1968 and became director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) in 1984; he has served as a key advisor to seven US presidents on various public health crises, including HIV/AIDS, Ebola, and Zika; Name this man who became a household name during the COVID-19 pandemic, providing regular updates and guidance to the public.",
            "answers": ["Anthony Fauci", "Fauci", "Tony Fauci"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This MLB team won the World Series in 1984 with a team led by Kirk Gibson and Jack Morris, their most recent World Series appearance was in 2012. Their mascot is Paws and their home stadium is Comerica Park, known for its Ferris wheel and carousel. They have a rich history with legendary players like Ty Cobb, Al Kaline, and Miguel Cabrera. Which Major League Baseball team plays in the Motor City and wears the Old English \"D\" on their caps?",
            "answers": ["Detroit Tigers", "Tigers"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Though they primarily feed on nectar, some species also consume pollen, tree sap, or even decaying animal matter. Their wings are covered in tiny scales, creating their vibrant colors and patterns. They undergo complete metamorphosis, transforming from egg to larva (caterpillar) to pupa (chrysalis) to adult. Known for their role in pollination and their symbolic representation of transformation, what are these insects belonging to the order Lepidoptera?",
            "answers": ["Butterfly"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Though he initially trained as a lawyer, he later devoted his life to art, co-founding the Der Blaue Reiter (The Blue Rider) group with Franz Marc. Born in Moscow, he was a pioneer of abstract art, exploring the emotional and spiritual power of color and form. Known for his \"Compositions\" series and his book \"Concerning the Spiritual in Art,\" he taught at the Bauhaus school in Germany. Which artist's painting \"Composition VIII\" is considered a masterpiece of abstract expressionism?",
            "answers": ["Wassily Kandinsky", "Candinsky"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Though it was initially adapted from a teleplay of the same name, it became a landmark film for its exploration of the American jury system. Set entirely in a jury room, it follows twelve jurors deliberating the guilt or innocence of a young man accused of murder. Known for its tense atmosphere and powerful performances, it features a cast including Henry Fonda, Lee J. Cobb, and E.G. Marshall. Which 1957 drama film examines themes of justice, doubt, and the importance of individual conscience?",
            "answers": ["12 Angry Men", "twelve angry men"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Though it initially began as a conflict between Protestant and Catholic states within the Holy Roman Empire, it eventually involved most of the major European powers. Marked by devastating battles like White Mountain and L\u00fctzen, it saw the rise of military leaders like Albrecht von Wallenstein and Gustavus Adolphus. Ending with the Peace of Westphalia in 1648, it resulted in significant political and religious changes in Europe. Which war, lasting from 1618 to 1648, is considered one of the longest and most destructive conflicts in European history?",
            "answers": ["Thirty Years' War", "thirty year war"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Initially established as a haven for debtors and those imprisoned for minor offenses, it was the last of the original Thirteen Colonies. This state's capital was originally called Terminus due to its location at the end of a railroad line. Named after King George II, it was founded by James Oglethorpe in 1733. Known for its peaches and peanuts, it was the fourth state to ratify the U.S. Constitution. Name this state that was home to Jimmy Carter.",
            "answers": ["Georgia"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This tennis player became the first African American woman to be ranked No. 1 in the world in the Open Era. Known for her powerful serve and aggressive baseline game, she initially rose to fame alongside her sister Serena. She has won seven Grand Slam singles titles, five at Wimbledon and two at the US Open. She has also won 14 Grand Slam doubles titles with her sister Serena. Which tennis star's signature fashion sense includes designing her own tennis apparel line, EleVen?",
            "answers": ["Venus Williams", "Venus"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Though it initially declared independence in 1948, it traces its historical roots to ancient Judah. Bordered by Lebanon, Syria, Jordan, and Egypt, its topography ranges from the coastal plain to the Negev Desert. Home to the Dead Sea, the lowest point on Earth, it also boasts the port city of Haifa and the ancient city of Jerusalem. Which Middle Eastern country is the world's only Jewish-majority state?",
            "answers": ["Israel"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Serving as Secretary of State under James K. Polk, he was the only president from Pennsylvania. His nickname was \"Old Buck,\" and he was a lifelong bachelor. Believing the issue of slavery would be settled by the Supreme Court, his presidency was dominated by the escalating tensions leading to the Civil War. Who was the 15th President of the United States?",
            "answers": ["James Buchanan", "Buchanan"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Though it primarily functions as a digestive organ, it also plays a role in immune response and hormone production. Its lining contains gastric glands that secrete hydrochloric acid and enzymes like pepsin. It is connected to the esophagus by the cardiac sphincter and to the small intestine by the pyloric sphincter. Known for its J-shape and ability to expand to accommodate food, what is this organ located in the upper left abdomen?",
            "answers": ["Stomach", "the stomach"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Though it was initially a box office flop, it has become a beloved holiday classic. Set in the fictional town of Bedford Falls, it tells the story of George Bailey, a man who sacrifices his dreams for the sake of his family and community. Featuring iconic scenes like the angel Clarence earning his wings and George wishing he had never been born, it stars Jimmy Stewart and Donna Reed. Which 1946 film explores themes of redemption, kindness, and the value of every life?",
            "answers": ["It's a Wonderful Life"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Though it initially aimed to restore imperial rule, it led to the modernization and Westernization of Japan. Triggered by the arrival of Commodore Matthew Perry and the signing of unequal treaties, it saw the overthrow of the Tokugawa Shogunate and the return of power to the emperor. It led to the abolition of the feudal system, the establishment of a constitutional monarchy, and the rapid industrialization and militarization of Japan. Which period marked a turning point in Japanese history, transforming the nation into a major world power?",
            "answers": ["Meiji Restoration"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Though it was initially a commercial failure, it is now considered one of the greatest American novels.  Set in the mid-19th century, it features a diverse crew of characters like Starbuck, Queequeg, and Pip. Narrated by Ishmael, a young sailor who joins the crew of the Pequod, it explores themes of obsession, revenge, and the relationship between man and nature. Which novel features Captain Ahab's relentless pursuit of a white whale?",
            "answers": ["Moby Dick"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Initially airing on Tuesdays before moving to Sundays, it became the first news program to win a primetime Emmy. Though it once featured a segment called \"Point/Counterpoint,\" it's best known for in-depth investigations and interviews. Originally co-hosted by Mike Wallace and Harry Reasoner, its ticking stopwatch has become an iconic symbol in broadcast journalism. What is this long-running news magazine program?",
            "answers": ["60 Minutes", "sixty minutes"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Though he initially studied under Arnold Sommerfeld, he later became a colleague of Niels Bohr in Copenhagen. He won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1932 for his work on quantum mechanics. His uncertainty principle states that it is impossible to simultaneously know both the position and momentum of a particle with perfect accuracy. Who led the German nuclear weapons program during World War II?",
            "answers": ["Werner Heisenberg", "heisenberg"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This geological wonder was initially discovered by the Spanish conquistador \u00c1lvar N\u00fa\u00f1ez Cabeza de Vaca in 1541, and it was named after a river which means \"big water\" in the Guaran\u00ed language. Straddling the border between Argentina and Brazil, it is actually a system of 275 waterfalls, with the Devil's Throat being the most impressive.  Surrounded by lush rainforest and home to diverse wildlife, these are one of the New Seven Wonders of Nature. What is this majestic waterfall system located in South America?",
            "answers": ["Iguazu Falls", "Iguacu falls"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Though this team holds the NFL record for most consecutive sold-out home games, their first winning season didn't occur until 1983. Their logo is inspired by a transformation mask from the Kwakwaka'wakw tribe, and their fight song is a parody of the ballad \"Louie, Louie.\" Coached by Pete Carroll from 2010-2023, their \"Legion of Boom\" defense led them to a Super Bowl victory in 2014. Which NFL team, known for its loud \"12th Man\" fan base, plays its home games at Lumen Field in Seattle, Washington? ",
            "answers": ["Seattle Seahawks", "Seahawks"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This movie was initially based on a Stephen King novel, but the author famously disliked Stanley Kubrick's film adaptation. Set in the isolated Overlook Hotel, it features a family facing supernatural forces during a harsh winter. Known for its eerie atmosphere and iconic scenes like the twins in the hallway and the \"Here's Johnny!\" line, it stars Jack Nicholson as Jack Torrance, a struggling writer who descends into madness. What is this 1980 psychological horror film?",
            "answers": ["The Shining"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Though he initially ran a haberdashery with a friend in Kansas City, he became the 33rd president after Franklin D. Roosevelt's death in 1945. He authorized the use of atomic bombs against Japan and led the U.S. during the early years of the Cold War. Known for his \"The buck stops here\" sign on his desk, he also implemented the a namesake doctrine and the Marshall Plan. Who unexpectedly won the 1948 presidential election against Thomas E. Dewey?",
            "answers": ["Harry S. Truman", "Harry Truman", "Truman"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This TV news network hosted the first 2024 US Presidential Debate between Joe Biden and Donald Trump. The debate was moderated by two of this network's journalists, Dana Bash and Jake Tapper. This network's first broadcast was about the attempted assassination of Vernon Jordan, and anchored by a husband and wife team. Founded by Ted Turner, it was the first all-news television channel in the United States. Name this cable news channel that is headquartered in Atlanta, Georgia.",
            "answers": ["CNN", "Cable News Network"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Though it initially aimed for political and societal reform, it ultimately led to the rise and fall of Napoleon Bonaparte. Sparked by economic inequality and Enlightenment ideals, it saw the storming of the Bastille and the establishment of the First French Republic. The Reign of Terror, led by Maximilien Robespierre, resulted in the execution of thousands by guillotine. Which period of radical social and political upheaval in France and its colonies began in 1789?",
            "answers": ["French Revolution"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Though he initially studied medicine, he switched to English literature and became a pioneer of African literature written in English. Born in Ogidi, Nigeria, he is best known for his debut novel, \"Things Fall Apart,\" which explores the impact of colonialism on Igbo society. His other works include \"No Longer at Ease,\" \"Arrow of God,\" and \"A Man of the People.\" Which author's writings often address the clash between traditional African values and Western influences?",
            "answers": ["Chinua Achebe", "Achebe"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Though he initially worked as a patent clerk in Switzerland, he became a Nobel laureate in Physics in 1921. His theories of special and general relativity revolutionized our understanding of space, time, and gravity. Known for his famous equation E=mc\u00b2, he also made significant contributions to the development of quantum mechanics. Which scientist, born in Ulm, Germany, is considered one of the most influential figures in the history of science?",
            "answers": ["Albert Einstein", "Einstein"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Though he initially ruled over a small kingdom in Anshan, he conquered the Median Empire and established the Achaemenid Empire. Known for his tolerant policies towards conquered peoples, he allowed the Jews to return to Jerusalem and rebuild their temple. His conquest of Babylon was facilitated by diverting the Euphrates River, and his legacy is preserved in the a namesake, alliterative cylinder. Which ruler is considered the founder of the Persian Empire?",
            "answers": [
                "Cyrus the Great",
                "Cyprus",
                "Cyrus II of Persia",
                "Cyrus"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This rock formation was initially named after Sir Henry Ayers, the eighth Premier of South Australia. It is composed of arkose, a type of sandstone rich in feldspar. It is a sacred site for the Anangu people, who believe it was created during the Dreamtime. Its surface appears to change color throughout the day, especially at dawn and dusk, due to the sunlight's angle and the rock's mineral composition. What is this large sandstone monolith in central Australia, a UNESCO World Heritage Site often referred to by its Aboriginal name?",
            "answers": ["Uluru", "Ayers Rock"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Though it was initially conceived as a representation of Dante Alighieri, the poet of the \"Divine Comedy,\" it later became a symbol of universal contemplation and human intellect. Originally part of Rodin's monumental sculptural group \"The Gates of Hell,\" it depicts a nude male figure seated on a rock, deep in thought. Numerous casts of this sculpture exist worldwide, with the most famous one located at the Mus\u00e9e Rodin in Paris. What is this iconic bronze sculpture by Auguste Rodin?",
            "answers": ["The Thinker"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Calvin Coolidge is the only US president to have been born on this day. Three US presidents, John Adams, Thomas Jefferson, and James Monroe, have died on this date which marks a US holiday. This holiday, established in 1776 to commemorate the signing of the Declaration of Independence, wasn't officially declared a federal holiday until 1870. Most historians have concluded that the Declaration was signed nearly a month after its adoption, on August 2, 1776, and not on this day as is commonly believed. Name this holday that is traditionally celebrated with parades, barbecues, and fireworks displays.",
            "answers": [
                "4th of July",
                "Fourth of July",
                "July 4",
                "July Fourth",
                "Independence Day",
                "American Independence Day"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Though this TV show was initially canceled after three seasons, it was revived by Netflix for two additional seasons. Set in Newport Beach, California, it follows the dysfunctional Bluth family after their real estate business goes bankrupt. Known for its satirical humor, meta-references, and recurring jokes like \"chicken dance\" and \"never nude,\" it features an ensemble cast including Jason Bateman, Portia de Rossi, and Will Arnett. What is this critically acclaimed comedy series narrated by Ron Howard?",
            "answers": ["Arrested Development"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This US soccer player was the youngest player to score 20 goals in a calendar year for the U.S. She became a two-time World Cup champion and Olympic gold medalist. Known for her signature \"teapot\" goal celebration and her advocacy for gender equality in sports, she co-captained the USWNT with Carli Lloyd and Megan Rapinoe from 2018 to 2020. Scoring her first World Cup goal in 2011, she gained early recognition as a member of the U.S. under-20 women's national soccer team. Which striker played for the San Diego Wave FC in 2023?",
            "answers": ["Alex Morgan", "Morgan"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Though initially founded as a safe haven for English Catholics, it was the seventh state to ratify the U.S. Constitution. Home to Fort McHenry, it was the site of the Battle of Antietam, the bloodiest single-day battle in American history. Known for its blue crabs and Old Bay seasoning, its flag features the coats of arms of the Calvert and Crossland families. Which state is home to the U.S. Naval Academy?",
            "answers": ["Maryland"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Though it was initially revealed to the Prophet Muhammad over 23 years, it is divided into 114 chapters called surahs. Containing stories of prophets like Abraham, Moses, and Jesus, it also provides guidance on various aspects of life, including faith, worship, morality, and law. Written in classical Arabic, it is considered the holy book of Islam and the word of God. Which book is the central religious text of Islam, revered by Muslims worldwide?",
            "answers": [
                "The Quran",
                "Koran",
                "The koran",
                "the quoran",
                "quaran"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This US state with 99 counties became the 29th state in 1846. Home to the National Mississippi River Museum & Aquarium, it is the only state bordered by two navigable rivers. Known for its rolling plains and cornfields, it is also home to the Bridges of Madison County. Name this state of 3 million people whose capital and most populous is Des Moines.",
            "answers": ["Iowa"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This politician called for a snap election to be held for the French Parliament on June 30 and July 7, 2024. This man served as Minister of Economics, Industry and Digital Affairs under President Fran\u00e7ois Hollande from 2014 to 2016 and Deputy Secretary-General to the President from 2012 to 2014. He is a part of the Renaissance Party which he helped to found in 2016. Name this French politician who in 2017, was elected the 25th President of France becoming the youngest person to hold the position at age 39.",
            "answers": ["Emmanuel Macron"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "Founded in 1898 as the Morgan Athletic Club in Chicago, this team is the oldest continuously operating professional American football club. They relocated to St. Louis in 1960 and then to Arizona in 1988. Their mascot is Big Red, and their home stadium is State Farm Stadium, known for its retractable roof and field. They lost to the Pittsburgh Steelers in Super Bowl XLIII. Which NFL team is quarterbacked by Kyler Murray?",
            "answers": ["Arizona Cardinals", "Cardinals"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Though he initially embarked on a grand tour of Asia, he was forced to return home early after an assassination attempt in Japan. Known for his close relationship with his cousin, Kaiser Wilhelm II of Germany, his reign saw the disastrous Russo-Japanese War and the Bloody Sunday massacre. Married to Alexandra Feodorovna, a granddaughter of Queen Victoria, he was the last Emperor of Russia. Who was overthrown in the February Revolution of 1917?",
            "answers": [
                "Tsar Nicholas II",
                "Nicholas",
                "Nicholas the second",
                "Nikolai II",
                "Czar Nicholas II"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Though she initially gained recognition with hits like \"Holiday\" and \"Borderline,\" her career skyrocketed with the release of her second album.  Known for her provocative image, elaborate stage shows, and numerous reinventions, she has sold over 300 million records worldwide. Appearing in films like \"Desperately Seeking Susan\" and \"Evita,\" she has also been a successful businesswoman and fashion icon. Which singer's 1984 performance of \"Like a Virgin\" at the MTV Video Music Awards became a cultural phenomenon?",
            "answers": ["Madonna"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Though they primarily walk sideways, some species can also swim. Their exoskeleton is made of chitin, and they must molt to grow. They belong to the order Decapoda, meaning \"ten-footed,\" and their claws are modified legs. Known for their pincers and ability to regenerate lost limbs, what are these crustaceans found in oceans, freshwater, and on land?",
            "answers": ["crab", "crabs"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "Though it is the smallest and shallowest of the world's oceans, it is home to a diverse range of marine life, including polar bears, walruses, and narwhals. Covered in sea ice for most of the year, its central surface is covered by a perennial drifting polar ice pack. It is surrounded by landmasses such as Greenland, Canada, Alaska, Russia, and Norway. Which ocean is home to the North Pole?",
            "answers": ["Arctic Ocean"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Great Lake is home to over 30,000 islands, including Manitoulin Island, the world's largest freshwater island. It experiences a unique weather phenomenon known as \"lake effect snow,\" which can produce heavy snowfall in the surrounding areas. Its name comes from a Native American tribe that inhabited the region. Name this lake, a crucial route for fur traders and explorers during the early European settlement of North America, which is the second-largest Great Lake by surface area.",
            "answers": ["Lake Huron", "Huron"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This state, not Illinois, was the birthplace of Abraham Lincoln in 1809, and it was also home to Fort Knox, established in 1918, which houses a significant portion of the United States' gold reserves. The state's Mammoth Cave National Park, established in 1941, is the world's longest known cave system.  Daniel Boone, a famous frontiersman, blazed a trail through the Cumberland Gap into this state in 1775, opening it up to westward expansion. Name this state with a capital of Frankfort.",
            "answers": ["Kentucky"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This musician, nicknamed \"the quiet Beatle,\" developed a keen interest in Indian music and spirituality, incorporating sitar and other Indian instruments into his band's music. He wrote several popular songs for The Beatles, including \"Here Comes the Sun\" and \"Something.\" After the band's breakup, he launched a successful solo career, releasing albums like \"All Things Must Pass.\" Who was this influential musician, known for his distinctive slide guitar style and exploration of diverse musical genres?",
            "answers": ["George Harrison"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete transitioned from judo to mixed martial arts (MMA) after winning a bronze medal at the 2008 Beijing Olympics. In MMA, she became the first UFC Women's Bantamweight Champion, known for her signature armbar submission. She was also the first woman inducted into the UFC Hall of Fame. Who is this athlete, who also acted in the film Furious 7?",
            "answers": ["Ronda Rousey", "Rowsy"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Shakespearean play, believed to be his last solo work, features a sorcerer named Prospero who conjures a storm to shipwreck his enemies on a remote island. It explores themes of revenge, forgiveness, and colonialism through characters like Ariel, a spirit, and Caliban, a native islander. It includes a famous quote about the world being a stage and life being but a fleeting dream. What is the title of this play, notable for its magical elements and complex characters?",
            "answers": ["The Tempest"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This 1683 battle marked the furthest westward advance of the Ottoman Empire in Europe. Polish King John III Sobieski led the defending forces, utilizing a massive cavalry charge involving over 20,000 horsemen. The siege lasted for two months and resulted in the defeat of the Ottomans, halting their expansion into Europe. What is the name of this battle, named for the capital of Austria, considered a turning point in European history?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Vienna"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This company has come under scrutiny for quality and manufacturing problems related to their largest commercial product. Initially establishing its headquarters in Seattle, Washington, it was founded in 1916. Known for iconic aircraft like the 747 \"Jumbo Jet\" and the 787 Dreamliner, it merged with McDonnell Douglas in 1997. Currently headquartered in Arlington, Virginia, it is a major player in both commercial and defense aviation. What is this American multinational corporation that designs, manufactures, and sells airplanes, rotorcraft, rockets, satellites, and missiles worldwide?",
            "answers": ["Boeing"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This bird of prey, which can live up to 30 years in the wild, plays a crucial role in maintaining the balance of aquatic ecosystems. It can dive at speeds of up to 100 miles per hour and its nests, called aeries, are often reused and added to each year. Its scientific name, Haliaeetus leucocephalus, comes from Greek words meaning \"sea eagle\" and \"white head.\" It is not closely related to other eagles found in Europe and Asia. What is the name of this bird, a national symbol of the United States, known for its white head and tail feathers?",
            "answers": ["Bald Eagle"],
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This animal, whose scientific name is Equus caballus, has a single toe on each foot, protected by a hoof, and its teeth continually erupt throughout its lifetime. It is a herbivore with a digestive system adapted for grazing, and its eyes are positioned on the sides of its head, providing a wide field of vision. This animal has played a significant role in human history, used for transportation, agriculture, and warfare. What is the name of this majestic creature, known for its speed, strength, and intelligence?",
            "answers": ["Horse", "equine"],
            "incorrect1": "Dog",
            "incorrect2": "Ox",
            "incorrect3": "Cow",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete made her professional tennis debut in 1995 at the Bell Challenge and won her first Grand Slam title at the US Open in 1999. She has won a record 13 Grand Slam doubles titles with her sister. She holds the Open Era record for most Grand Slam singles titles, with 23 wins. She also won four Olympic gold medals, one in singles and three in doubles. Who is this dominant American tennis player, considered one of the greatest athletes of all time?",
            "answers": ["Serena Williams"],
            "incorrect1": "Venus Williams",
            "incorrect2": "Maria Sharpova",
            "incorrect3": "Steffi Graf",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This country, known for its comic book tradition, has produced internationally acclaimed works like The Adventures of Tintin and The Smurfs. It is also home to the Atomium, a giant model of an iron crystal built for the 1958 Brussels World's Fair.  The country is divided into three distinct regions: Flanders, Wallonia, and Brussels, each with its own language and cultural identity. What is the name of this country, famous for its waffles, chocolate, and beer, located in Western Europe? ",
            "answers": ["Belgium"],
            "incorrect1": "Netherlands",
            "incorrect2": "Luxembourg",
            "incorrect3": "Austria",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This writer, while studying medicine at I.M. Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University, wrote short stories under the pseudonym Antosha Chekhonte. He wrote about the lives of ordinary people in late 19th-century Russia, often with a melancholic and humorous tone. Some of his most famous works include \"The Seagull,\" \"Uncle Vanya,\" and \"The Cherry Orchard.\" Who was this Russian playwright and short-story writer, considered a master of realism and a major influence on modern theater?",
            "answers": ["Anton Chekhov", "Chekov"],
            "incorrect1": "Fyodor Dostoevsky",
            "incorrect2": "Leo Tolstoy",
            "incorrect3": "Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This puzzle toy celebrated its 50th birthday in 2024. It was most popular in the 1980s, when it was estimated that one-fifth of the world's population had tried it. The was originally called the Magic Cube, but it now bears the name of its inventor, a Hungarian sculptor and architecture professor. Consisting of 26 smaller cubes, or \"cubies,\" each of the six faces is covered by nine stickers, each of one of six solid colors. Name this this puzzle which requires the solver to strategize to return it to a state where each face shows a single solid color.",
            "answers": ["Rubik's cube", "Rubix Cube", "Rubiks"],
            "incorrect1": "Mastermind",
            "incorrect2": "Bop It",
            "incorrect3": "Simon Says",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This famous civil rights leader was imprisoned for larceny and breaking and entering in 1946. While in prison, he joined the Nation of Islam and became a vocal advocate for Black nationalism. He later made a pilgrimage to Mecca, which led to a shift in his views towards racial reconciliation. Name this civil rights leader, assassinated in 1965, who changed his surname to a single letter to symbolize his rejection of his slave name.",
            "answers": ["Malcolm X", "Malcolm Little"],
            "incorrect1": "Martin Luther King Jr.",
            "incorrect2": "Muhammad Ali",
            "incorrect3": "John Lewis",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This British band, known for their elaborate stage shows and philosophical lyrics, rose to prominence during the psychedelic rock era of the 1960s. They are renowned for their use of experimental sounds, extended compositions, and concept albums. Their iconic albums, including \"The Dark Side of the Moon\" and \"The Wall,\" explored themes of alienation, madness, and social critique. Who is this influential band, whose members included Roger Waters, David Gilmour, Nick Mason, and Syd Barrett, considered pioneers of progressive rock?",
            "answers": ["Pink Floyd"],
            "incorrect1": "Led Zeppelin",
            "incorrect2": "Sex Pistols",
            "incorrect3": "Rolling Stones",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Born on the island of Corsica in 1769, this military and political leader rose to power during the French Revolution. He crowned himself Emperor of the French in 1804. His military campaigns, including victories at Austerlitz and Jena-Auerstedt, led to the establishment of the French Empire across much of Europe. Who was this influential figure, ultimately defeated at the Battle of Waterloo in 1815, who left a lasting impact on European history?",
            "answers": ["Napoleon Bonaparte", "Napoleon"],
            "incorrect1": "Henri Giraud",
            "incorrect2": "Winston Churchill",
            "incorrect3": "Arthur Wellesley",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "The opening theme for this podcast is composed by the musical duo Wonderly, which constists of Jim Brunberg and Ben Landsverk. Launched in 2017 as an extension of \"The Run-Up,\" this news podcast quickly garnered a massive following, reaching one million listeners a day within a year. Hosted by Michael Barbaro and Sabrina Tavernise, its weekday episodes typically feature interviews with New York Times journalists about a topical news story. What is the name of this popular podcast?",
            "answers": ["The Daily", "daily"],
            "incorrect1": "Matter of Opinion",
            "incorrect2": "Pod Save America",
            "incorrect3": "The Headlines",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This state was the site a series of violent confrontations between pro-slavery and anti-slavery forces in the 1850s. It is also known for its significant role in the civil rights movement, as the location of the landmark Brown v. Board of Education Supreme Court case in 1954. Amelia Earhart was born in this state in 1897, and it is home to the Eisenhower Presidential Library and Museum.  Which state is this, nicknamed \"The Sunflower State\"?",
            "answers": ["Kansas"],
            "incorrect1": "Missouri",
            "incorrect2": "Texas",
            "incorrect3": "South Carolina",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This epic poem tells the story of the Trojan War, focusing on the wrath of Achilles and his conflict with Agamemnon. It features iconic characters like Hector, Paris, and Helen of Troy, and includes scenes such as the duel between Hector and Achilles and the Trojan Horse stratagem. What is the name of this ancient Greek epic poem, traditionally attributed to Homer, considered one of the foundational works of Western literature?",
            "answers": ["The Iliad", "illiad"],
            "incorrect1": "The Odyssey",
            "incorrect2": "Dionysiaca ",
            "incorrect3": "Beowulf",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Egyptian pharaoh, known as Ozymandias in Greek, had a reign that lasted for 66 years and is believed to have fathered over 100 children. He led his armies in the Battle of Kadesh against the Hittites, resulting in the earliest known peace treaty. He also ordered the construction of the Abu Simbel temples. Who was this pharaoh, often considered one of the greatest rulers of ancient Egypt? ",
            "answers": ["Rameses II", "Ramseys"],
            "incorrect1": "Tutankhamun",
            "incorrect2": "Cleopatra VII",
            "incorrect3": "Akhenaten",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Martin Scorsese film, set in South Boston, follows an undercover cop infiltrating an Irish-American organized crime ring and a mole leaking information to the mob. It won four Academy Awards, including Best Picture and Best Director. The film's soundtrack features \"I'm Shipping Up to Boston\" by the Dropkick Murphys. Starring Leonardo DiCaprio, Matt Damon, and Jack Nicholson, it is known for its intense plot twists and gritty portrayal of Boston's criminal underworld. What is the name of this critically acclaimed crime thriller?",
            "answers": ["The Departed"],
            "incorrect1": "The Town",
            "incorrect2": "Goodfellas",
            "incorrect3": "The Irishman",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This insect, which has existed for over 320 million years, can survive for up to a week without its head. It can hold its breath for 40 minutes and run up to three miles per hour. Its exoskeleton contains chitin, a tough, protective substance also found in the shells of crustaceans. There are over 4,000 species of this insect worldwide, but only about 30 are considered pests. What is the name of this resilient creature, often associated with unsanitary conditions?",
            "answers": ["Cockroach"],
            "incorrect1": "Dung Beetle",
            "incorrect2": "Grasshopper",
            "incorrect3": "Praying Mantis",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This mountain range is the source of the Garonne River, which flows through southwestern France. It is home to a special desman, a semi-aquatic mammal found nowhere else in the world. This range played a crucial role in the Reconquista, the centuries-long Christian effort to reclaim the Iberian Peninsula from Muslim rule. It also forms a natural border between Spain and France, and is home to Andorra, a small independent principality. What is the name of this mountain range?",
            "answers": ["Pyrenees"],
            "incorrect1": "French Alps",
            "incorrect2": "Dolomites",
            "incorrect3": "Balkan Mountains",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team, founded in 1901 as the Washington Senators, relocated in 1961 and adopted their current name. Their home stadium, Target Field, opened in 2010 and features a unique limestone fa\u00e7ade. They have won three World Series championships, in 1924, 1987, and 1991. They are known for their \"Bomba Squad\" nickname, referring to their powerful offense and home run hitting ability. What is the name of this Minnesota Major League Baseball team, whose mascot are named T.C. and Minnie?",
            "answers": ["Minnesota Twins", "Twins"],
            "incorrect1": "Washington Nationals",
            "incorrect2": "Seattle Mariners",
            "incorrect3": "Baltimore Orioles",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This artist found his breakthrough with the painting \"House by the Railroad\" in 1925. His wife, Jo Nivison, was not only his life partner but also his muse and model for many of his paintings. He is best known for his depictions of solitary figures in urban settings, such as \"Nighthawks\" and \"Automat.\" Who is this American realist painter, considered a master of capturing the mood and atmosphere of modern life?",
            "answers": ["Edward Hopper"],
            "incorrect1": "Norman Rockwell",
            "incorrect2": "Winslow Homer",
            "incorrect3": "Grant Wood",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete, born in Sherwood Content, Jamaica, briefly played professional soccer after retiring from track. He achieved a \"triple-triple,\" winning gold medals in the 100m, 200m, and 4x100m relay at three consecutive Olympic Games. He holds world records in both the 100m and 200m sprints, and his 100m record of 9.58 seconds has stood since 2009. Who is this athlete, considered the fastest person ever recorded?",
            "answers": ["Usain Bolt", "Bolt"],
            "incorrect1": "Tyson Gay",
            "incorrect2": "Carl Lewis",
            "incorrect3": "Andre De Grasse",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This movement began in 1517 with the posting of the \"Ninety-Five Theses,\" criticizing the Catholic Church's sale of indulgences. It led to the establishment of new Christian denominations like Lutheranism and Calvinism, emphasizing salvation through faith alone. The printing press played a crucial role in spreading this movement's ideas, leading to widespread religious and political upheaval across Europe. What was this 16th-century movement that challenged the Catholic Church's authority?",
            "answers": ["Protestant Reformation", "The Reformation"],
            "incorrect1": "Spanish Inquisition",
            "incorrect2": "French Revolution",
            "incorrect3": "Charismatic Movement",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This politician was a Democrat from Tennesse and a vocal opponent of the Fourteenth Amendment. He served as a tailor's apprentice before his political career. He often clashed with Radical Republicans over Reconstruction which led him to be the first president to be impeached by the House of Representatives. Name this 17th US President who ascended to the presidency upon Lincoln's assassination.",
            "answers": ["Andrew Johnson"],
            "incorrect1": "Andrew Jackson",
            "incorrect2": "James Garfield",
            "incorrect3": "Ulysses S. Grant",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These bones come in five distinct types: cervical, thoracic, lumbar, sacral, and coccygeal. They are connected by facet joints and discs, allowing for flexibility and shock absorption, and they protect the spinal cord. While humans typically have 33 of these bones, the number can vary slightly from person to person. What are these individual bones that make up the backbone and support the body's structure?",
            "answers": ["Vertebrae"],
            "incorrect1": "Carpals",
            "incorrect2": "Metacarpals",
            "incorrect3": "Coccyx",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Great Lake, the smallest by surface area, is the only one that does not border the state of Michigan. It holds four times the water volume of Lake Erie and has the lowest mean surface elevation of all the Great Lakes. Home to the Thousand Islands region, an archipelago of nearly 2,000 islands, this lake was formed by glacial activity during the last ice age. What is the name of this lake, the easternmost of the Great Lakes, that borders both Canada and the United States?",
            "answers": ["Lake Ontario"],
            "incorrect1": "Lake Huron",
            "incorrect2": "Lake Michigan",
            "incorrect3": "Lake Erie",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This political commenator reported to prison on July 1, 2024 after being sentenced to four months in prison for contempt of Congress in 2022. This man was the acting director of the research project Biosphere 2 in 1993, and he served as an executive producer of 18 films from 1991 to 2016. He served as the White House's chief strategist for the first seven months of U.S. president Donald Trump's presidency. Name this man who helped found Breitbart news and served on the board of the Cambridge Analytica.",
            "answers": ["Steve Bannon"],
            "incorrect1": "Roger Stone",
            "incorrect2": "Michael Flynn",
            "incorrect3": "Michael Cohen",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "The TV show's theme song, \"Frolic,\" was composed by Luciano Michelini, and its title is a satirical response to the excessive enthusiasm often seen in American society. The HBO comedy series, co-created by and starring Larry David, the co-creator of Seinfeld, is known for its semi-improvised dialogue and cringe humor. What is the name of this critically acclaimed show, which follows the misadventures of a semi-retired television writer and producer in Los Angeles?",
            "answers": ["Curb Your Enthusiasm"],
            "incorrect1": "Seinfeld",
            "incorrect2": "Friends",
            "incorrect3": "The Office",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This artist apprenticed under Filippo Lippi and was commissioned by the Medici family to paint several works, including portraits of family members. His most famous works, \"The Birth of Venus\" and \"Primavera,\" depict mythological scenes with graceful figures and intricate details. Who is this Italian Renaissance painter, known for his contributions to the Early Renaissance style in Florence?",
            "answers": ["Sandro Botticelli", "Botticelli"],
            "incorrect1": "Raphael",
            "incorrect2": "Michaelangelo",
            "incorrect3": "Leanardo Da Vinci",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This man was born into a Muslim family in the Yunnan Province of China and was captured and castrated as a young boy, later becoming a trusted advisor to the Yongle Emperor. He commanded seven voyages across the Indian Ocean with a fleet of over 300 ships and 28,000 crew members. His expeditions were known for their massive treasure ships. Who is this Chinese explorer, diplomat, and fleet admiral, considered a key figure in China's maritime history during the Ming dynasty?",
            "answers": ["Zheng He", "Cheng Ho"],
            "incorrect1": "Gaozu of Tang",
            "incorrect2": "Wu of Han",
            "incorrect3": "Qi Shi Huang",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This inland sea, named for its hydrogen sulfide layer, is connected to the Mediterranean Sea through the Bosporus Strait and the Sea of Marmara. It is bordered by six countries and is a vital waterway for trade and transportation. Ancient Greek colonists once called it the \"Inhospitable Sea.\" Which sea is this, known for its sturgeon population and its role in the geopolitical landscape of Eastern Europe and Western Asia?",
            "answers": ["Black Sea"],
            "incorrect1": "Dead Sea",
            "incorrect2": "Bay of Bengal",
            "incorrect3": "Bering Sea",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This British politician was elected prime minister on July 4, 2024. He was born in London in 1962 and grew up in Surrey. In 2014, he was appointed Knight Commander of the Order of the Bath for his services to law and criminal justice. He has been Member of Parliament for Holborn and St Pancras since 2015. Name this man who has served as the leader of the Labour Party since 2020.",
            "answers": ["Keir Starmer", "Sir Keir Starmer"],
            "incorrect1": "Rishi Sunak",
            "incorrect2": "David Cameron",
            "incorrect3": "Liz Truss",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Netflix political thriller, a remake of a 1990 British miniseries, was the first original series produced for the streaming platform. It follows Frank Underwood, a ruthless politician who manipulates his way to power, and his equally ambitious wife, Claire. Starring Kevin Spacey, Robin Wright, and Michael Kelly, it garnered critical acclaim and numerous award nominations. What is the name of this show, known for its dark and cynical portrayal of Washington, D.C. politics?",
            "answers": ["House of Cards"],
            "incorrect1": "Anatomy of a Scandal",
            "incorrect2": "Downton Abbey",
            "incorrect3": "The Crown",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This state was home to the Coeur d'Alene people for thousands of years before European explorers arrived. It was admitted to the Union as the 43rd state in 1890 and is known for its vast wilderness areas, including the Frank Church\u2013River of No Return Wilderness, the largest contiguous wilderness area in the contiguous United States. This state's capital is Boise and it was the site of the controversial Ruby Ridge incident in 1992. Which state is this, nicknamed the \"Gem State?\"",
            "answers": ["Idaho"],
            "incorrect1": "Montana",
            "incorrect2": "Wyoming",
            "incorrect3": "Nevada",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This Scottish-born inventor, inspired by his mother and wife's hearing impairments, initially focused on improving devices for the deaf. He founded the Volta Laboratory, where he collaborated with other scientists on various inventions. He experimented with aeronautics, developing early versions of hydrofoils and airplanes, but he is best known as the inventor of the telephone. Who was this prolific inventor, a founding member of the National Geographic Society? ",
            "answers": ["Alexander Graham Bell"],
            "incorrect1": "Thomas Edison",
            "incorrect2": "Benjamin Franklin",
            "incorrect3": "Nikola Tesla",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team, founded in 1968, starting playing at the Fiserv Forum in 2018. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, formerly known as Lew Alcindor, led this team to their first NBA championship in 1971. In 2021, Giannis Antetokounmpo, nicknamed the \"Greek Freak,\" led this team to their second NBA championship, earning the Finals MVP award. What is the name of this NBA team, known for their green and cream uniforms?",
            "answers": ["Milwaukee Bucks", "Bucks"],
            "incorrect1": "Utah Jazz",
            "incorrect2": "New Orleans Pelicans",
            "incorrect3": "Miami Heat",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This actor, known for his distinctive method acting style, received an Academy Award nomination for his breakthrough role as Michael Corleone. He is famous for his passionate delivery of lines like \"Say hello to my little friend!\" in \"Scarface.\" A recipient of the \"Triple Crown of Acting,\" he has won numerous awards, including an Oscar, two Tonys, and two Emmys. Who is this legendary actor, known for his roles in iconic films like \"Serpico\" and \"Dog Day Afternoon\"?",
            "answers": ["Al Pacino"],
            "incorrect1": "Robert De Niro",
            "incorrect2": "Jack Nicholson",
            "incorrect3": "Joe Pesci",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This body of water, containing over 250 small islands, islets, and reefs, is a crucial shipping route, with over $3 trillion in trade passing through it annually. Its Spratly Islands are claimed by six different countries, leading to ongoing territorial disputes. Historically, it was a major trade route for Chinese, Indian, and Arab merchants. What is the name of this marginal sea, a major source of geopolitical tension in Southeast Asia?",
            "answers": ["South China Sea"],
            "incorrect1": "Bay of Bengal",
            "incorrect2": "Bering Strait",
            "incorrect3": "English Channel",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This author's debut novel, \"Go Tell It on the Mountain,\" explored his religious upbringing in Harlem. His essay \"The Fire Next Time\" became a powerful meditation on race and religion in the United States. A close friend of Maya Angelou and Toni Morrison, he often explored themes of identity, sexuality, and social injustice. Who was this influential American writer?",
            "answers": ["James Baldwin"],
            "incorrect1": "James Patterson",
            "incorrect2": "Ta-Nehisi Coates",
            "incorrect3": "Nikki Giovanni",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This athlete wore the number 99, was nicknamed \"The Great One,\" and began his NHL career with the Edmonton Oilers. He holds the record for most goals and assists in NHL history, with a combined total of 2,857 points. He won four Stanley Cup championships with the Edmonton Oilers and was awarded the Conn Smythe Trophy twice. He was inducted into the Hockey Hall of Fame in 1999. Who is this legendary Canadian ice hockey player, widely regarded as the greatest of all time?",
            "answers": ["Wayne Gretzky", "Gretsky"],
            "incorrect1": "Bobby Orr",
            "incorrect2": "Mario Lemieux",
            "incorrect3": "Guy Lafleur",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This Italian physicist invented the first electric battery in 1800, known as the voltaic pile, by stacking discs of copper and zinc. He engaged in a scientific rivalry with Luigi Galvani, whose experiments with frogs led to the discovery of animal electricity. The unit of electric potential is named after him. Who was this pioneer in the study of electrical phenomena? ",
            "answers": ["Alessandro Volta", "Volta"],
            "incorrect1": "Heinrich Hertz",
            "incorrect2": "André-Marie Ampère",
            "incorrect3": "Nikola Tesla",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This pop star has a claim to the song of the summer with her hit, \"Espresso\". The former child actress, who started her musical journey posting covers on YouTube, gained initial recognition for her role in the Disney Channel series \"Girl Meets World.\"  With hits like \"Nonsense\" and \"Skin,\" which became her first entry on the US Billboard Hot 100 chart, this singer-songwriter has cemented her status as a rising star. Who is this pop star?",
            "answers": ["Sabrina Carpenter"],
            "incorrect1": "Selena Gomez",
            "incorrect2": "Dua Lipa",
            "incorrect3": "Vanessa Hudgens",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This battle, one of the final major offensives of World War II in Europe, began on April 16, 1945. It involved over 2.5 million Soviet soldiers and 6,250 tanks, making it one of the largest battles in history. During this battle, Adolf Hitler committed suicide in his F\u00fchrerbunker. The city's defenders surrendered on May 2, 1945, marking the end of the battle and a significant turning point in the war. What was the name of this battle, which ultimately led to the collapse of Nazi Germany?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Berlin", "Fall of Berlin"],
            "incorrect1": "Battle of the Somme",
            "incorrect2": "Battle of Flanders",
            "incorrect3": "Hamburger Hill",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This US state was the first home to the\u00a0Ringling Brothers circus in 1884. Joseph McCarthy began his political career as a circuit judge in 1939 in this state, and the Republican Party was founded here in 1854. This state was historically home to the Menominee and Ho-Chunk tribes and has a capital of Madison. Name this state which is led by Governor Tony Evers.",
            "answers": ["Wisconsin"],
            "incorrect1": "Minnesota",
            "incorrect2": "Kentucky",
            "incorrect3": "Tennessee",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This Southwestern city broke multiple heat records in July 2024, including reaching its highest temperature of 120 degrees Fahrenheit and having at least 7 days in a row above 115 degrees. The desert city, founded in 1905, is home to the iconic Fremont Street Experience, a pedestrian mall with a 1,500-foot-long LED canopy displaying light shows. Name this city that experiences over 300 days of sunshine annually and is located in Clark County. It is known for iconic gambling and nightlife experiences.",
            "answers": ["Las Vegas", "Vegas"],
            "incorrect1": "Phoenix",
            "incorrect2": "Atlanta",
            "incorrect3": "Los Angeles",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This bustling Southeast Asian city is situated on the Chao Phraya River delta and is often referred to as the \"Venice of the East\" due to its network of canals. It is home to the Grand Palace, the official residence of the Thai monarch, as well as Wat Arun, a temple famous for its towering spires. Name this city that is about 25 miles from the Gulf of Thailand, that is also known for signature dishes like Pad Thai and Tom Yum Goong.",
            "answers": ["Bangkok"],
            "incorrect1": "Kuala Lumpur",
            "incorrect2": "Phuket",
            "incorrect3": "Taipei",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Oxford professor, known for his high fantasy works, created the intricate world of Middle-earth, complete with detailed languages and histories. His experiences in World War I had a profound impact on his writing, often drawing parallels between the horrors of war and his characters', such as Frodo Baggins, struggles. His most famous novels, \"The Hobbit\" and \"The Lord of the Rings\" trilogy, explore themes of good versus evil, the power of language, and the importance of nature. Who is this beloved author?",
            "answers": [
                "J.R.R. Tolkien",
                "Tolkein",
                "John Ronald Reuel Tolkien"
            ],
            "incorrect1": "C.S. Lewis",
            "incorrect2": "Peter Jackson",
            "incorrect3": "H.P. Lovecraft",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This Italian poet's love for Beatrice Portinari, whom he met as a child, is a recurring theme in his poetry. He was born in Florence in 1265 and was deeply involved in the city's political struggles, which led to his exile in 1302. He is best known for his epic poem which describes a journey through Hell, Purgatory, and Paradise. Who is this influential figure in Italian literature and Renaissance thought, the author of the Divine Comedy?",
            "answers": ["Dante", "Dante Alighieri"],
            "incorrect1": "Homer",
            "incorrect2": "Ovid",
            "incorrect3": "Socrates",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American heavy metal band, formed in Los Angeles in 1981, is considered one of the pioneers of thrash metal. Their early albums, including \"Kill 'Em All\" and \"Ride the Lightning,\" showcased a raw and aggressive sound that helped to define the genre. They achieved mainstream success with their self-titled 1991 album, also known as \"The Black Album,\" which featured the hit singles \"Enter Sandman\" and \"Nothing Else Matters.\" Their music often deals with themes of social injustice, personal struggles, and addiction. Who is this iconic band that has sold over 125 million albums worldwide?",
            "answers": ["Metallica"],
            "incorrect1": "AC/DC",
            "incorrect2": "Iron Maiden",
            "incorrect3": "Van Halen",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team reached the NBA Finals in 1995 led by Shaquille O'Neal and Penny Hardaway, but were swept by the Houston Rockets. In 2009, they made it back to the finals with Dwight Howard as their star player, but ultimately lost to the Los Angeles Lakers. The team's colors are blue, black, and silver, and their logo features a stylized basketball with a star. Which team was founded in 1989 and became the first major professional sports franchise in Central Florida?",
            "answers": ["Orlando Magic", "Magic"],
            "incorrect1": "Miami Heat",
            "incorrect2": "Tampa Bay Rays",
            "incorrect3": "Memphis Grizzlies",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "Fluent in French and skilled in violin playing, this historical figure designed his own unique plow based on European models. He was a passionate advocate for religious freedom, leading to the passage of the Virginia Statute for Religious Freedom. During his presidency, the Louisiana Purchase doubled the size of the United States, dramatically expanding its territory. Who is this Founding Father, best known for drafting the Declaration of Independence? ",
            "answers": ["Thomas Jefferson"],
            "incorrect1": "Benjamin Franklin",
            "incorrect2": "George Washington",
            "incorrect3": "John Adams",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This mathematician collaborated with Charles Babbage on his Analytical Engine, a mechanical general-purpose computer. Her notes on the engine include what is now recognized as the first algorithm intended to be carried out by a machine. She, the daughter of the poet Lord Byron, is often credited as the world's first computer programmer. She recognized the potential of computers to go beyond mere calculation and envisioned their use for broader applications. Who is this pioneering figure in computer science?",
            "answers": ["Ada Lovelace"],
            "incorrect1": "Alan Turing",
            "incorrect2": "Allegra Byron",
            "incorrect3": "Grace Hopper",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This bone, the second longest in the human body, forms the medial part of the ankle joint and articulates with the femur at the knee joint. Its shaft is triangular in cross section and features several important landmarks, including a namesake tuberosity, which serves as the attachment point for the patellar ligament. Fractures of this bone are common, especially in athletes and individuals with osteoporosis. What is this weight-bearing bone that connects the knee to the ankle?",
            "answers": ["Tibia", "shinbone"],
            "incorrect1": "Fibula",
            "incorrect2": "Ulna",
            "incorrect3": "Femur",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This religious figure is believed to have lived in ancient Persia, sometime between 1700 and 600 BCE, and his teachings are considered the foundation of one of the world's oldest religions. He is said to have received divine revelations from Ahura Mazda, the supreme god of his religion. His name is often associated with the concept of dualism, the eternal struggle between good and evil, which is a central theme in his religion, Zoroastrianism. Who is this prophet and founder of one of the world's oldest religions? ",
            "answers": ["Zoroaster"],
            "incorrect1": "Confucius",
            "incorrect2": "Siddhartha Gautama",
            "incorrect3": "Jesus Christ",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This city is nicknamed \"Egoli,\" meaning \"City of Gold,\" and was founded in 1886 following the discovery of gold on the Witwatersrand ridge. It is the largest city in South Africa by population and houses the Apartheid Museum and Constitution Hill, a former prison and military fort that now houses the Constitutional Court. Despite not being one of the three capitals of the country, it serves as the seat of the Constitutional Court. What is this economic and cultural hub of South Africa?",
            "answers": ["Johannesburg"],
            "incorrect1": "Cape Town",
            "incorrect2": "Lagos",
            "incorrect3": "Kinshasa",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This politician graduated from Harvard Business School, worked in the oil industry, and owned the Texas Rangers before he served as the governor of Texas from 1995-2000. He was later elected president in an election which was contested in the Supreme Court and signed major tax cuts and the No Child Left Behind Act. Name this 43rd president of the United States who served from 2001-2009.",
            "answers": ["George W. Bush"],
            "incorrect1": "Ronald Reagan",
            "incorrect2": "Bill Clinton",
            "incorrect3": "Jimmy Carter",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NBA team was originally founded in Vancouver in 1995. They have a dedicated fan base known for their \"Grit and Grind\" mantra, reflecting the team's tough and tenacious playing style. They now have exciting young stars like Desmond Bane, Jaren Jackson Jr., and Ja Morant. What is this NBA team that plays their home games at the FedExForum in Memphis?",
            "answers": ["Memphis Grizzlies", "Grizzlies"],
            "incorrect1": "Miami Heat",
            "incorrect2": "Toronto Raptors",
            "incorrect3": "Oklahoma City Thunder",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This Atlantic hurricane, the second of the 2024 season, rapidly intensified into a Category 5 storm, making it the earliest-forming Category 5 hurricane on record. It caused significant damage in the Caribbean, particularly in the Cayman Islands and Grenada, before making landfall as a Category 1 hurricane in Texas. It caused widespread power outages and flooding in Texas, and was responsible for multiple deaths. What was the name of this atypical hurricane, known for its rapid intensification and early formation in the season?",
            "answers": ["Hurricane Beryl", "Beryl"],
            "incorrect1": "Hurricane Alice",
            "incorrect2": "Hurricane James",
            "incorrect3": "Hurricane Bonnie",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American sitcom, which ran for nine seasons from 1989 to 1998, known for its observational humor, quirky characters, and catchphrases like \"yada yada yada\" and \"master of my domain.\". It is often described as \"a show about nothing.\" It follows the daily lives of four friends living in New York City: Jerry, a stand-up comedian; George, his neurotic best friend; Elaine, his on-again, off-again girlfriend; and Cosmo, his eccentric neighbor. What is the name of this iconic sitcom that has left a lasting impact on American pop culture?",
            "answers": ["Seinfeld"],
            "incorrect1": "Friends",
            "incorrect2": "The Office",
            "incorrect3": "Cheers",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This French artist, known for his vibrant use of color and light, was a leading figure in the Impressionist movement. His paintings often depicted scenes of everyday life, such as dance halls, cafes, female figures, and portraits. His most famous works include \"Bal du moulin de la Galette,\" \"Luncheon of the Boating Party,\" and \"The Bathers.\" Despite suffering from rheumatoid arthritis in his later years, he continued to paint prolifically. Who is this celebrated painter?",
            "answers": ["Pierre-Auguste Renoir", "Pierre Renoir", "Renoir"],
            "incorrect1": "Claude Monet",
            "incorrect2": "Edgar Degas",
            "incorrect3": "Paul Cezanne",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "During this period of English history, the Domesday Book, a manuscript record of the \"Great Survey\" of much of England and parts of Wales, was completed. This historical event began in 1066 with the Battle of Hastings, where William the Conqueror defeated the Anglo-Saxon King Harold Godwinson. It led to profound changes in England's language, culture, and legal system, as Norman French became the language of the ruling class.",
            "answers": [
                "Norman Conquest",
                "Norman Rule",
                "Norman",
                "Norman Reign"
            ],
            "incorrect1": "Spanish Inquisition",
            "incorrect2": "Ottoman Empire",
            "incorrect3": "Viking Conquest",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This famous Renaissance fresco, painted by Raphael between 1509 and 1511, is located in the Apostolic Palace in Vatican City. It depicts a gathering of ancient philosophers, mathematicians, and scientists engaged in lively discussion and debate. The central figures are Plato and Aristotle, representing the two main schools of ancient Greek philosophy. It is one of four frescoes in the Stanza della Segnatura, each representing a different branch of knowledge. What is the name of this iconic artwork, often considered a masterpiece of Renaissance art?",
            "answers": ["The School of Athens", "school of athens"],
            "incorrect1": "Creation of Adam",
            "incorrect2": "The Sistine Madonna",
            "incorrect3": "Disputation of the Holy Sacrament",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This Swiss city is situated at the northwestern tip of a lake bearing the same name. The Limmat River runs through it, offering picturesque views and recreational opportunities. Its well-preserved historic center features landmarks like the Grossm\u00fcnster cathedral and the Fraum\u00fcnster church. It is the largest city in the country by population and a major financial center, often considered one of the most livable cities in the world. Which city is this?",
            "answers": ["Zurich"],
            "incorrect1": "Geneva",
            "incorrect2": "Vienna",
            "incorrect3": "Budapest",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This US state, not Georgia, is the leading peach producer east of the Mississippi River and is home to the only tea plantation in the contiguous United States. This state also boasts the oldest landscaped gardens in America, Middleton Place, which dates back to 1741. The first state to secede from the Union, this state's flag features a palmetto tree and crescent moon, symbols stemming from the Revolutionary War defense of Fort Moultrie. What is this state?",
            "answers": ["South Carolina"],
            "incorrect1": "Louisiana",
            "incorrect2": "North Carolina",
            "incorrect3": "Maryland",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This American rock band's self-titled debut album, released in 1967, reached number two on the Billboard 200 chart. Their music often explored themes of rebellion, freedom, and the dark side of the American dream. Their hit songs, including \"Light My Fire,\" \"Break on Through (To the Other Side),\" and \"Riders on the Storm,\" are considered classics of rock music. They are known for their psychedelic sound, poetic lyrics, and charismatic frontman, Jim Morrison. Who are they?",
            "answers": ["The Doors"],
            "incorrect1": "The Ramones",
            "incorrect2": "Led Zeppelin",
            "incorrect3": "Pink Floyd",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These invertebrates belong to several different phyla, including Annelida, Nematoda, and Platyhelminthes, and their body shape and size vary greatly depending on the species. Some are segmented and have a distinct head and tail, while others are ribbon-shaped and lack distinct body segments. While many are beneficial, some species can be parasitic and cause harm to plants and animals. Name these animals found in nearly all environments on Earth, that play a crucial role in maintaining soil health by aerating and enriching it.",
            "answers": ["Worm", "earthworms", "worms"],
            "incorrect1": "Beetle",
            "incorrect2": "Termite",
            "incorrect3": "Ant",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This European prime minister met with former president Donald Trump after the July 2024 NATO Summit. This man leads the Fidesz political party and served as prime minister from 1998-2002. He was then re-elected to the office in 2010 and has held it since. In the wake of the Revolutions of 1989, this man entered politics after studying law at E\u00f6tv\u00f6s Lor\u00e1nd University. Name this nationalistic prime minister of Hungary.",
            "answers": ["Viktor Orban", "Orban"],
            "incorrect1": "Robert Fico",
            "incorrect2": "Anik\u00f3 L\u00e9vai",
            "incorrect3": "P\u00e9ter Magyar",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NFL team, established in 1960, has won five Super Bowl championships and is known for its iconic star logo and enthusiastic fan base. They hold the NFL record for most consecutive winning seasons with 20. They play their home games at a state-of-the-art stadium in Arlington, Texas, and are one of the most valuable sports franchises in the world. Their rich history includes legendary players like Roger Staubach, Emmitt Smith, and Troy Aikman. What is this iconic American football team?",
            "answers": ["Dallas Cowboys", "Cowboys"],
            "incorrect1": "Houston Texans",
            "incorrect2": "Atlanta Falcons",
            "incorrect3": "Pittsburgh Steelers",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This Pulitzer Prize-winning novel, published in 1960, is set in a fictional Alabama town during the Great Depression. It is narrated from the perspective of a young girl named Scout Finch, who learns valuable lessons about racial injustice and prejudice through the experiences of her father, Atticus Finch, a lawyer defending a black man wrongly accused of rape. The novel deals with themes of morality, compassion, and the importance of standing up for what is right. What is the title of this classic American novel by Harper Lee?",
            "answers": ["To Kill a Mockingbird"],
            "incorrect1": "Catcher in the Rye",
            "incorrect2": "Lord of the Flies",
            "incorrect3": "Fahrenheit 451",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NFL team, established in 1999, replaced a previous franchise that had relocated to Tennessee. They began play as an expansion team in 2002, making them the youngest franchise currently competing in the NFL. The team's colors are Deep Steel Blue, Battle Red, and Liberty White, and their logo features a bull head with a star. They play their home games at NRG Stadium and are the only NFL team to have never appeared in a conference championship game. Which team is this, representing the fourth-largest city in the United States?",
            "answers": ["Houston Texans", "Texans"],
            "incorrect1": "Dallas Cowboys",
            "incorrect2": "Arizona Cardinals",
            "incorrect3": "Jacksonville Jaguars",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This 1777 battle, fought in upstate New York, was a major turning point in the American Revolutionary War. British General John Burgoyne's invasion from Canada was thwarted, leading to his surrender. The American victory boosted morale and convinced France to ally with the colonists. The battle consisted of two separate engagements, Freeman's Farm and Bemis Heights, fought eighteen days apart. What is the name of this significant Revolutionary War battle?",
            "answers": ["Battle of Saratoga", "Saratoga", "Saratoga Campaign"],
            "incorrect1": "Battle of Delaware",
            "incorrect2": "Battle of Gettysburg",
            "incorrect3": "Battle of Yorktown",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This drug manufactured by Novo Nordisk, was originally developed to treat type 2 diabetes. It mimics a naturally occurring hormone that regulates appetite and metabolism, leading to decreased food intake and increased calorie burning. While lauded for its effectiveness in managing obesity, this injectable drug has also faced scrutiny for potential side effects like nausea and pancreatitis. Name this that medication gained notoriety in 2023 due to its off-label use for weight loss.",
            "answers": ["Ozempic", "Wegovy"],
            "incorrect1": "Insulin",
            "incorrect2": "Adderall",
            "incorrect3": "Lipitor",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These small canids, found on every continent except Antarctica, are known for their intelligence and distinctive bushy tails. They are opportunistic omnivores, with a diet that includes rodents, rabbits, fruits, and insects. Many species exhibit seasonal changes in coat color, and some, like the fennec variety, have adaptations for surviving in extreme desert environments. What are these resourceful and versatile mammals, often featured in folklore and mythology?",
            "answers": ["Fox"],
            "incorrect1": "Squirrel",
            "incorrect2": "Dog",
            "incorrect3": "Wolf",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This US state played a crucial role in the development of the American ski industry, with the first ski lift being installed in Gunstock Mountain Resort in 1937. The first colony to declare its independence from British rule, this state's motto, \"Live Free or Die,\" is prominently displayed on its license plates. Home to the tallest peak in the northeastern United States, Mount Washington, what is this state with a capital of Concord?",
            "answers": ["New Hampshire"],
            "incorrect1": "Vermont",
            "incorrect2": "Massachusetts",
            "incorrect3": "New York",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This major African river has a unique \"boomerang\" shape, flowing in a wide arc through several West African countries. Its source is in the Guinea Highlands, and it travels northeast into the Sahara Desert before turning southeast and eventually emptying into the Gulf of Guinea. Its fertile basin supports a wide variety of plant and animal life, and its annual floods play a crucial role in agriculture. Which river, the third longest in Africa, is a vital lifeline of West Africa?",
            "answers": ["Niger River"],
            "incorrect1": "Nile River",
            "incorrect2": "Amazon River",
            "incorrect3": "Brahmaputra River",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This Italian film, set during the Holocaust, combines comedy and drama to tell the story of a Jewish man who uses his imagination and humor to shield his son from the horrors of a concentration camp. The film is partly inspired by Rubino Romeo Salmoni's book, \"In the End, I Beat Hitler\". The film won three Academy Awards, including Best Foreign Language Film and Best Actor for Roberto Benigni, who also directed and co-wrote the screenplay. Which film is this, with the italian title La vita \u00e8 bella, praised for its heartwarming message and unique approach to a difficult subject matter?",
            "answers": ["Life Is Beautiful", "La vita \u00e8 bella"],
            "incorrect1": "The Sound of Music",
            "incorrect2": "The Pianist",
            "incorrect3": "Casablanca",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This monarch's desire for a male heir led to the establishment of the Church of England, after his request for an annulment from his first wife was denied by the Pope. Known for his athleticism in his youth, he later became corpulent and suffered from a leg ulcer. He was a patron of the arts and an accomplished musician, even composing a few pieces himself. During his reign, he had six wives, two of whom were executed. Who is this infamous king?",
            "answers": ["Henry VIII", "Henry the eight", "Henry"],
            "incorrect1": "Queen Victoria",
            "incorrect2": "Elizabeth I",
            "incorrect3": "Henry V",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This inventor's Wardenclyffe Tower project, aimed at wireless power transmission, was never completed due to funding issues. He developed the AC induction motor, which is widely used today, and held over 300 patents for various inventions. He engaged in a rivalry with Thomas Edison over the best type of electrical current for widespread use. Born in what is now Croatia, he immigrated to the United States in 1884 and became a naturalized citizen. Who is this pioneering figure in electrical engineering?",
            "answers": ["Nikola Tesla", "Tesla"],
            "incorrect1": "Alessandro Volta",
            "incorrect2": "Heinrich Hertz",
            "incorrect3": "Andr\u00e9-Marie Amp\u00e8re",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This naval base was bombed by Japanese forces on December 7, 1941, resulting in the deaths of an estimated 2,403 Americans and over 3,800 civilians. The attack on this base sank or heavily damaged twelve U.S. Navy ships, including eight battleships, and destroyed 188 U.S. aircraft. The attack on this base ultimately led to the United States' entry into World War II. Name this base which was the subject of the \"Day of Infany Speech.\"",
            "answers": ["Pearl Harbor", "Pearl Harbor Hawaii"],
            "incorrect1": "Fort Campbell",
            "incorrect2": "Fort Hood",
            "incorrect3": "Guantanamo Bay",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This city, situated on the Yamuna River, is home to the Red Fort, a UNESCO World Heritage Site that served as the residence of Mughal emperors. It is also home to the Jama Masjid, one of the largest mosques in India, and the Lotus Temple, a Bah\u00e1\u02bc\u00ed House of Worship known for its distinctive lotus-shaped structure. This city has served as the capital of several empires and kingdoms throughout history, including the Delhi Sultanate and the Mughal Empire. What is the name of this bustling metropolis that is the capital of India?",
            "answers": ["Delhi", "New Delhi"],
            "incorrect1": "Mumbai",
            "incorrect2": "Lahore",
            "incorrect3": "Kathmandu",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This Major League Baseball team, originally established in 1961, briefly went by the name \"California\" before reverting to its original city in its official title in 2005. Their home stadium, in Anaheim, is one of the oldest active ballparks in the MLB. The team's sole World Series victory came in 2002, with a roster featuring players like Troy Glaus and Garret Anderson. What is this team, previos home to two-way sensation Shohei Ohtani, and currently rostering Mike Trout?",
            "answers": ["Los Angeles Angels", "Angels"],
            "incorrect1": "Los Angeles Dodgers",
            "incorrect2": "New York Yankees",
            "incorrect3": "San Francisco Giants",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This film's iconic shower scene, featuring Bernard Herrmann's screeching violin score, is considered one of the most terrifying moments in cinematic history. Shot in black and white to avoid excessive gore, it took seven days to film. The film's protagonist, Marion Crane, is killed off surprisingly early, defying traditional storytelling conventions. The film's antagonist, Norman Bates, is a motel owner with a deeply disturbed psyche and an unhealthy obsession with his mother. What is the title of this 1960 Alfred Hitchcock thriller that redefined the horror genre?",
            "answers": ["Psycho"],
            "incorrect1": "Vertigo",
            "incorrect2": "Carrie",
            "incorrect3": "The Shining",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "In this state, a gunman shot at former president Donald Trump while he was holding a campaign rally. The rally was being held near the town of Butler in this state. Prior to becoming a state, the southeast portion of the state was a Swedish Empire colony known as New Sweden between 1638 and 1655. The state is home to cities like Allentown and Reading. Name this state, the first largest by population which is nicknamed the Keystone State.",
            "answers": ["Pennsylvania"],
            "incorrect1": "Michigan",
            "incorrect2": "Nevada",
            "incorrect3": "Wisconsin",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This play, set in late 1940s Brooklyn, follows the final days of Willy Loman, an aging salesman struggling with disillusionment and despair. The play delves into Willy's fractured relationships with his sons, Biff and Happy, and his wife, Linda, as he grapples with his failures and regrets. It critiques the American Dream and its emphasis on material success and popularity. What is the title of this Pulitzer Prize-winning play by Arthur Miller?",
            "answers": ["Death of a Salesman"],
            "incorrect1": "Our Town",
            "incorrect2": "The Glass Menagerie",
            "incorrect3": "A Raisin in the Sun",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "Premiering in 1938, this play, set in the fictional town of Grover's Corners, New Hampshire, explores the universal themes of life, love, and death through the everyday lives of its inhabitants. It features a Stage Manager who narrates the action and interacts with the audience, breaking the fourth wall. This play won the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1938 and has become a classic of American theater. What is the title of this three-act play?",
            "answers": ["Our Town"],
            "incorrect1": "A Raisin in the Sun",
            "incorrect2": "A Streetcar Named Desire",
            "incorrect3": "Fences",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This lawyer from Illinois engaged in a series of debates with Stephen Douglas in 1858, focusing on the issue of slavery's expansion. Though he lost the Senate race that year, these debates elevated his national profile, contributing to his successful presidential bid two years later. During these debates, he famously asked, \"A house divided against itself cannot stand.\" Who is this historical figure known for his beard and stovepipe hat?",
            "answers": ["Abraham Lincoln", "Lincoln"],
            "incorrect1": "Franklin Pierce",
            "incorrect2": "Theodore Roosevelt",
            "incorrect3": "John C. Calhoun",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Early in this philosopher's career, he worked as a journalist, often writing about social and economic issues. His most ambitious work, \"Das Kapital,\" remained unfinished at the time of his death. He collaborated with Friedrich Engels on numerous projects, including the seminal work \"The Communist Manifesto.\" Who is this influential thinker whose ideas have shaped political and economic discourse for generations?",
            "answers": ["Karl Marx", "Carl Marks", "Marx"],
            "incorrect1": "Friedrich Nietzsche",
            "incorrect2": "Adam Smith",
            "incorrect3": "Vladimir Lenin",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "Former president Donald Trump chose this senator to be his vice presidential running mate for the 2024 election. He served in the Marine Corps during the Iraq war before going to Ohio State and then Yale Law School. Prior to becoming a senator for the state of Ohio, he was best known for his memoir which described his troubled upbringing in Middletown Ohio. Name this author of Hillbilly Elegy.",
            "answers": ["J.D. Vance", "JD Vance", "Vance"],
            "incorrect1": "Kamala Harris",
            "incorrect2": "Vivek Ramaswamy",
            "incorrect3": "Doug Burgum",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This TV show, known for its mockumentary style, follows the lives of three interconnected families living in Los Angeles. It features an ensemble cast with memorable characters like Phil Dunphy, the goofy dad, and Jay Pritchett, the patriarch. Winning 22 Primetime Emmy Awards, it tackled themes like adoption, same-sex marriage, and cultural differences. What is the name of this critically acclaimed sitcom that aired for 11 seasons?",
            "answers": ["Modern Family"],
            "incorrect1": "Friends",
            "incorrect2": "New Girl",
            "incorrect3": "Parks and Recreation",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team, initially known as the Montreal Expos, relocated to the United States in 2005. Their mascot, Screech the Eagle, was chosen through a fan contest in 2005.  The team secured their first World Series championship in 2019, becoming the first team in MLB history to win all road games in a World Series. What is the name of this baseball team that plays its home games in Washington, D.C.?",
            "answers": ["Washington Nationals", "Nationals"],
            "incorrect1": "Baltimore Orioles",
            "incorrect2": "Detriot Tigers",
            "incorrect3": "Miami Marlins",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This element, isolated by Daniel Rutherford in 1772, was originally named \"noxious air\" due to its inability to support life. It exists as a diatomic gas under standard conditions and is relatively inert, making it useful for preserving food and other materials. This element is a key component of amino acids, the building blocks of proteins, and is essential for plant growth. What is this element that makes up about 78% of Earth's atmosphere?",
            "answers": ["Nitrogen", "n"],
            "incorrect1": "Carbon",
            "incorrect2": "Oxygen",
            "incorrect3": "Hydrogen",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This city, situated on the northern tip of the North China Plain, is surrounded by mountains on three sides, giving it a strategic location throughout history. Home to the Forbidden City, a vast palace complex that served as the imperial palace for centuries, it also boasts the Temple of Heaven, a UNESCO World Heritage Site where emperors prayed for good harvests. In 2008, it hosted the Summer Olympics, showcasing its modern infrastructure and cultural heritage. What is the name of this city, the capital of China and one of the world's most populous cities?",
            "answers": ["Beijing", "Pekking"],
            "incorrect1": "Shanghai",
            "incorrect2": "Tokyo",
            "incorrect3": "Bangkok",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This former Pakistani prime minister has been accused on treason by the government of his political rival, Shehbaz Sharif. On July 13, while this politician was imprisoned, his conviction for a breach of national marriage laws was overturned on appeal. However, he remains in prison on corruptions charges. Before this man served as prime minister he was the captain of Pakistan's national cricket team in the 1980s and 1990s, including for Pakistan's 1992 World Cup victory. Name this man who leads Pakistan's PTI party.",
            "answers": [
                "Imran Khan",
                "Imran Kahn",
                "Khan",
                "Imran Ahmed Khan Niazi"
            ],
            "incorrect1": "Benjamin Netanyahu",
            "incorrect2": "Ali Khamenei",
            "incorrect3": "Narendra Modi",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This geological formation, consisting of approximately 40,000 interlocking basalt columns, is the result of an ancient volcanic eruption. Located on the coast of County Antrim in Northern Ireland, it was declared a UNESCO World Heritage site in 1986. This natural wonder, featured in legends as a crossing built by a Fionn mac Cumhaill--a giant--, is a popular tourist attraction known for its unique hexagonal columns. What is this natural wonder called?",
            "answers": ["Giant's Causeway", "Cloch\u00e1n an Aifir"],
            "incorrect1": "Cliffs of Moher",
            "incorrect2": "Aran Islands",
            "incorrect3": "Victoria Falls",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This author's debut novel, \"The Bluest Eye,\" explored the damaging effects of racism and beauty standards on a young black girl. She was the first African-American woman to win the Nobel Prize in Literature, awarded for her profound exploration of African-American identity and experience. Her most celebrated work, \"Beloved,\" tells the haunting story of a former slave haunted by the ghost of her daughter. This author also served as an editor at Random House, where she championed the works of many Black writers. Who is this influential novelist and essayist?",
            "answers": ["Toni Morrison", "Morrison"],
            "incorrect1": "Maya Angelou",
            "incorrect2": "James Baldwin",
            "incorrect3": "bell hooks",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This band, formed in Los Angeles in 1983, is known for their eclectic mix of funk, rock, and punk music. Their breakthrough album, \"Blood Sugar Sex Magik,\" released in 1991, catapulted them to international fame. Their iconic logo, a stylized asterisk, has become synonymous with their brand. They have won six Grammy Awards and were inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 2012. What is the name of this band, known for hits like \"Under the Bridge\" and \"Californication\"?",
            "answers": ["Red Hot Chili Peppers"],
            "incorrect1": "Nirvana",
            "incorrect2": "Foo Fighters",
            "incorrect3": "Pearl Jam",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NFL team, founded in 1960, holds the unfortunate distinction of losing four consecutive Super Bowls between 1990 and 1993. Led by quarterback Jim Kelly and running back Thurman Thomas during their Super Bowl runs, they were known for their high-powered \"K-Gun\" offense. The team's name was inspired by an All-America Football Conference (AAFC) franchise that played in the same city. Name this team that plays its home games at Highmark Stadium in Orchard Park, New York.",
            "answers": ["Buffalo Bills", "Bills"],
            "incorrect1": "New York Jets",
            "incorrect2": "New York Giants",
            "incorrect3": "Cincinnati Bengals",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This monarch's reign saw the rise of the British Empire, the Industrial Revolution, and significant social reforms. During her time, Britain abolished slavery, expanded suffrage, and saw advancements in science and technology. She was the first British monarch to travel by train and to be photographed. Known for her strict moral code and devotion to her husband, Prince Albert, she mourned his death for the rest of her life, wearing black until her own passing. Who is this iconic queen?",
            "answers": ["Queen Victoria", "Victoria", "Alexandrina Victoria"],
            "incorrect1": "Elizabeth II",
            "incorrect2": "Charles III",
            "incorrect3": "Alexander the Great",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "Found on every continent except Antarctica, this type of bird is known for its ability to mimic human speech and other sounds. With over 350 species, this bird is found in a variety of habitats, from rainforests to deserts. Some species of this bird can live for over 50 years, and many form strong pair bonds with their mates. What is this colorful and intelligent bird known for its curved beak and zygodactyl feet (two toes facing forward and two toes facing backward)?",
            "answers": ["Parrot"],
            "incorrect1": "Eagle",
            "incorrect2": "Hawk",
            "incorrect3": "Gull",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This city was bombed by a B-29 Superfortress bomber named \"Enola Gay\" which was piloted by Colonel Paul Tibbets. The bombing of this city resulted in the immediate deaths of an estimated 80,000 people, with tens of thousands more dying later from radiation exposure. This mission was the first use of a nuclear weapon in warfare, leading to Japan's surrender and the end of World War II. It was also a turning point in history, marking the beginning of the Atomic Age. Name this city which was bombed by an atomic bomb nicknamed \"Little Boy.\"",
            "answers": ["Hiroshima", "Hiroshima Japan"],
            "incorrect1": "Tokyo",
            "incorrect2": "Iwo Jima",
            "incorrect3": "Dresden",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "This painting, depicting the Infanta Margarita and her entourage, is known for its complex composition and enigmatic atmosphere. It features a self-portrait of the artist at work on a large canvas, the back of which is visible to the viewer. The painting also includes a mirror reflecting the image of King Philip IV and Queen Mariana, suggesting their presence in the room. What is the title of this famous masterpiece by Diego Vel\u00e1zquez?",
            "answers": ["Las Meninas"],
            "incorrect1": "Guernica",
            "incorrect2": "The Birth of the World",
            "incorrect3": "The Third of May 1808",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This iconic peak, whose name means \"meadow peak\" in German, has four distinct faces aligned almost perfectly with the cardinal directions. Located on the border between Switzerland and Italy, it stands at 4,478 meters (14,692 feet) tall. The mountain's distinctive pyramidal shape has been featured in numerous works of art and literature and has become synonymous with the Swiss Alps. The first successful ascent of this mountain took place in 1865, but it resulted in tragedy as four climbers died during the descent. What is the name of this iconic mountain?",
            "answers": ["Matterhorn", "Cervino", "Mt Cervin", "Mount Cervin"],
            "incorrect1": "Mount Everest",
            "incorrect2": "Mount Blanc",
            "incorrect3": "Mount Kilimanjaro",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This state, once part of Massachusetts, became the 23rd to join the Union in 1820 as part of the Missouri Compromise. It's famous for its rocky coastline, lobster industry, and is the easternmost point in the contiguous United States. Additionally, it's the only state with a one-syllable name and the only state that borders just one other state. Name this state.",
            "answers": ["Maine"],
            "incorrect1": "Wisconsin",
            "incorrect2": "New Hampshire",
            "incorrect3": "Utah",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This inventor's most famous creation, a safer alternative to nitroglycerin, was initially used for mining and construction but also found applications in warfare. He held 355 patents for various inventions, including synthetic rubber and leather. He was a polyglot, fluent in six languages, and had a lifelong interest in literature and philosophy. Upon his death, he bequeathed his fortune to establish the prestigious awards that bear his name. Who is this inventor and philanthropist?",
            "answers": ["Alfred Nobel", "Nobel"],
            "incorrect1": "Marie Curie",
            "incorrect2": "Alexander Fleming",
            "incorrect3": "Albert Einstein",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This city hosted the 2024 Republican National Convention. This city is home to the world's largest music festival, Summerfest, and also boasts a rich brewing history, earning it the nickname \"Brew City.\"  Additionally, it is home to the Harley-Davidson Museum, showcasing the legacy of the famous motorcycle brand. Name this city on Lake Michigan's shores which is also known for its iconic Bronze Fonz statue, a tribute to the popular character from the TV show \"Happy Days.\"",
            "answers": ["Milwaukee", "Milwaukee Wisconsin"],
            "incorrect1": "Chicago",
            "incorrect2": "Cleveland",
            "incorrect3": "Dallas",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This film, featuring a wormhole near Saturn, explores a future where humanity seeks a new home due to Earth's deteriorating environment. The film's scientific advisor, Kip Thorne, ensured the accurate depiction of black holes and gravitational time dilation. A key plot point revolves around the protagonist's daughter, who ages much slower than him due to the effects of relativity. What is the title of this 2014 science fiction film directed by Christopher Nolan?",
            "answers": ["Interstellar"],
            "incorrect1": "The Martian",
            "incorrect2": "Ad Astra",
            "incorrect3": "Arrival",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NFL team, established in 1919, is the only community-owned franchise in the league. It boasts the most NFL championships with 13 wins, including four Super Bowl titles. Coached by the legendary Vince Lombardi during their first two Super Bowl victories, they were the only team to defeat the AFL before the merger. Name this historic team that plays at Lambeau Field, nicknamed the \"Frozen Tundra.\"",
            "answers": ["Green Bay Packers", "Packers"],
            "incorrect1": "Chicago Bears",
            "incorrect2": "Detroit Lions",
            "incorrect3": "Minnesota Vikings",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "Convened in response to the Protestant Reformation, this council addressed doctrinal challenges and aimed to reform the Catholic Church from within. Held in three sessions over eighteen years in a city in Northern Italy, it reaffirmed traditional Catholic teachings on salvation, the sacraments, and the authority of the Pope. This council also established seminaries for the education of priests and sought to address abuses within the clergy. What was this significant council in Catholic history?",
            "answers": ["Council of Trent"],
            "incorrect1": "Spanish Inquisition",
            "incorrect2": "Council of Florence",
            "incorrect3": "Council of Five Elders",
            "used": "FALSE",
            "source": "Marty Heavey"
        }
    ]
]
